in order to be successful you need to
为了获得成功，你需要
know that people have a small number of
要知道人们拥有的数量很少
slots in their brain for who they
他们大脑中为他们自己预留了位置。
remember so you've got to get into
记住，你必须进入
people's head and in order to do that
人们的头脑，为了做到这一点
you need to know two things the first
你需要知道两件事，第一件
one is 7114 which we'll talk about and
其中之一是7114，我们稍后会谈到它。
the second thing is that your brain is
第二点是，你的大脑是
extremely good at deleting messages but
非常擅长删除信息，但是
there's five things that will not be
有五件事不会发生
deleted by the brain and the last two
被大脑删除，以及最后两个
are the ones that are most useful so the
是最有用的那些。
first one is I wish I knew this stuff at
第一件事是，我希望我早点知道这些。
the start of my career Daniel Priestley
我的职业生涯始于丹尼尔·普里斯特利
is the money-making expert and serial
是赚钱专家和连环杀手
entrepreneur who's built several
这位企业家已经创建了多家公司
multi-million dollar businesses from
来自价值数百万美元的企业
nothing and has meor over 3,500
什么都没有，而且超过 3,500
businesses with the same Frameworks for
具有相同框架的企业
Career Success that you're about to
你即将迎来的职业成功
learn the problem that we have now is
了解我们现在面临的问题是：
that we live in a digital world but all
我们生活在一个数字化的世界，但所有
of society is built for the Industrial
社会是为工业而建立的。
Revolution system which means that we're
革命体系意味着我们是
playing by an old set of rules and going
按照一套旧的规则行事并前进
through a schooling system that is
通过一个教育体系，
preparing them for a world that no
让他们为一个没有
longer exists so people feel like that
已经不存在了，所以人们才会有这种感觉。
there are no opportunities there are no
没有机会，没有
safe jobs anymore feeling like you're in
不再有安全的工作，感觉就像身处险境
competition with AI and that leaves a
与人工智能的竞争，留下了一个
whole generation of people feeling
整整一代人的感觉
absolutely wiped out before they've even
他们还没来得及行动就被彻底消灭了。
started so what are the new set of
开始了，那么新的一组是什么？
skills people need to know to set them
人们需要了解的技能才能设置它们
up in this Digital World well there's
在这个数字世界里，嗯……
actually a step-by-step approach for
实际上，这是一个循序渐进的方法。
doing that including building a personal
这样做包括建立个人
brand okay let's pause there why does
品牌，好的，我们先暂停一下，为什么？
that matter cuz that's the key to
那很重要，因为那是关键所在。
Capital Talent customers and it's not
Capital Talent 的客户，而且并非如此
about becoming an influencer with
关于如何成为一名有影响力的人
millions of followers but if you're seen
拥有数百万粉丝，但如果你被看到
as a key person of influence that's
作为一位关键人物，这……
enough to make seven figures and is that
足以赚到七位数，就是这样。
where your 5ps come in yeah and I'll
你的5便士就派上用场了，对，我会
take you through all of those and then
带你了解所有这些，然后
there's the entrepreneurial pyramid
这就是创业金字塔。
which opens you up to this whole other
这让你接触到完全不同的世界。
world of opportunities as well as side
充满机遇的世界以及周边
hustles and the two types of
奋斗和两种类型的
opportunities that everyone needs to
每个人都需要的机会
know about I want to go through all of
了解我想了解的所有内容
that let's do it
那就这么办吧
this has always blown my mind a little
这件事一直让我有点难以置信。
bit 53% of you that listen to the show
53% 的听众收听了该节目
regularly haven't yet subscribed to the
经常还没有订阅
show so could I ask you for a favor
所以，我能请你帮个忙吗？
before we start if you like the show and
在我们开始之前，如果你喜欢这个节目，
you like what we do here and you want to
你喜欢我们在这里做的事情，并且你想……
support us the free simple way that you
您支持我们的方式很简单，而且完全免费。
can do just that is by hitting the
做到这一点的方法就是点击
Subscribe button and my commitment to
订阅按钮以及我对订阅的承诺
you is if you do that then I'll do
如果你那样做，那我也会那样做。
everything in my power me and my team to
我和我的团队将竭尽全力
make sure that this show is better for
确保这个节目对……更好
you every single week we'll listen to
我们每周都会听你的节目。
your feedback we'll find the guest that
您的反馈将帮助我们找到合适的客人
you want me to speak to and we'll
你想让我跟谁谈谈，我们……
continue to do what we do thank you so
请继续做我们正在做的事情，谢谢。
much
很多
[Music]
[音乐]
Daniel Priestley how do you define and
丹尼尔·普里斯特利，你如何定义和
describe what it is that you do with
请描述一下你用它做什么。
your content with your work um and
你对你的工作的内容，嗯，还有
through all of these books that you've
在你读过的所有这些书中……
published what is the summary of what
已发布的摘要是什么？
you do and who you do it for so I have a
你做什么，以及你为谁做，所以我有一个
massive passion for entrepreneurship
对创业充满热情
about 20 years ago I started seeing a
大约20年前，我开始看到
massive Trend uh about entrepreneurs who
大量趋势，呃，关于那些企业家
could stand out scale up and make a
可以脱颖而出，扩大规模并取得成功
positive impact in the world through
通过以下方式对世界产生积极影响
business um I have built multiple
我已经建立了多个业务。
businesses over the last 20 years and
过去20年的企业和
I'm just uh fascinated by the
我只是对……很感兴趣
predictable stages that people go
人们会经历的可预测阶段
through in order to build successful
通过建立成功
businesses um as I've been growing my
随着我的业务不断发展，我的
businesses I've been writing about it in
我一直在撰写有关此事的企业
my books um mostly to document what I'm
我的书，嗯，主要是为了记录我……
learning myself um and I also built a
自学过程中，我还建造了一个
community of entrepreneurs who wanted to
一群想要……的企业家
uh essentially make the most of the
呃，基本上就是充分利用
times that we in so what's happening at
我们所处的时代，究竟发生了什么？
the moment is we're going through
此刻，我们正经历着这一切。
massive amounts of change it's very
变化巨大，非常巨大
similar to the agricultural age when it
类似于农业时代
was replaced by the IND Industrial Age
被工业时代所取代
and there were New Economic rules that
并且出现了新的经济规则。
didn't apply to the agricultural age but
不适用于农业时代，但
did apply to the Industrial Age so the
确实适用于工业时代，所以
agricultural age was the feudal system
农业时代是封建制度时期。
and the Industrial Age was the
工业时代是
capitalist system what's happening is
资本主义制度正在发生的事情是
the Industrial Age is fast being
工业时代正在迅速消逝
replaced by the digital age and as we go
被数字时代所取代，而且我们一直在这样做
through this massive change we're seeing
我们正在目睹这场巨大的变革。
new rules and New Economic rules that
新规则和新经济规则
apply so give you an example in the
应用，所以给你举个例子。
Industrial Age people had to to become
工业时代的人们不得不成为
successful people had to gain skills and
成功人士必须掌握技能，
then get a job and find an employer who
然后找份工作，找到一个雇主
would uh employ them for those skills as
会利用他们的这些技能来雇用他们。
we go into the digital age what works is
我们进入数字时代，哪些方法行之有效？
to build a personal brand based on your
打造基于你的个人品牌
unique intellectual property and then to
独特的知识产权，然后是
position that brand next to a scalable
将该品牌定位在可扩展的旁边
digital uh elegant business model and
数字化的优雅商业模式和
those who are doing that and those who
那些这样做的人和那些
have figured that out are doing
已经弄清楚了，正在做
incredibly well and succeeding at speed
表现出色，并且速度很快。
and there's actually a step-by-step
实际上，这里有一个循序渐进的步骤。
approach for doing that I want to go
我想采用的方法是
through all of that I am I was running
在这一切过程中，我一直在奔跑
in Cape Town look at me plugging my
在开普敦，看看我插着我的
running brand that's lasted for 5 days
持续使用5天的跑步品牌
um I was run in Cape Town and a young
嗯，我曾在开普敦生活过，当时我还很年轻。
couple came up to me at the end of my
在我行程的最后，一对夫妇走过来和我搭讪。
run when I'd stopped uh running
当我停止跑步时，他跑了起来。
underneath this tree and they came up to
他们来到这棵树下，然后走到
me it was about the second or third of
对我来说，那大概是第二或第三个
January they said um Steve we love your
一月份的时候，他们说，嗯，史蒂夫，我们爱你
content we've been listening to dersy a
我们一直在听的内容 dersy a
while and they looked at each other and
他们互相看着对方，
you could see that they were really
你可以看出他们真的很
stressed and they said we're just trying
他们很紧张，但他们说我们只是在尝试。
to figure out how to start a business
弄清楚如何创业
and what we should be doing and I could
以及我们应该做什么，我可以
see in their face that they had been
从他们的脸上可以看出，他们曾经
mulling it for a long long time there
在那里反复思考了很久很久。
was this like they're very very young
这是因为他们年纪还很小吗？
I'd say they were like 21 years old and
我猜他们当时大概21岁左右。
they were saying like what do we do and
他们当时在问，我们该怎么办？
actually at that time I said you need to
实际上，当时我说你需要
need to listen to an episode I did with
需要听听我之前和……一起做的那期节目。
Daniel Priestley but I also knew you
丹尼尔·普里斯特利，但我也认识你
were coming on so I said and I'm
他们会过来，所以我说，我是
recording with him shortly so make sure
稍后会和他一起录音，所以请务必注意。
you listen to that so through the lens
你透过镜头听着。
of that 21y old you've detailed that
关于你详细描述的那个21岁年轻人，
their world has now changed they're
他们的世界已经改变了，他们是
living in this digital world where would
生活在这个数字世界里，我们会……
you advise those two to start if they
你建议那两个人开始，如果他们
want to capitalize on the opportunity
想抓住这个机会
that's presented itself okay so I'll
既然已经呈现出来了，那我就……
slow down for a minute what's happening
慢点，想想发生了什么。
at the moment is people in that
目前是这些人
situation they're feeling incredibly
他们目前所处的境况令他们感到难以置信
invisible um that they don't matter they
隐形的，嗯，它们无关紧要。
feel stuck that there are no
感觉被困住了，因为没有
opportunities you can't buy a house you
你没有机会买房
can't get a career uh there are no safe
找不到工作，呃，没有安全的地方。
jobs anymore um AI is disrupting
人工智能正在颠覆就业市场。
everything um and they feel detached
一切都……嗯，他们感觉很疏离。
from meaning and purpose and that leaves
从意义和目的出发，这就留下了。
a whole generation of young people
整整一代年轻人
feeling absolutely wiped out before
之前感觉筋疲力尽
they've even started it doesn't actually
他们甚至已经开始了，但实际上并没有。
exclusively apply just to people in
仅适用于以下人群
their 20s I know people in their 40s 50s
我认识一些二十多岁的人，也认识一些四五十岁的人。
60s I know entrepreneurs who have
我认识一些六十多岁的企业家，他们
traditional businesses who feel that way
有这种想法的传统企业
so it's worth acknowledging that it's a
因此，值得承认的是，这是一个
widespread phenomenon everywhere in the
普遍现象
world people feeling invisible feeling
世界人民感到隐形的感觉
the pain of like not being able to
无法做到的那种痛苦
connect with the right people um and
与合适的人建立联系
feeling stuck and feeling detached from
感到困顿和疏离
meaning so what we need to do is address
所以，我们需要做的就是解决
that be because what's happening is
那是因为正在发生的事情是
you're playing by an old set of rules
你还在沿用一套陈旧的规则。
and that's normal because the school
这很正常，因为学校
system told you an old set of rules
系统告诉你一套旧的规则
because it was based in the Industrial
因为它位于工业区
Age and we have to start by learning the
年龄，我们必须从学习开始
new set of rules so if I was advising 21
新的规则，所以如果我建议21
year olds in particular the first thing
尤其是对于几岁的孩子来说，第一件事
that you want to do is called an
你想做的叫做
entrepreneur apprenticeship uh an
创业学徒制
entrepreneur apprenticeship is where
创业学徒制就是在这里
where you go and work in a small team of
你去的地方，在一个小型团队中工作
less than 12 people where you have
人数少于 12 人的地方
direct contact with an entrepreneur and
与企业家直接接触
in particular you're looking for an
具体来说，你正在寻找一个
entrepreneur who has somewhat of a
一位具有一定能力的企业家
personal brand so they have let's say
个人品牌，比如说，他们有
5,000 to 50,000 uh followers on social
社交媒体上拥有 5,000 到 50,000 名粉丝
media and they've got an elegant
媒体，而且他们有一种优雅的
business model that inspires you it
让你深受启发的商业模式
doesn't necessarily have to be exactly
不一定非得完全一样。
what you want to do in the future but
你未来想做什么，但是
you need to learn the new rules so you
你需要学习新规则，这样你
need to learn how is that person
需要了解那个人是怎样的人
building their personal brand and how
打造个人品牌及其方法
are they building their business so that
他们正在建立自己的业务，以便
it can scale how how do they communicate
它可以扩展他们如何沟通
with people anywhere in the world how do
如何与世界各地的人相处
they sell to people anywhere in the
他们向世界各地的人销售产品。
world so those are some of the key
世界，所以这些是一些关键因素。
things that you have to do you do not
你必须做的事情，你不需要做。
want to become an entrepreneur straight
想直接成为一名企业家
away it's too big a shift you need to be
离开这里，转变太大了，你需要……
a number two I was a number two I had a
我曾是二号选手，我曾是二号选手。
mentor I worked for an amazing guy for
我曾为一位很棒的人担任导师。
two years uh we went from 0 to 6 million
两年时间，我们从零增长到了六百万。
in a year and from zero people to 60
一年内，人数从零增加到60人
people in one year so I got the
一年内有这么多人，所以我得到了
entrepreneur apprenticeship first and
创业学徒制优先
that's where you want to start and then
那是你该开始的地方，然后
once you do that you can do side hustles
一旦你做到了这一点，你就可以做副业了。
and then begin the entrepreneurial
然后开始创业
Journey on your own but how do you know
独自踏上旅程，但你怎么知道
if it's for you how do you know if you
如果是为你准备的，你怎么知道它是否适合你？
cut out for it so at the moment what's
已经做好了准备，所以目前的情况是……
happening is that the rules are changing
正在发生的事情是，规则正在改变。
so fast that you it's not like anyone's
速度快到你感觉不像任何人的。
cut out for it right so there is no sure
正好适合，所以没有确定性
feeling where you go oh I'm really cut
感受着你的去向，哦，我真的受伤了。
out for this because it's giving me
我之所以退出，是因为它给了我
clear signals during times of disruption
动荡时期发出清晰信号
the signals get uh jammed so what's
信号被干扰了，那会怎么样？
happening is people are going through a
目前的情况是人们正在经历……
schooling system that is preparing them
为他们做准备的教育体系
for a world that no longer exists so we
为了一个已经不复存在的世界，所以我们
go through 12 years of school and it's
经过12年的学校教育，就……
saying oh you know here's how you get
比如说，你知道，你可以这样得到
ready for an employer well there are no
准备好迎接雇主了吗？嗯，没有。
employers and here's how you get ready
雇主们，以下是您需要准备的内容
for a career there's no such thing as
对于职业生涯而言，并不存在这样一种说法：
careers anymore um and here's how you
职业生涯不再是问题了，嗯，以下是方法……
get ready for a job oh by the way that
准备去上班，哦对了……
job can easily be done by AI already so
这项工作现在完全可以由人工智能完成。
all of this is happening and that means
这一切都在发生，这意味着
that people are feeling this void and
人们感受到了这种空虚感，
they're saying well I don't feel ready
他们说，我觉得我还没准备好。
for anything that's because you had 12
任何事都是因为你有12
years of training for a world that
为了一个世界而进行的多年训练
doesn't exist anymore so what we have to
已经不存在了，所以我们必须……
do is say all right let's look at the
就是说，好吧，我们来看看……
world that is uh emerging and let's
一个正在兴起的世界，让我们……
position ourselves for that world and
我们为这个世界做好准备
res skill ourselves and reposition our
重新提升自身技能并重新定位我们
El for that world when you were talking
当你在谈论那个世界时，埃尔
about that entrepreneurial
关于那项创业
apprenticeship it sounded like a new
学徒制听起来像是一种新的
form of Education a new form of
教育形式 新形式
University are there any other ways if
大学还有其他途径吗？
we're talking about that preparation
我们正在讨论的是准备工作。
phase where you're getting ready are
准备阶段
there any other ways you would advise
还有其他建议吗？
someone to rapidly Excel their Knowledge
有人迅速提升自己的知识水平
and Skills in preparation to become an
以及成为……的准备技能
entrepreneur um is it books is it do I
企业家，嗯，是书吗？是吗？我
sit on chat GPT what worked for you
坐着聊天 GPT 对你有效吗？
books are great YouTube channels are
书籍是很棒的 YouTube 频道
great I didn't have any of that um you
太好了，我没有那些东西，嗯，你
know believe it or not even books were
信不信由你，就连书籍也是如此。
hard to come by when I was a teenager um
我十几岁的时候很难找到。
you know you had to kind of order
你知道你必须得有个规矩。
business books in or you had to go to a
商业书籍，或者你必须去……
big book store that had a business book
一家大型书店，里面有一本商业书籍。
section um we didn't have Amazon and we
嗯，我们那部分没有亚马逊，而且我们
certainly you know anything like a
当然，你肯定知道类似这样的事情
podcast you actually paid for cassette
你花钱买的播客磁带
tapes and CDs and they were $1,000 they
磁带和CD，它们售价1000美元。
were really expensive just to listen to
光是听这些歌就很贵了。
some business content believe it or not
信不信由你，有些商业内容
that was a thing um and all of it's for
那件事确实存在，而且这一切都是为了
free now online however there's you
现在网上免费，不过你……
can't learn to ride a bike uh through
学不会骑自行车
books and videos you have to get on the
你必须下载的书籍和视频
bike so the best thing to do is to work
骑自行车，所以最好的办法就是工作
for someone who's building a business
对于正在创业的人来说
and if you can't do that become a
如果你做不到这一点，那就成为一个
co-founder with someone who's got more
与一位更有经验的人共同创立
experience than you um and if you can't
比你更有经验，嗯，如果你不能
do that then you need to do some small
那样做之后，你需要做一些小事。
side hustles a side hustle is an open
副业（side hustle）是一种开放的副业。
and shut business case so within 90 days
并在90天内结束商业案例
you're going to start something and
你打算开始做某件事，
finish something all with within 90 days
在90天内完成所有事情
you're not going to get yourself into a
你不会让自己陷入困境
long-term thing you're just going to
从长远来看，你只需要……
start something see how it goes and it
开始做点什么，看看结果如何，然后
ends in 90 days when I was a teenager I
90天后结束，那时我还是个十几岁的孩子。
did nightclub parties so the nightclub
夜总会举办派对，所以夜总会
part had a time where we would agree
曾经有一段时间，我们会达成共识
with the club that we were going to uh
我们当时要去的那个俱乐部……
have the venue then we had a promotion
有了场地，我们就搞了个推广活动。
phase then we ran the party and then
阶段之后我们主持了派对，然后
that was it at the end of the night we
那天晚上结束时，事情就是这样。
split the money and that was uh the
平分了钱，事情就是这样。
finish and it all happened very quickly
结束了，一切发生得非常快。
and you get the learning experience but
你能获得学习经验，但
you don't have the ongoing um connection
你没有持续的嗯连接
to the business I also sold roses uh
我还向那家店卖过玫瑰花。
door too um so on Valentine's Day I
门也……嗯，所以在情人节那天我
bought a few hundred roses we dressed up
买了几百朵玫瑰，我们盛装打扮
in tuxedos and we went door Todo selling
我们穿着燕尾服挨家挨户去推销Todo产品。
uh Valentine's Day roses and that
呃，情人节玫瑰之类的。
probably lasted 3 weeks um from the time
大概持续了3周，嗯，从那时开始
we came up with the idea to the time we
我们想出了这个主意，当时我们
found a supplier bought the Roses went
找到供应商，买下了玫瑰花
door too uh and made our sales and then
门也……呃，然后我们的销售额就……
it was all finished at the end of
一切都在最后结束了。
Valentine's Day so these are called side
情人节，所以这些被称为配菜
hustles and the important point is that
忙碌而重要的是……
they're not ongoing Ventures they're
它们不是持续进行中的项目，它们是
just open and shut and then you can
只需打开和关闭，然后你就可以
reflect you can then sort of see what
反思之后，你就能大致看出什么了。
worked what didn't work and then see if
找出哪些方法有效，哪些无效，然后看看是否有效。
you want to continue after that
你想在那之后继续吗？
something else that i' I don't think
还有一件事，我觉得……
I've ever heard many entrepreneurs or
我曾听过很多企业家或
Founders talk about when they're giving
创始人谈论他们何时捐赠
advice on that preparation learning
关于准备学习的建议
phase is the importance of
阶段的重要性
writing yeah has that had a profound
是的，写作确实产生了深远的影响。
impact on me um my the rate in which I
对我的影响，嗯，我的速度
Learned was having a practice what stage
学习正在进行哪个阶段的练习
in your journey did you write so I made
在你的旅途中，你是否写下了什么，所以我做了
a commitment to myself when I was 24 to
我24岁时对自己做出的承诺
write a tweet every day okay and I would
每天发一条推文，好吗？
screenshot it then post it on Instagram
截屏后发布到 Instagram
now this was maybe the single biggest
这或许是最大的一件事。
hack in my life that I've never really
在我的生活中闯入了一个我从未真正经历过的陷阱
talked about because of the all of the
之所以谈论这些，是因为所有这些
downstream consequences that occurred
发生的下游后果
Downstream consequence number one got to
下游后果一是
a million followers on Instagram by
在 Instagram 上拥有百万粉丝
posting these quotes of ideas that I had
发布这些我曾经有过的想法语录
every day so every day at 7 p.m. my
每天，也就是每天晚上7点。我的
girlfriend knew at the time she goes
女朋友当时就知道她要走了
he's going to go off for an hour and
他要离开一个小时，
think of something to say um Downstream
想想该说些什么，嗯，下游
consequence number two is it taught me
第二个后果是它教会了我
how to communicate ideas in a concise
如何简洁地表达想法
high impact way and kind of what people
高影响力的方式和人们的那种方式
respond to uh and I'd say number three
回答“呃”，我会说是三号。
is it generally meant that if I went
这通常意味着如果我去
through my day and something had
我一整天都在想着这件事，但总觉得有什么不对劲。
happened it gave me a moment to condense
这件事给了我一点时间来浓缩信息。
that down into wisdom a little pie truth
那一点点真理，就蕴藏在智慧之中。
a piece of Truth so that day I learned
那天我学到了一部分真理。
something and um without that practice
有些东西，嗯，如果没有那种练习。
those learnings kind of would have
这些经验教训某种程度上会……
passed you by so what you're describing
你错过了，所以你描述的是什么？
is actually Beyond just writing it's
实际上，这不仅仅是写作而已。
publishing um and Publishing means to
出版，出版意味着
make public to put something into the
公开表明要投入一些东西
public domain so yeah there's journaling
公共领域，所以是的，有日记这种东西。
which you keep private but then there's
你会把这些保密信息保留下来，但还有……
making something public um and when you
将某些东西公开，嗯，当你
when you do this you have to think about
当你这样做的时候，你必须考虑……
how would this be of value to others um
这对其他人有什么价值呢？
so you'll thinking you know
所以你会觉得你知道
entrepreneurs have to be thinking about
企业家必须考虑……
how would this be of value to others
这对其他人有什么价值？
you're putting it into the public domain
你把它放到了公共领域。
so you're getting feedback as to whether
所以你会收到关于是否
this is a good idea or a bad idea or
这是一个好主意还是一个坏主意？
okay idea um so yeah publishing doesn't
好的，想法，嗯，所以，是的，出版业并不……
have to be tweeting it doesn't have to
必须发推文，也不一定非要发推文。
be um writing a book publishing is video
嗯，写书出版是视频
audio um it can be long form content it
音频，嗯，它可以是长篇内容。
can be short content uh you could do
可以是短篇内容，嗯，你可以这样做
shorts you could do tweets right all of
短线，你可以直接发推文。
that is publishing the the essence of
那就是发表其本质
publishing is that you're taking your
出版就是你把你的
ideas and sharing it publicly putting it
想法并公开分享。
in the public domain that is a very
在公共领域，这是一个非常
rapid way to get started um interesting
快速入门的方法，嗯，挺有意思的。
fact on this that out of the billion
事实是，在这十亿人中
people who use LinkedIn only 3% are
只有3%的人使用LinkedIn
publishing regularly and less than 1%
定期出版，出版量低于1%
publish weekly so you think that you're
每周发布，所以你认为你是
in competition with a billion people on
与十亿人竞争
LinkedIn 99% of people are just there to
LinkedIn 上 99% 的人只是为了……
kind of lurk and watch what other people
有点像潜水员，观察其他人做什么
are doing only 1% of people are
只有 1% 的人这样做
competing 1% of people are creating the
竞争者中仅有1%的人正在创造
content on that platform um when it
那个平台上的内容，嗯，当它
comes to YouTube there's 2.7 billion
YouTube 上有 27 亿用户。
users of YouTube but only 4% of people
YouTube 用户，但仅占总用户数的 4%。
have an account and only a fraction of
拥有一个账户，但只有一小部分
those accounts are active so it's a tiny
这些账户都是活跃的，所以影响很小。
percentage of the world's population
占世界人口的百分比
that are creating something most people
创造大多数人喜欢的东西
are consuming so one thing that you're
你在消耗一些东西，所以你
describing is the move from being a
描述是从成为
consumer to a Creator and entrepreneurs
从消费者到创作者和企业家
have to make that move how have you
必须采取那个行动，你怎么做到的？
accelerated your learning because you're
因为你加速了你的学习，所以
someone that is able to give out lots of
能够给予很多东西的人
different ideas from lots of different
来自许多不同事物的不同想法
references points and there must be some
参考点，而且必须有一些
kind of underlying framework you're
你是某种底层框架
using to like learn process and publish
用来学习过程并发布
which now presents you which is part of
现在向您展示的是其中的一部分
the reason you get invited on to all
你被邀请参加所有活动的理由
these podcasts now and people are paying
现在这些播客节目都付费了。
you to speak at their events Etc what
邀请你参加他们的活动并发言等等
was that framework for you so my
那个框架是为你准备的吗？所以我的
background was I used to have an agency
我的背景是我曾经拥有一家代理公司。
and we used to run all these different
我们过去常常运行所有这些不同的
events and we used to uh have to put
事件，我们过去常常不得不……
stuff onto people's seats when we were
我们当时把东西堆到人们的座位上
running events and I had to kind of
举办活动，我不得不……
write stuff all the time like quick
经常快速地写东西
reports and all of that so I got in the
报告等等，所以我进去了。
habit of writing I saw the power of
写作的习惯让我看到了它的力量
writing um in 2009 the entire world
2009年，全世界都在写这篇文章
tipped on its head um after the global
全球性事件后，它被彻底颠覆了。
financial crisis and I was completely
金融危机，我完全……
disrupted uh I went from millions of
被打断了，呃，我从数百万美元……
Revenue down to a few hundred thousand
收入降至几十万美元
of Revenue I lost 90% of my Revenue in
收入方面，我损失了90%的收入。
one year um it was mass it was I
一年，嗯，那是弥撒，那是我
remember one Christmas party 17 18
记得17、18年的一次圣诞派对
people at a Christmas party the
圣诞派对上的人们
following year was three um it was
第二年是三年，嗯，是
morbid so during that time where the
所以在那段时间里，病态的……
global financial crisis had such a deep
全球金融危机的影响如此之深
impact I began writing about what is it
影响 我开始写作，探讨它究竟是什么
that I know to be true what is it that
我知道的真相是什么？
like I don't know much because I've just
好像我懂得不多，因为我刚……
had the rug pulled out from under me
感觉就像被人从脚下抽走了地毯。
what is it I do know to be true what are
我确信什么是真的？
the most uh strong truths that I could
我能想到的最强烈的真相
share and I ended up writing the book
分享之后，我最终写了这本书。
called key person of influence in 2009
2009年被称为关键人物
and it came out in
它最终出版了
2010 and what I felt very confident
2010年，我当时非常有信心
about was this idea that the future was
这种想法认为未来是
going to see a shift from business and
将会见证商业的转变
institutional Brands to personal brands
从机构品牌到个人品牌
that we would see the decline of big
我们会看到大型企业的衰落。
faceless companies and the rise of uh
无面孔的公司和呃的兴起
individuals whose personal Brands were
个人品牌是
bigger than the institutions um and it
比这些机构更大，嗯，而且
was pretty radical idea at the time but
在当时这确实是个相当激进的想法，但
I felt pretty confident about it and the
我对此相当有信心，而且
more I wrote about it the more I felt
我越写越觉得
this was where the world was heading um
这就是世界的发展方向。
if we look today we can see Brian Cox
如果我们看看今天，我们可以看到布莱恩·考克斯
Professor Brian Cox has more followers
布莱恩·考克斯教授拥有更多追随者
than CERN um we can see Richard Branson
比欧洲核子研究中心更甚，我们可以看到理查德·布兰森
has orders of magnitude more followers
拥有数量级以上的追随者
than Virgin uh we can see elon's got
比维珍航空更甚，我们可以看到埃隆·马斯克已经……
more followers than NASA uh we can see
比NASA的粉丝还多，我们可以看到
you know Trump is way more powerful than
你知道特朗普的权力比任何人都大得多。
the rep Republican party so the the
共和党代表们
essentially the personal brand has just
个人品牌本质上已经……
gone whoosh ahead um but I was I I
嗖的一声就过去了，嗯，但我当时……
started that process very murky that I
这个过程一开始非常模糊，以至于我
didn't quite know what it was it was a
不太清楚那是什么，那是一个
feeling or a sense and by the time I'd
感觉或某种感觉，到那时我
gone through the publishing process of
经历了出版流程
writing uh I was clear and the macro
写作时，我表达得很清楚，而且是宏观的。
factors that brought that about what are
导致这种情况发生的因素是什么？
those underlying shifts that happened
那些发生的根本性转变
that meant we went from the logo to the
这意味着我们从标志设计过渡到了
person let's zoom out 300 years so the
这个人，我们把时间线拉远300年，这样……
the agricultural age uh was essentially
农业时代基本上是
the economic system was called feudalism
这种经济制度被称为封建主义。
and there was Lords and kings and queens
那里有领主、国王和王后。
and then there were surfs and people who
然后还有冲浪和人们
surfed the land and then technology
冲浪于陆地，然后是科技
changed things you can imagine what it
改变了很多事情，你可以想象那意味着什么。
must have been like when 300 people were
肯定跟300人的时候差不多。
on a farm and then they saw three people
在农场里，他们看到了三个人。
on a tractor and then that tractor went
在一辆拖拉机上，然后那辆拖拉机开走了
and went and did the job of hundreds of
然后他去做了数百人的工作
people with three people on it and it's
上面有三个人，而且是
like oh my goodness what are we all
我的天哪，我们都是什么？
going to do um how are we all going to
接下来我们该怎么做？我们大家打算怎么做？
live our lives anymore right and then
我们还能继续这样生活下去吗？
they would have said well what are going
他们会说，好吧，接下来会发生什么？
to be the jobs like everyone works in
从事像其他人一样的工作
farming and it's like well there's going
务农，感觉就像……嗯，还有去处。
to be this whole new system there will
要成为一个全新的系统，那里将会
be a completely new economic system
成为一个全新的经济体系
called the industrial system and it's
它被称为工业体系，它是
going to replace everything so back in
准备把所有东西都换掉，所以又回来了。
the agricultural age uh if you were a
农业时代，呃，如果你是……
lord right and if you were Rich if you
主啊，没错，如果你很富有，如果你
were successful you had vast tracks of
如果你成功了，你就拥有了广阔的赛道。
agricultural land but as soon as the
农田，但一旦
Industrial Age kicked in you didn't even
工业时代来临，你甚至都没意识到这一点。
need land you only needed a tiny amount
只需要土地，你只需要一小块。
of land to put a factory on What
一块地用来建工厂，这块地怎么样？
mattered is that you had the ability to
重要的是你拥有这种能力
organize lab LA and machinery and if you
组织实验室 LA 和机器设备，如果你
could organize a factory that was way
可以组织一家工厂，那真是
more economically productive thanu
经济生产力比
hundreds of Acres so the whole economic
数百英亩，因此整个经济
system got tipped on its head and
系统彻底颠覆了，
suddenly it didn't matter if you a dukee
突然间，你是不是公爵都无关紧要了。
it mattered if you an industrialist if
如果你是实业家，这很重要。
you're a capitalist so this whole new
你是个资本家，所以这一切新……
system took over we had 200 years of
系统接管了我们200年的时间
innovation and it went through multiple
它经历了多次创新。
waves but the important thing to know is
波浪，但重要的是要知道
that it's technology that changed things
是科技改变了一切。
right it's always a technology shift
没错，这始终是一场技术变革。
right the the the fundamentals of the
没错，就是基本原理
economy are dictated by the technology
经济受技术支配。
that we have available to us so what
我们拥有的资源是什么？
happened around the 2000s to
大约发生在2000年代
2020 is we had these general purpose
2020年，我们拥有了这些通用用途
technologies that just got introduced as
刚刚推出的技术
though they were nothing you know
虽然他们什么都不是，你知道的
suddenly everyone can publish a video
突然间，人人都能发布视频了。
online suddenly everyone can write a
突然之间，网络上人人都能写东西了。
blog suddenly everyone can tweet
博客突然间人人都能发推文了
everyone can form a community on
每个人都可以组建社区
Facebook uh there's this device that you
Facebook，呃，这里有个设备，你
put in your pocket that is better than a
放进口袋里比……更好
uh traditional camera studio that the
呃，传统的摄影棚。
BBC would have had so the the power was
BBC本来应该拥有这样的权力。
is just rapidly swinging from
只是快速地从
institutions to individuals I'm sitting
从机构到个人，我正坐在这里
there going wait a second an individual
他们会等一会儿，一个人
has got all the things that a
它拥有所有……
multinational corporation has access to
跨国公司拥有以下资源
but they don't have the bureaucracy
但他们没有官僚主义。
right they don't have the the weight on
对，他们没有负重。
their shoulders they don't make slow
他们的肩膀，他们不会慢慢地耸动。
decisions they can make fast decisions
他们能够迅速做出决定
so as I witnessed this technology being
因此，当我亲眼目睹这项技术时……
introduced I said the way this is going
我介绍说，事情会这样发展下去。
is it's going to take all the power of
这需要动用所有的力量
big businesses and institutions and just
大型企业和机构，以及
give that to individuals that's exactly
把这个给那些人，正是如此。
what happened and I mean if there was
发生了什么事？我的意思是，如果真的发生了什么事的话？
ever a year where that's been more in
过去一年，这种情况更为普遍。
focus with this election cycle and what
关注本次选举周期以及什么
we've seen with Trump and going on Rogan
我们已经看到特朗普上了罗根的节目。
and Cela going on Alex Cooper in the
Cela 和 Alex Cooper 一起上节目。
media lands that's what cost the
媒体土地，这就是代价。
election so that's a big Trend um US
选举，所以这是一个很大的趋势，嗯，美国
presidential elections have always
总统选举一直以来
predicted major Trends so Franklin
富兰克林预测了主要趋势
Roosevelt in the 30s he did the national
罗斯福在30年代做了全国性的
radio campaign JFK in the 60s did the
肯尼迪在 60 年代开展的广播竞选活动
televised campaign Obama in 2008 did the
奥巴马在2008年进行的电视竞选活动
social media campaign of those campaigns
这些活动的社交媒体宣传
changed the game Trump in 2016 did a
特朗普在2016年改变了游戏规则。
hyper personalized digital datadriven
超个性化数字数据驱动
campaign famously with Cambridge
剑桥大学的著名竞选活动
analytica and that actually gave birth
分析公司，而这实际上催生了它。
to data analytics and
数据分析和
hyper-personalization and then something
高度个性化，然后是某种……
big happened in
发生大事
2024 and what happened is that Trump
2024年发生的事情是，特朗普
broke the mold on campaigning and he
他打破了竞选的固有模式，而且
started going on all these major
所有这些重大事件都开始发生了。
podcasts and if we actually crunch the
播客，如果我们真的深入分析一下……
numbers Trump uh did something like 40
特朗普的数字大概是40左右。
hours worth of Watch time uh and it got
几个小时的观看时间，呃，然后它就……
124 million views and uh Kamala did I
1.24亿次观看，呃，卡马拉做了什么？
think it was 7 hours just in the long
我想光长途就花了7个小时。
form yeah just on the long form she did
是的，她只是在长表格上填写了。
seven hours total and it only got a few
总共七个小时，但只拍了几集。
million views and one of her podcasts
百万次观看，以及她的一档播客节目
only last 7 minutes now what she did is
只持续了7分钟，她做了什么？
she approached it like a McKenzie
她采取的方式就像麦肯齐一样
consultant which is she turned up and
这位顾问如约而至。
she said here's the script here's the
她说，这是剧本，这是……
questions um ask me these questions and
问题，嗯，问我这些问题吧。
then I'm out of here and it was very
然后我就离开了这里，那感觉非常……
much the kind of um professional
非常像那种专业人士
corporate approach Trump rocks up onto
企业策略 特朗普强势登场
comedians podcast and says yeah ask me
喜剧演员播客说，是的，问我
anything and then he just goes on a big
不管什么事，然后他就开始大吵大闹。
rant and it goes for 3 hours now what's
抱怨已经持续了3个小时了，这是怎么回事？
actually happening is is quite
实际上发生的事情相当
predictable in a world of short videos
在短视频的世界里，这是可以预见的。
and in a world of AI and in a world of
在一个人工智能的世界里，在一个
confusion and disruption and and where
混乱和中断，以及在哪里
everyone's throwing um punches at each
每个人都在互相挥拳。
other saying your misinformation your
其他人说你散布了错误信息
misinformation you've seen some of this
你可能已经看到过一些这样的错误信息。
right going on right misinformation
正确的做法是传播错误信息
misinformation what actually going on is
错误信息，实际情况是
that people say hey enough's enough I
人们会说，够了，够了！
want to see a long form piece of content
想看一篇长篇内容
and make my own mind up I don't want
我自己决定，我不想要
anyone to tell me what's in
谁能告诉我里面是什么？
misinformation I'm smart enough I want
错误信息 我足够聪明 我想要
to see if this Trump guy is a crazy guy
看看特朗普这家伙是不是个疯子
I want to be able to see him you know
我想见他，你知道的。
for two or three hours and I'll make my
两三个小时后，我就可以做我的
own mind up on that because everyone's
因为每个人都有自己的想法，所以每个人都……
saying so many different things and I
说了好多不同的话，而我
know that there's all this confusion I
我知道这里有很多混乱。
want the long form piece of content so
想要篇幅较长的内容，所以
2024 began the long form unscripted era
2024年开启了长篇无剧本时代。
right so now where we are with marketing
好的，那么我们现在在市场营销方面进展如何呢？
is you've got to drop the script and you
你必须放弃剧本，然后你
got to do long form content and here's
得写长篇内容了，这是……
my prediction the prediction is is we're
我的预测是，我们
going to see the biggest CEOs in the
去拜访业内最大的CEO们
world clamoring to get onto this podcast
全世界都在争相收听这个播客。
and other podcasts like it they're all
以及其他类似的播客，它们都
going to be wanting desperately to build
将会非常渴望建造
their personal brand because they know
他们之所以能打造个人品牌，是因为他们知道
that the long form unscripted podcast is
长篇无脚本播客是
the only way to hire talented people the
招聘优秀人才的唯一途径
only way to get loyal customers the only
获得忠实客户的唯一途径
way to keep investors happy it's going
让投资者满意的方法正在发生
to be the key to the entire shooting
成为整个拍摄过程的关键
match is that the CEO of a big company
匹配项是：一家大公司的首席执行官
has to become human and they have to be
必须变成人类，他们必须是
unscripted and what advice would you
即兴发挥，你会给出什么建议？
give them because you consult for a lot
给他们是因为你提供了很多咨询服务。
of people they come to you for advice
人们会来向你寻求建议
whether it's the biggest influencers of
无论是最大的影响者
the world or CEOs if if you were giving
世界或首席执行官们，如果你是给予
them advice on how to achieve that goal
他们就如何实现该目标向他们提供建议
what would you say well I I mostly talk
你会怎么说？嗯，我主要都在说话。
to entrepreneurs and I mostly care about
对于创业者而言，我最关心的是
entrepreneurs and the advice I give to
企业家以及我给他们的建议
entrepreneurs is work your way up the
创业者就是一步步往上爬。
podcast pyramid um so there's literally
播客金字塔，嗯，所以实际上有
thousands and thousands of podcasts that
成千上万个播客
get a few thousand views just go on
获得几千次浏览量，继续吧。
those go on lots of them um if you do a
很多情况下都会用到，嗯，如果你这样做的话
good job you'll eventually be invited
干得好，你最终会被邀请的。
onto a slightly bigger one and you'll
换到稍大一点的上面，你就会
eventually be invited onto a slightly
最终被邀请参加一个略微
bigger one again and there's this
又一个更大的，还有这个
pyramid of you know there's there's a
你知道，金字塔里有一个
few podcasts as big as yours but there's
像你们这样规模的播客不多，但也有。
thousands of podcasts in every single
每家每户都有成千上万个播客
Nation Vertical where anyone can go on
Nation Vertical，任何人都可以访问
and you know talk about who they are and
然后你知道，谈谈他们是谁
what they do so for any entrepreneur my
他们这样做对任何企业家来说都是如此
challenge to them the ones that I'm
向他们发起挑战，那些我……
working with is an absolute minimum I
合作的最低限度是我
want them to create 10 to 20 uh hours of
希望他们创作 10 到 20 小时的作品
watch time in the year ahead so I want
未来一年我打算花些时间观看比赛，所以我想
people to go on 10 podcasts that last
人们会参加10期持续播出的播客节目
for 2 hours or 1 to two hours and I want
两个小时或者一到两个小时，我想要
them talking through their business
他们谈论他们的业务
story their origin their mission their
故事、起源、使命
Vision uh you know how they got started
Vision，你知道他们是怎么起步的。
the types of people they employ the
他们雇佣的人员类型
types of customer problems they solve
他们解决的客户问题类型
the outcomes they deliver all of that
他们所取得的成果都是如此。
put it all into a podcast get good at
把所有内容都做成播客，努力做好这件事
that format you publish in lots of ways
你可以用多种方式发布这种格式的内容。
right you publish written form you
你有权发表你的书面形式
publish in video is there anything at
发布视频有什么问题吗？
all that's if there was one single thing
这一切的前提是，如果真有那么一件事的话。
that's helped become better at speaking
这有助于提高我的口语能力。
or communicating ideas and you can't say
或者交流想法，但你不能说
no I'll take away the restraints what
不，我会解除束缚。
would you say it is Frameworks
你会说它是框架吗？
Frameworks what does that mean so you
框架是什么意思？所以你
need communication Frameworks so if I'm
需要沟通框架，这样如果我
introducing myself uh to someone I use
向我常用的人介绍我自己
something called name same Fame aim in a
某种叫做名字的东西，同样的名声，目标是……
game so we can break that down pleas um
游戏，所以我们可以详细分析一下，请……
what is my name and my business name uh
我的名字和公司名称是什么？
what is uh what is it that I'm the same
到底是什么？我为什么还是一样？
as that you already understand
正如你已经明白的那样
okay let's pause there why is why does
好的，我们先暂停一下。为什么是……？为什么……
that matter uh when people are storing
那很重要，呃，当人们储存的时候。
information they need to open a folder
他们需要的信息才能打开文件夹
and they want to open a folder that's
他们想打开一个文件夹，该文件夹是
very easy to label so um they don't want
很容易贴标签，所以他们不想贴。
to open a folder that says like I'm an
打开一个文件夹，上面写着“我是一个”
energetic healer that works with
与……合作的能量治疗师
transmutational objects that that
嬗变对象，即
transcend time space and blah blah blah
超越时空等等等等
they want to go oh you know you're a
他们想说，哦，你知道你是一个
life coach okay great I understand that
人生教练：好的，我明白了。
or you're a vet okay cool you're a
或者你是兽医，好的，酷，你是……
consultant you're you know you're a
顾问，你知道你是……
software company got it so it's like
软件公司拿到了，所以就像
just the most basic thing that I can
我能做的最基本的事情
then hang everything on that um cuz I
然后把所有东西都挂在那上面，嗯，因为我
already understand it so name same Fame
已经明白了，所以就叫它同样的名声吧
so Fame is like what makes you
所以，名声就像是什么造就了你
interesting what makes you fascinating
是什么让你如此迷人？
what big brands have you worked with
你曾与哪些知名品牌合作过？
what interesting projects have you
你有哪些有趣的项目？
landed uh so anything that would make
着陆了，呃，所以任何能……
you stand out any big numbers any awards
你在任何大数字或奖项方面都脱颖而出
any big names um any of that would be
任何大牌明星，嗯，任何那些都算在内。
your fame um so name same Fame aim what
你的名气，嗯，所以名字一样，名气目标是什么？
are you working on in the next 90 days
接下来90天内，您将致力于哪些工作？
and then game what is your bigger Vision
然后，游戏环节，你更大的愿景是什么？
what do you want to achieve the next 3
未来三年你想实现什么目标？
to 6 years I think a lot of people
我觉得很多人会持续6年。
aren't even clear on that a lot of
很多人甚至都不清楚这一点
people aren't and that's why the
人们并非如此，这就是为什么
framework's powerful because it forces
框架之所以强大，是因为它强制执行
you to get clear on it if you then get
如果你能弄清楚这一点，你就会明白。
clear on it you can introduce yourself
明确之后，你就可以自我介绍了。
with power and authority uh you can do
凭借权力和权威，你可以做到
the beginning of a podcast you can be on
你可以参与的播客的开头部分
a stage just introducing yourself at a
一个自我介绍的舞台
networking function believe it or not
网络功能，信不信由你
you can cram all of that into 30 seconds
你可以把所有这些都压缩到30秒内完成。
MH and so going back to this point of
MH，所以回到这一点
preparation right so one of the big
准备工作做得很好，所以其中一项重要内容是……
things that is going to give me a
能给我带来什么的东西
significant competitive advantage if I'm
如果我拥有显著的竞争优势
building a business is personal branding
打造企业就是个人品牌塑造
what else do you think someone like me
你觉得像我这样的人还能做什么？
at the start of my career needs to
在我职业生涯的初期，我需要
understand about the game of personal
了解个人游戏
branding is there are there any
品牌推广是否存在？
particular platforms I should be aiming
我应该重点关注哪些平台？
at a particular upload Cadence a
在特定的上传节奏
particular type of content here's what
这里指的是特定类型的内容。
you need to
你需要
know you need to know that humans have a
你需要知道，人类拥有
limited ability to remember names and
记忆名字的能力有限
faces they only have a small number of
他们只有少数几张面孔
slots in their brain for who they
他们大脑中为他们自己预留了位置。
remember and the number is about 1,500
记住，这个数字大约是1500。
in in
在
total um and it's about 150 that you can
总共大约是150个，你可以
kind of remember well and these are
我记得很清楚，这些都是
called Dunbar numbers and Dunbar numbers
称为邓巴数和邓巴数
basically said you've got a few slots
基本上就是说你还有几个空位。
for your family and then some more slots
为您的家人，还有一些老虎机
for friends then you've got your
如果是朋友，那你就有你的
acquaintances right out to 1500 people
从熟人到1500人
that you can easily put a name in a face
你可以轻易地将名字与面孔对应起来。
to in order to you for you to be
为了让你成为
successful you've got to get into
要想成功，你必须进入
people's head they have to kind of know
人们的头脑里，他们必须大致了解这一点。
who you are um in order to do that they
你是谁？嗯，为了做到这一点，他们
have to spend time with you they have to
他们必须花时间陪你，他们必须
have rep uh repetition with you and they
他们和你都有重复的习惯，而且他们
have to see in multiple contexts so the
必须在多种语境下看待这个问题
research says
研究显示
7114 7 hours 11 interactions on four
7114 7 小时 11 次互动（四人）
platforms per in order for you to
每个平台，以便您
remember me okay total so for example
记住我，好的，总共，例如
you and I we've now connected a few
你我现在已经联系上了一些
times um so we have probably clocked up
嗯，所以我们可能已经计时完毕了。
maybe 7 hours together now what that
或许现在已经在一起7个小时了，那又怎样？
means is that uh if I bumped into you at
意思是说，呃，如果我碰巧遇到你……
a conference even if I was on one side
即使我身处会议的一方，也应该参加会议。
of the room and you're on the other side
房间的另一边，你正对着它。
of the room you'd say oh there's Daniel
你会说，哦，那是丹尼尔。
your brain would immediately go Oh
你的大脑会立刻发出“哦”的声音。
there's Daniel I'll walk over I'll say
丹尼尔在那儿，我走过去跟他说。
hello
你好
because we've spent enough time together
因为我们在一起的时间足够长了。
um now there's this phenomenon called
嗯，现在有一种现象叫做
parasocial relationships parasocial
准社会关系 准社会
relationships are basically one-sided
人际关系基本上是单方面的。
relationships it it's how we feel
人际关系，关键在于我们的感受。
towards famous people so we think that
对名人，我们认为
we know George Clooney we think that we
我们认识乔治·克鲁尼，我们认为我们
know Angelina Jolly we don't it's a
我们并不认识安吉丽娜·朱莉，这是一个
parasocial relationship that person
与此人存在准社会关系
we've spent time with them through their
我们曾花时间陪伴他们度过他们的时光
movies through their media appearances
通过媒体曝光而拍摄的电影
and therefore because they've clocked up
因此，因为他们已经积累了足够的时间
7-Eleven 4 with us we then feel that we
与我们一起在7-Eleven 4号店购物，我们就会感到我们
know them is this making sense makes
了解他们是否有意义
perfect sense yeah so what we have to do
完全正确，所以我们该怎么做？
is build parasocial relationships at
建立准社会关系
scale so what we have to do is put out
规模化，所以我们必须做的就是推出
enough stuff where anyone can spend 7
东西多到任何人都能花7美元
hours 11 interactions for on four
11 小时互动，共四次
platforms so when I work with
所以当我与平台合作时
entrepreneurs here's one of the
这里是企业家之一
questions I always ask I say if I was to
我总是问的问题，我说如果我要……
block out tomorrow and I'm going to take
明天空出来，我要去
all day to watch read or listen to
整天用来看书或听书
everything that you've got available
你拥有的一切
online and uh I'm looking for things
我在网上找东西。
that are on message that tell me about
那些在消息中告诉我
who you are who you serve what it is
你是谁？你服务于谁？它是什么？
that you do can I spend all day going
你能让我花一整天时间去吗？
through your online environment and just
通过你的网络环境，而且
fill the entire day and most people say
把一整天都填满，大多数人都会这么说
no and then occasionally some people say
不，但偶尔也会有人说
yes and they say yeah actually you can
是的，他们说，实际上你可以
I've been on a few podcasts I've got an
我上过几个播客节目，我有一个
audio book that I released I've got some
我发布的有声书里有一些
videos on YouTube I've got some posts on
我在 YouTube 上发布了一些视频和帖子。
LinkedIn you could go through all of
在LinkedIn上，你可以浏览所有内容。
that those are the ones that are scaling
正是这些正在扩大规模的企业。
really fast because they've put in the
速度很快，因为他们已经投入了
work to be scalable they can build a
为了实现可扩展性，他们可以构建一个
parasocial relationship like that and if
像这样的准社会关系，如果
we drill down into the art of building a
我们深入探讨建造的艺术
parasocial relationship because it's
因为这是准社会关系。
funny at the start of the conversation
对话开始时很有趣
you said that these are the new rules in
你说这些是新规则
business and the world because of these
由于这些原因，商业和世界都受到了影响。
macro changes but at some point the new
宏观变化，但在某种程度上，新的
rules become the old rules again when
当规则再次变回旧规则时
everyone listens to this podcast and you
每个人都在听这个播客，而你
kind of see it at the moment on LinkedIn
目前在领英上好像看到了这种情况。
LinkedIn is a um a long stream of
LinkedIn 是一个很长的……
professional personal brand builders
专业个人品牌建设者
whereas 5 years ago it wasn't the the
而五年前并非如此。
case but the but the numbers are still
但情况是，但数字仍然
only 1% of people are doing it 99% of
只有1%的人这样做，99%的人
people aren't posting weekly so we're
人们不再每周都发帖，所以我们……
still early we're still way early but is
现在还早，我们离目标还很远，但是……
there is there a framework for creating
是否存在一个用于创建的框架
some kind of differentiation
某种程度的差异化
amongst a noisy crowd yeah so the the
在嘈杂的人群中，是的，所以
differentiation so a lot of people ask
区分，所以很多人都会问
me about differentiation so let's talk
跟我谈谈差异化，我们来聊聊吧。
about what makes you different and to
关于是什么让你与众不同，以及
you to talk about this let's go through
我们来谈谈这个，一起来看看。
a scenario and the scenario is that
一个场景，而这个场景是：
you're walking down the street and
你正走在街上，
you're walking down Oxford Street and
你正沿着牛津街走着，
it's thousand thousand of people really
真的是成千上万的人。
busy street and as you're walking down
繁忙的街道，当你沿着这条路走下去
your brain has this lyic system that
你的大脑里有这样一个酸性系统，
just deletes people so you just kind of
它会直接删除用户，所以你只能……
see people as blobs not to hit and you
把人看作是不要打的肉块，你
just kind of walk and if I stop you at
你就随便走走，如果我拦住你……
the end of the street and I say how many
街的尽头，我问有多少人
people do you remember seeing you'll go
你还记得见过哪些人吗？你会去的。
none I don't remember seeing anyone in
我不记得看到过任何人。
particular if I said describe some of
特别是如果我说描述一些
the people what they were wearing I
人们的穿着
can't remember anything so your brain is
什么都记不起来了，所以你的大脑……
extremely good at deleting messages and
非常擅长删除信息和
this is what's happening in our
这就是我们正在经历的事情
marketplaces people just delete
市场上的人们直接删除
everything
一切
here's what doesn't get deleted so
以下是不会被删除的内容
there's there's five things that will
有五件事会
not be deleted by the brain the first
首先，大脑不会删除它。
one is scary so if something is scary we
一个很可怕，所以如果某件事很可怕，我们
pay attention to it this is why the news
注意它，这就是新闻的由来
has been so successful for many many
对许多人来说都非常成功
years because they say if it bleeds it
多年，因为他们说如果它流血了
leads if it's scary if it's horrible
如果很可怕，如果很恐怖，就会引出问题。
people will watch it let's find the the
人们会看的，让我们找到答案。
worst possible things that happen today
今天发生的最糟糕的事情
let's blow them up and put them in
我们把它们炸掉，然后放进……
everyone's house so that they spend time
大家一起去家里，这样他们就可以花时间待在一起。
watching uh watching the news so so be a
看新闻，所以……
scary person so be scary right
既然是可怕的人，那就得可怕才行，对吧？
uh the next one is be strange so if you
呃，下一个是“奇怪”，所以如果你
saw someone walking down the street
看到有人沿着街道走
dressed as a giant hot dog you'd say oh
如果你打扮成一个巨大的热狗，你会说“哦”。
I remember the guy who was dressed as a
我记得那个打扮成……的人
giant hot dog cuz it's so strange
巨型热狗，因为它太奇怪了
peacocking yep well peacocking yeah uh
炫耀？嗯，炫耀？是啊，呃……
you could try yeah exactly you could
你可以试试，没错，你可以
wear that big kind of hat that you've
戴上你那顶大帽子
got in the cupboard that uh that you
进了橱柜，呃，你
don't talk about M uh and then the next
别提M了，嗯，然后是下一个
one's sexy so so we've got strange we've
一个很性感，所以我们很奇怪，我们有
got scary we've got sexy now these are
变得可怕，我们现在变得性感了，这些都是
three things that most businesses don't
大多数企业不做的三件事
want to be so most business can't stand
想成为大多数企业都无法忍受的那种人
out and sexy even if they wanted to be
即使他们想，也要表现得性感迷人
that most people can't pull that one off
大多数人都做不到这一点。
anyway um so only a few lucky people get
总之，只有少数幸运儿才能得到
to do that one um but actually the last
要做那件事，嗯，但实际上是最后一件事。
two are the ones that are most useful
其中两个是最有用的。
and that is providing free value so free
这就是提供免费价值，所以是免费的。
things anyone who gives free value away
任何提供免费价值的人都会这样做
is immediately stand
立即站立
out okay we've got to make sure that it
好的，我们必须确保它
is value it's got to be value because
就是价值，它必须是价值，因为
everyone thinks what they're doing is
每个人都认为自己正在做的事情是
value totally it's got to be something
绝对有价值，它肯定有某种意义。
that people would have otherwise paid
人们原本会为此付费
for um and it has to be beautifully
嗯，它必须很漂亮。
packaged so if I hand you a piece of
包装好了，所以如果我递给你一块
jewelry in a plastic bag you're going to
你要把珠宝放在塑料袋里
think oh it's fake or it's you know
想想，哦，这是假的，或者你知道的。
stolen or it's you know not real or
偷来的，或者你知道的，不是真的，或者
something like that it's cheap right if
类似这样的东西很便宜，对吧？
I hand it to you in a beautiful box and
我用漂亮的盒子把它递给你。
it's beautifully wrapped you're going to
包装精美，你即将……
say oh that's a very thoughtful gift so
说：“哦，这是一份非常贴心的礼物。”
it's the way that it's packaged and it's
问题在于它的包装方式，而且……
also you know that it's actually
你也知道，实际上
something that people would otherwise
人们原本会……
pay for so providing free
付费才能提供免费服务
value um and also being familiar which
价值嗯，而且熟悉哪个
is clocking up the 7-Eleven 4 so free
7-Eleven 4 号店正在免费营业。
and familiar are the two things that
熟悉和熟悉是这两件事
anyone can apply so look at let's look
任何人都可以申请，所以我们来看看。
at you for example you spend tens of
例如，你花几十美元
thousands of pounds producing episodes
制作剧集需要花费数千英镑
of this show and you just make it freely
这个节目，你完全可以自由发挥。
available on um YouTube I Wish that's
可以在 YouTube 上找到，我希望如此。
how much I spent well each each show
我每场演出都花了多少钱
right um so you're putting all this
对，嗯，所以你把所有这些都放进去了。
energy and effort in and you're putting
你投入了精力和努力。
high production value you're going to
你将会获得很高的制作价值
the expense of getting all these great
获取所有这些伟大成就的费用
guests all of this stuff's going on and
宾客们，所有这些事情都在发生，
then you're making it free for so many
这样一来，你就让很多人免费享受这项服务了。
people you're including people in
你把这些人包括在内
conversations that they normally
他们通常的对话
wouldn't have access to so you have
你无法获得，所以你有
clocked up enormous amounts of standout
积累了大量杰出成就
value for people because you've been
因为你一直以来都对人们有价值
consistent so 7-Eleven four people have
所以7-Eleven有四个人，情况一直如此。
spent 7 hours 11 interactions four
耗时7小时，互动11次，共4次
locations with you um and also you've
和你在一起的地方，嗯，还有你……
done free value so you've given a lot
你创造了很多免费价值，付出了很多。
for free so um essentially those are the
免费，所以基本上就是这些。
two um and you're also strange so so
两个嗯，而且你也很奇怪，所以
with those three things you've been able
有了这三件事，你就能够
to uh succeed massive we do have scary
为了取得巨大的成功，我们确实有可怕的
conversations as well I have to be
对话中我也必须如此
honest we do the nuclear bomb
说实话，我们确实制造了核弹。
conversation sexy millionaire so you've
与性感百万富翁的对话，所以你已经
got that as well yeah sexy as well thank
我也明白了，嗯，也很性感，谢谢。
you so much for that you've got all five
你真是太厉害了，你已经拿到全部五个了。
going on but when you were saying this I
事情还在继续，但当你这么说的时候，我
was actually thinking of this as a a
我其实是这么想的……
marketing framework for Brands as well I
品牌营销框架
was thinking of that kid that I met on
我想起了我在……遇到的那个孩子
the in the prominade in Cape Town with a
在开普敦的滨海大道上
couple and I was thinking if they were
一对情侣，我在想他们是不是
starting out with an idea today in a
今天从一个想法开始
very saturated environment like Oxford
像牛津这样高度饱和的环境
Street in London pulling in on some of
伦敦街头的一些车辆正在驶入
these actually gives you such an unfair
这实际上会给你带来极大的不公平。
advantage to get to get going and I I
有优势可以开始行动，而且我
know this myself because when I was 18
我自己也知道这一点，因为我18岁的时候就明白。
one of the things that I realized in
我意识到的其中一件事是
hindsight was working for me was I
事后诸葛亮对我来说真是太有用了。
looked a bit strange I had this big
看起来有点奇怪，我有一个很大的
which some people will find photos of
有些人会找到照片
this big hat that I used to wear and I
我以前常戴的那顶大帽子，还有我
would wear it everywhere I wore it
我会把它穿在任何我穿它的地方。
because my hair was but it became
因为我的头发很糟糕，但它变成了
this like this distinctive thing that at
这就像这个独特的东西，在
conferences at events on my LinkedIn it
我在LinkedIn上发布的会议和活动信息
became part of my brand that's why I
成为我品牌的一部分，这就是我的原因。
interjected with the word peacocking
插话道：“炫耀”
because looking slightly different in
因为看起来略有不同
some way does actually it does work yeah
某种程度上来说，它确实有效，是的。
it cuts cuts through the noise the other
它能穿透噪音，另一个
thing too let's go to your friends the
还有一件事，我们去你朋友家吧。
20 Oney olds in Cape Town one of the
开普敦的 20 Oney Olds 是其中之一
first things we can do for free is we
我们首先可以免费做的事情是：
can um productize what's called the demo
可以将所谓的演示产品化吗？
and the customer needs analysis so let's
以及客户需求分析，那么我们开始吧。
get really tactical here um when it
这里要真正讲究策略，嗯，当……
comes to what most people do to launch a
说到大多数人如何启动一个
business they make a real focus on the
他们非常重视的业务
supply of what they do so if they let's
如果他们允许的话，他们就会提供他们所需要的东西。
say they want to do a drinks business
他们说他们想开一家饮料店
they're going to like talk to bottling
他们会和装瓶厂谈谈。
companies and they're going to talk to
公司，他们将与……进行洽谈
you know how much do I have to spend
你知道我得花多少钱吗？
buying the fruit to put in the tea and
买水果放进茶里
do all that sort of stuff they're
他们会做所有这些事情
thinking about the supply of what they
思考他们的供应情况
do um if they're going to launch a
如果他们打算推出……
consulting company they're thinking
他们正在考虑的咨询公司
about oh do I have the right MBA
关于“我是否拥有合适的MBA学位”这个问题。
qualifications and all of this stuff is
资格证书以及所有这些东西都是
the supply side of what they do what we
他们所做的事情的供给侧，我们所做的
want to do when we launch anything is we
我们推出任何产品时都想做的是……
want to test the demand of what we do so
想测试一下我们所做的事情是否受市场需求影响。
testing demand the best way to do this
测试需要最好的方法来做到这一点。
is or one of the best ways to do this is
是，或者说，最好的方法之一是
to productize the demo and a customer
将演示产品化并吸引客户
needs analysis so that is where we go
需要进行需求分析，这就是我们要去的地方。
around and we sell a presentation that
我们四处兜售一种演示文稿，
might be 15 minutes to an hour where we
可能需要15分钟到1个小时，我们
present what it is that we can do and
展示我们能做什么，
how it works and the principles of how
它的工作原理和原则
it works and then we collect enough data
它奏效了，然后我们收集了足够的数据
to identify whether you've got the need
确定你是否需要
for that product so it's called a
所以该产品被称为
customer needs analysis so the demo and
客户需求分析，因此需要进行演示和
the customer needs analysis you can
您可以进行客户需求分析
package that up so it feels like a
把它包装起来，让它感觉像是一个
product it feels like something free of
这款产品感觉像是自由自在的。
value um so give me an example then
价值嘛，嗯，那给我举个例子吧。
using I'm going to launch a a new coffee
我打算推出一款新的咖啡
yeah and it's the the point of
是的，这就是重点。
difference with my coffee is it is going
我的咖啡和它不一样的地方在于它正在
to be if
如果
Fido fantastic so uh let's imagine that
菲多太棒了，所以，让我们想象一下……
we're going to sell that through
我们将通过以下方式出售它
retailers yeah and the real customer is
零售商是的，真正的顾客是
not the end User it's the retailer who's
不是最终用户，而是零售商。
going to stock it so what I would do is
我打算进货，所以我会这样做：
I would say we've got a new coffee brand
我认为我们推出了一款新的咖啡品牌。
coming and it's all about coffee for
来了，一切都与咖啡有关。
libido boosting um and what we want to
提高性欲，嗯，以及我们想要的
do is we want to present to you the data
我们想向您展示这些数据。
the research as to how this coffee works
关于这种咖啡如何运作的研究
and why it works and all of that sort of
以及它为什么有效等等。
stuff we want to show you the branding
我们想向您展示的品牌信息
we want to show you like what this is
我们想向您展示这是什么。
going to look like and then also we want
看起来会像这样，而且我们也想要
to do is set up a customer needs
要做的是确定客户需求
analysis where we collect the data from
分析过程中，我们会收集来自以下来源的数据：
several of your locations to find out in
您需要前往以下几个地点进行查找
advance whether people would sample this
进一步探讨人们是否会尝试这种产品
product whether they'd buy this product
他们是否会购买这款产品
how much they'd spend um so we will at
他们会花多少钱，嗯，所以我们会……
our expense do the clipboard or we'll do
我们的费用由剪贴板决定，或者我们会这样做
the um weight list campaign um or we
体重清单活动，或者我们
will uh collect the data uh through um
将会通过某种方式收集数据
you know a coming soon promotion so
你知道，即将推出的促销活动就是这样。
essentially what we're going to do is
我们基本上要做的事情是：
we're going to present the data and
我们将展示数据，
we're going to do the customer needs
我们将满足客户的需求
analysis or present the demo the
分析或演示
customer needs analysis and that's all
分析客户需求，仅此而已。
going to be packaged up as our first
将会作为我们的第一批产品打包出售。
thing now mind you we may have no coffee
请注意，现在我们可能没有咖啡了。
at this point we may actually have no
到那时，我们可能实际上并没有
physical product but big retailers they
实体产品，但大型零售商
move slow anyway even if you had product
即使你有产品，也要放慢速度。
they wouldn't buy it today so they're
他们今天不会买，所以他们是
going to say oh that's fantastic that's
我会说，哦，那太棒了，那真是
what we'd like to do we want to collect
我们想做的是收集
the data and we want to see the demo and
我们需要数据，也想看看演示。
see the research so by packaging that up
看看这项研究，然后把它打包起来。
as a first step uh you're actually
作为第一步，你实际上是
providing initial value do you know one
提供初始值，你知道吗？
of the things that I don't think I've
我不认为我拥有的事情
ever talked about that I think um
我想，我们之前有没有谈论过这个？嗯……
entrepreneurs and people that are
企业家和那些人
founding companies should really
创始公司真的应该
consider
考虑
is if you're thinking about let's say
比如说，如果你在想……
writing a
写
book instead of writing the book and
与其写书，不如买书。
then hoping it does well what you should
然后希望它能做好你该做的事。
do is you should take the book ID you
你应该做的就是记下图书ID。
have and then run it as a Facebook ad
拥有它，然后将其作为 Facebook 广告投放。
run a hundred different titles um and
运行一百个不同的标题，嗯，
when people click on that Facebook ad
当人们点击那则 Facebook 广告时
they hit waiting list yes now in that
是的，他们现在已经进入候补名单了。
whole process what you've just done
你刚才做的整个过程
there is you figured out the exact
你已经弄清楚了确切情况。
percentage of people that will click on
点击率
um a 100 different ideas so for my
嗯，我有100个不同的想法，所以对于我
upcoming book one of the things that I
即将出版的书是我即将出版的一本书。
did and some people listening to this
确实如此，而且有些人正在听这个
now would have seen the ads is I ran 70
如果我跑了70趟，现在应该就能看到广告了。
book titles beautiful so 70 books like
书名很美，所以有70本书喜欢
this would have popped up in your feed
这条消息应该会出现在你的动态消息里。
and people have clicked on them and
人们点击了它们，
they've said I want I would like that
他们说我想要，我喜欢那样
book they put their email address in or
他们在书里输入了他们的电子邮件地址
something like that and now I have this
类似这样，现在我有了这个
data and I can tell off the top of my
数据表明，我可以立即判断出这一点。
head which is the most successful 15% of
最成功的15%的领导者
people clicked a certain one and the
人们点击了某个链接，然后
worst performing one was clicked by 0.3%
表现最差的那个点击量仅为0.3%。
of people and I could have written a
很多人，我本来可以写一篇
book um about that 0.3 and my maths
书里提到了0.3和我的数学
isn't exceptional but the very between a
并非特殊，而是介于两者之间
0.3% conversion and a 15% conversion is
0.3%的转化率和15%的转化率分别是
like what is that 1,500% or something
比如说，1500% 之类的到底是什么意思？
crazy um and and it was and it was cost
疯狂的，嗯，而且是，而且是代价
me 200 quid to run the test yeah um
我花了200英镑做这个测试，嗯。
that's the beauty of Facebook ads you
这就是Facebook广告的魅力所在。
know you can do a I mean at any given
我知道你可以做到，我的意思是，在任何给定情况下
time we've got hundreds of different
我们已经有数百种不同的
variations of ads running and they it's
广告投放方式多种多样，而且它们是……
like you know it's basically The Hunger
你知道，这基本上就是《饥饿》
Games for which ad performs better um
广告效果更好的游戏
and people don't do this sort of stuff
人们不会做这种事
and this is how professionals like
这就是专业人士喜欢
yourself launch businesses so um with
自己创业，所以嗯……
anything that I'm launching whether it's
任何我推出的产品，无论是……
a book or a product or a new business
一本书、一件产品或一项新业务
we're going to run a set of Facebook ads
我们将投放一系列 Facebook 广告
probably 10 20 30 different variations
可能有 10、20、30 种不同的变体
when you click on the link it says this
点击链接后，它会显示以下内容
product's no longer available in your
您所在地区已不再提供该产品。
area or this product is not yet
该地区或该产品尚未
available in your area M um but you can
您所在地区有售，M um，但您可以
join the waiting list click here to join
加入候补名单，点击此处加入
the waiting list now once people click
现在，一旦有人点击，候补名单就会显示出来。
to join the waiting
加入等待
list uh that's where we ask about five
列表，嗯，我们就是在那里问到五个问题的。
or six key questions so there's this
或者说，有六个关键问题，所以就有了这些。
thing inside people's head called the
人们头脑中叫做……的东西
situational model and the situational
情境模型和情境
model is where am I now where do I want
模型是我现在所在的地方，我想要去哪里。
to be what's in my way and what do I
成为我前进道路上的障碍，我该怎么办？
perceive as the path of least resistance
将其视为阻力最小的路径
so all the questions that we ask are
所以我们提出的所有问题都是
tell me about who you are today which
请告诉我你现在的样子，
best describes your current situation
最能描述您当前状况的词语
tell me about where you want to be which
告诉我你想去哪里，哪个
best describes the outcome that you're
最能描述你所面临的结果的是
looking for from this product or
正在寻找此产品或
service uh what's in the way which best
服务方面，呃，有什么障碍物？哪个最好？
describes the reason you've not been
描述了你一直没来的原因
able to get that outcome in the past mhm
过去能够取得那种结果，嗯。
and what are you currently considering
你目前正在考虑什么？
as an option for getting that out
作为一种将其取出的选项
outcome right so those are the key four
结果正确，所以这四个是关键点。
key questions then we might ask some
那么，我们可能会问一些关键问题。
price questions uh what price do you
价格问题，呃，你们的价格是多少？
feel would be a fair price to pay what
感觉这是值得付出的合理代价
price do you think would be so cheap
你觉得价格会这么便宜吗？
that it would make you question the
这会让你质疑
quality what price would be so expensive
质量这么好，价格怎么会这么贵？
um that you would no longer be able to
嗯，你将无法再……
afford this so we'll ask a few pricing
我们负担得起，所以我们会问一些价格问题。
questions so we don't just get people to
提出问题，这样我们就不会只是让人们……
join a waiting list we're saying we want
加入等候名单，我们说我们想要
to understand this situational model
理解这种情境模型
because here's the interesting thing
因为有趣的是……
especially with other products not
尤其是与其他产品不兼容
necessarily books but with other
不一定是书籍，但还有其他
products sometimes you get a lower
有时产品价格会更低
clickthrough rate sometimes you get um
点击率有时会达到……
what appears to be cheaper marketing but
看似更便宜的营销方式，但
it attracts the wrong person yeah and
是的，它会吸引错误的人。
then sometimes you get a poorer
有时你会变得更穷
performing marketing campaign so this
开展营销活动，所以这
one might produce leads at10 a lead this
有人可能会以每条线索 10 的价格生产线索。
one might produce leads at 20 pound a
有人可能会以每磅 20 美元的价格生产铅块。
lead but this one might be attracting
领先，但这个可能更有吸引力。
students who are broke and this one
那些没钱的学生，还有这个
might be attracting chief executive
可能会吸引首席执行官
officers who are on 500 Grand a year I'd
年薪50万美元的警官，我会……
rather pay 2020 for that client than £10
宁愿为这位客户支付 2020 年的费用，也不愿支付 10 英镑。
for that client M so by getting the
对于客户 M，通过获取
situational model uh we can actually
情境模型，嗯，我们实际上可以
then understand which is the best
然后了解哪个最好
campaign is there anything else that's
竞选活动还有其他内容吗？
really sort of pertinent to testing if
这确实与测试有关，如果
my idea has legs and I want to just add
我的想法可行，我只想补充一点。
an element to this which is we're not
其中的一个因素是我们并非
just talking here about the first idea
这里只是谈谈第一个想法。
we're talking about every product you
我们正在讨论你使用的每一种产品。
then release in the future every product
然后在未来发布所有产品
every business even your marketing
每个企业，甚至包括你的营销。
campaigns and everything you do yeah the
是的，竞选活动以及你所做的一切。
the world is moving so fast that if
世界变化如此之快，以至于如果
you're an existing business listening to
您是一家正在收听的现有企业
this let's say you're a big business you
假设你是一家大企业……
do tens of millions of profit you're
赚取数千万美元的利润
going to be pivoting into new products
即将转型开发新产品
new markets new territories you're going
你要去新市场，新领域。
to be um trying to attract different age
嗯，试图吸引不同年龄段的人
demographics you're going to be you know
人口统计数据表明，你将会成为你知道的那种人。
all of that sort of stuff this is one of
诸如此类的东西，这是其中之一。
the rules of the current economy is
当前经济的规则是
about data and testing you've got to be
关于数据和测试，你必须是
really fast with how fast you can
速度真的很快，你能做到如此之快
prototype and test and get the data um
制作原型并进行测试，然后获取数据。
so we love intro events where you just
所以我们喜欢这种介绍活动，你只需要……
simply do an introduction event on Zoom
只需在 Zoom 上举办一个介绍会即可
uh to talk to customers um so we're
呃，和顾客交谈，嗯，所以我们是
introducing you to this new coffee um
向您介绍这款新的咖啡
what do you think uh come and join the
你觉得怎么样？来加入我们吧！
introduction event we're going to share
我们将分享的介绍活动
with you some research we're going to
我们将和你一起做一些研究。
have a guest speaker who you've already
邀请一位你已经认识的嘉宾演讲。
heard of right so that would be an
听说过吧，所以那将是一个
introduction event um I'm a big fan of
介绍活动 嗯，我是……的忠实粉丝
discussion groups discussion groups are
讨论组 讨论组是
awesome for testing an idea so let's say
非常适合用来检验一个想法，比如说
um it's a discussion group you know
嗯，这是一个讨论组，你知道的。
let's say you're doing a a new brand of
假设你正在打造一个新品牌
coffee and it's for sex coffee sex
咖啡，而且是为了性爱，咖啡性爱
coffee right sexy sexy coffee um so yeah
咖啡，对，性感的咖啡，嗯，所以，是的
we're going to do the sexy coffee
我们要喝那种性感咖啡
discussion group right and it's
讨论组对，就是这样。
basically we're launching a new product
我们基本上是要推出一款新产品。
um and it's all about uh bringing sexy
嗯，这一切都与展现性感有关。
back to Coffee um and if you love having
回到咖啡的话题，嗯，如果你喜欢……
coffee and you want uh want to be part
咖啡，你想……你想参与其中
of this new brand that we're launching
我们即将推出的这个新品牌
join the discussion group discussion
加入讨论组讨论
groups are pretty wild so I'll give you
各个团体都挺疯狂的，所以我给你讲讲。
two examples of discussion groups one of
讨论小组的两个例子，其中之一是
our clients um Gabriella Rosa she uh ran
我们的客户，嗯，Gabriella Rosa，她，呃，跑了
a clinic um and it was a fertility
一家诊所，嗯，那是一家生育诊所
clinic and it was about natural
诊所，而且是关于自然疗法的。
fertility breakthroughs um and what she
生育方面的突破，嗯，还有她
did is she had a physical Clinic that
她做的就是去了一家诊所。
was running a traditional way she wanted
她想以传统的方式经营。
to go and be more digital so she
为了更加数字化，她
launched an online Discussion Group
发起了一个在线讨论组
where she said this is a discussion
她说这是一场讨论
group for people who want uh fertility
想要生育的人们的群组
breakthroughs 23,000 people joined the
突破性进展：23000人加入
discussion group right and it was super
讨论小组对，而且非常棒
active and she never had to worry about
她性格活泼，从不用担心什么。
customers ever again and she built her
她再次拥有了顾客，并建立了她的
business then globally uh from there she
然后是全球商业，呃，从那里开始她
wrote a book and she changed her
她写了一本书，她改变了自己
business she went from a physical
她从一家实体店转行到一家实体店。
location to a digital business um but it
地理位置对于一家数字企业来说，嗯，但是
it started with a discussion group um
一切都始于一个讨论小组。
another guy one of our clients Max he
另一个家伙，也是我们的客户之一，Max，他
sold a business not for crazy amounts of
出售公司并非为了获得天价报酬
money but a decent sale and he decided
他花了不少钱，但卖得还不错，于是他决定了。
he wanted to um spend time with people
他想和人们待在一起。
who had uh family officers and family
那些有家庭官员和家庭的人
officers have hundreds of millions of
官员们拥有数亿美元的
dollars to invest and they're like
有美元可以投资，他们就像
basically the family office of
基本上是家族办公室
multi-billionaires and things he reached
亿万富翁和他所取得的成就
out on LinkedIn and he said I'm
他在领英上说我是
launching a WhatsApp group for people
为人们创建一个 WhatsApp 群组
who run a multif family office or a
经营多元家族办公室或
family office if you'd like to join uh
家族办公室，如果您想加入的话……
it's limited to 400 people if you'd like
人数限制为400人，如果您愿意的话。
to join fill in the application form to
如需加入，请填写申请表。
be part of our WhatsApp group for family
加入我们的家庭WhatsApp群组
office so he ended up with 400 people
所以他最终有了400名员工。
who have collectively over 10 billion to
他们总共拥有超过100亿
invest
投资
and he built himself a a group of people
他建立了自己的团队
who are some of the most successful
其中一些人是最成功的
investors in the world and some of the
世界各地的投资者以及一些
biggest checkbooks in the world um so it
世界上最大的支票簿，嗯，就是这样。
just started with a WhatsApp group so um
刚建了个WhatsApp群，所以……
a discussion group is just a super easy
讨论组非常简单
way to launch anything um and it costs
启动任何东西的方法，嗯，而且成本很高。
nothing to set up a discussion group on
没有什么可以建立讨论组的。
WhatsApp on Facebook on LinkedIn um so
WhatsApp、Facebook、LinkedIn 嗯，所以
those are some of the some of the best
这些都是一些最好的。
ways and the final one that I love is
方法，而我最喜欢的最后一个是……
called an assessment so a quiz or an
称为评估，所以可以是测验或考试。
assessment and this is basically where
评估，这基本上就是……
essentially you turn the customer needs
本质上，你要做的就是满足客户的需求。
analysis into an assessment and people
分析评估和人员
fill in questions to find out uh if they
填写问题以了解他们是否
would like the thing so for example I
例如，我想要这个东西。
noticed on one of your which one hu
注意到你其中一个 hu
sorry I noticed on hu that you have a
抱歉，我注意到你在hu上有一个
quiz um and the quiz is which hu is
测验是哪个 hu 是
right for you um and if you click that
正适合你，嗯，如果你点击那个
button you answer a series of questions
点击按钮，回答一系列问题
and it tells you which product would be
它会告诉你哪种产品是
the best product for you to uh for you
最适合你的产品
to take I noticed that whoop didn't have
我注意到 Whoop 没有
it right so I actually created one for
没错，所以我实际上创建了一个。
you anyway I'll give it to you later um
反正我待会儿会给你的，嗯。
but basically if you wanted to launch a
但基本上，如果你想启动一个
product like whoop you might do an
像 Whoop 这样的产品，你可能会做
assessment which is how well do you know
评估标准是：你对这方面了解多少？
your health and fitness you know um do
你的健康和体能，你知道的，嗯，做
you are you tracking your sleep are you
你在追踪你的睡眠情况吗？
doing this are you doing that so by
你这样做，你这样做，所以……
launching the assessment first while
首先启动评估
you've got the product in development
你们的产品正在开发中
you could get 10,000 people who filled
你可以找到 10,000 名填满表格的人。
in the assessment now if they've come up
在评估中，如果他们已经提出异议的话。
with a score that is like oh I only know
得分就像“哦，我只知道”一样
my health and fitness 22% I need to get
我的健康状况和体能状况需要改善22%。
that up to over 80% I need a product
超过 80% 的人需要产品
that helps me to do that so that
这有助于我做到这一点。
assessment is essentially diagnosing a
评估本质上是对某种疾病的诊断。
need you're helping the customer
你需要帮助客户
diagnose a need maybe they won't clear
诊断出需求，但他们可能不会清除。
on yeah so this is customer needs
是的，这是客户需求。
analysis smart businesses often sell the
分析能力强的企业通常会出售……
needs analysis before they sell the
在销售之前进行需求分析
product especially with anything that's
尤其是对于任何……产品
C uh especially anything that is complex
呃，尤其是任何复杂的东西。
but it goes beyond that because most
但这还远不止于此，因为大多数
customers now feel a sense of clutter in
顾客现在感觉店内杂乱无章。
their lives we've gone from feeling 100
他们的生活，我们已经从感觉100%变成了
years ago we felt that we had lots and
多年前，我们觉得我们拥有很多，
lots of things that we wanted or needed
我们想要或需要的很多东西
and we had unmet needs most people feel
我们有很多未被满足的需求，大多数人都有这种感觉。
the opposite today we feel that we have
今天我们却感觉恰恰相反，我们拥有
too many books and we haven't read them
书太多了，我们还没读过。
we have too much entertainment we
我们娱乐活动太多了
haven't watched it we have too many
还没看过，我们家太多了。
clothes and they're cluttering up our
衣服太多了，都堆满了我们的房间。
wardrobes our houses are full of stuff
我们家里的衣柜里堆满了东西。
so people feel such clutter that they
所以人们感到如此杂乱，以至于他们
only want things that are hyper
只想要超高速的东西
personalized to the thing they actually
根据他们实际的物品进行个性化定制
need um because otherwise they feel you
需要他们，否则他们会觉得你
know that it's going to be another thing
我知道这将是另一回事。
that they're not using so by selling a
他们并没有利用这一点，而是通过出售……
customer needs analysis when people see
当人们看到客户需求分析时
that it's a perfect fit then they want
如果这完全符合他们的要求，他们就想要
to buy in my last book The Diversy of 33
在我的上一本书《33个物种的多样性》中提到过。
laws I talk about um the idea that
我谈到的法律，嗯，这个想法是……
friction can create value and I give
摩擦可以创造价值，我同意
examples of where someone has added
例如，有人添加了
friction to the customer process and
客户流程中的摩擦和
it's resulted in more people buying and
这导致更多的人购买和
one of the studies I talk about is where
我谈到的研究之一是……
they took two groups of people they
他们带了两组人。
exposed one of them to a survey in order
为了进行调查，让其中一人参与调查。
to enter a discussion group MH right so
进入讨论组 MH 没错
they had to go through the survey
他们需要完成调查问卷。
process to get in and they let the
进入流程，他们允许
second group straight into the
第二组直接进入
discussion group Y and then they asked
Y 小组讨论，然后他们问
both groups to rate how valuable and
两组人员对价值和
enjoyable they found their Discussion
他们觉得讨论很有趣
Group to be now the group that had had
现在这个团体就是曾经拥有过这个团体的团体。
to go through a survey to get in yeah
需要填写调查问卷才能参加，是的。
reported that the discussion group was
报告称，讨论小组是
like really interesting etc etc and the
比如真的很有趣等等等等，还有
group that had been let straight in
直接进入的那群人
reported that it was boring and it was
据报道，它很无聊。
an intentionally boring group The so
一个故意无聊的团体
they made an intentionally boring group
他们故意组建了一个无聊的团队。
but just because you made someone go
但仅仅因为你让某人走了
through a process to get in people
通过一个过程来吸引人们
reported that it was more valuable than
据报道，它比
otherwise which says something about our
否则，这说明我们存在一些问题。
psychology well friction does create
心理学方面，摩擦确实会产生
value um demand and supply high tension
价值、需求和供给、高压
is the ultimate test of value um you
价值的最终考验，嗯，你
know it's horrible to say and I I hate
我知道这么说很糟糕，我讨厌这样。
this being true but there is no such
虽然这话属实，但实际上并不存在这样的事。
thing as objective value nothing is
事物作为客观价值，没有什么是
objectively valuable everything is
客观上有价值的一切都是
subjective why is a Bitcoin worth what a
主观上，比特币的价值究竟几何？
Bitcoin is because there's more buers
比特币之所以流行，是因为买家更多。
than sellers there's demand and Supply
比起卖家，需求和供给更多
tension why is water free because it's
张力，为什么水是免费的，因为它是
freely available there's no friction why
免费提供，没有任何阻碍，为什么？
do we never stop and think about how
我们难道从未停下来思考过这个问题吗？
incredible it is that we have Google
令人难以置信的是，我们竟然拥有谷歌
Maps and like we go like oh my goodness
地图，还有我们就像，哦我的天哪
someone's spent a billion dollar sending
有人花了十亿美元发送
satellites up so that I can have maps on
卫星升空，这样我就可以在地图上查看信息了。
my phone for free like no one's weeping
我的手机免费送我，好像没人会为此哭泣似的。
tears of joy for Google Maps and we
我们为谷歌地图喜极而泣。
should be because he you know someone
应该是因为他认识某人
spent a billion dollars on our behalf so
他们代表我们花费了十亿美元，所以
we've got free maps on our phone but
我们手机里有免费地图，但是
there's no friction around it now if
现在这方面没有任何摩擦。
they suddenly said we're taking it away
他们突然说我们要把它拿走。
we'd hit the roof yeah and if they said
我们会气疯的，如果他们说
it's 10 bucks a month we'd pay 10 bucks
每月10美元，我们愿意支付10美元。
a month MH um so friction creates value
一个月 MH 嗯，摩擦创造价值
um demand and Supply tension creates
供需紧张导致
value now the very difficult thing that
现在重视的是非常困难的事情
we have in the world right now is that
我们现在所处的这个世界是这样的：
in a digital environment there's no
在数字环境中，不存在
natural tension right so 100 million
自然张力，对吧，所以1亿
people can watch a video in a week and
人们一周可以看完一部视频，
you know it transcends time space wear
你知道它超越了时间和空间。
and tear there's no barriers there's
撕裂，没有障碍，只有
nothing that stops IT the money
没有什么能阻止IT行业的资金。
accumulates around those tension points
积聚在这些紧张点周围
so the successful businesses they know
所以他们知道，成功的企业都明白这一点。
how to use the digital environment to
如何利用数字环境
drive up demand and manufactured desire
刺激需求和制造欲望
and manufacture demand and then they
制造需求，然后他们
have choke points in their business or
他们的业务存在瓶颈或
tension points in their business where
他们业务中的紧张点
demand and Supply tension is rif and
供需紧张局势十分普遍。
those are the places where they monetize
这些就是他们盈利的地方。
mhm um something that's really
嗯，嗯，一些真正……
interesting about monetization that's
关于盈利模式，这很有意思。
happening at the moment is that all the
目前发生的事情是所有这些
money is moving up to the top 10% right
资金正在向最富有的10%人群流动。
so as as we go through this big
所以，当我们经历这个大过程时……
transition the affluence is all up in
过渡时期，富裕程度完全上升了
the top 10% so we did some research into
所以我们对前 10% 的人群进行了一些研究。
this the top 1% of people in your
这是你所在地区排名前 1% 的人群。
audience in everyone's audience whether
无论每个人的观众是谁
you're a you know LinkedIn account or
你是一个LinkedIn账号，或者
whether you've got millions of followers
无论你拥有数百万粉丝
top 1% have got a total of 15% of the
排名前 1% 的人总共获得了 15% 的份额
budget available to spend the next 9%
可用于支出接下来9%的预算
have got 45% of the budget available to
已有45%的预算可供使用
spend so in the top 10% there is 60% of
支出方面，前 10% 的人占 60%。
the available budget and then the bottom
可用预算，然后是底部
90% collectively have
90%的人合计拥有
40% so what happens is that the new
40%，所以接下来发生的事情是新的
business model that's emerging is that
正在兴起的商业模式是：
you give free value to the bottom 90%
你为底层90%的人提供了免费价值
and you don't ask anything in return but
而且你不要求任何回报，
you monetize the top 10% and you find
你把前 10% 的收益变现，然后你发现
things that are very special very rare
非常特别、非常罕见的事物
special experiences special products
特别体验 特别产品
limited editions um communities uh
限量版 嗯 社区 嗯
special access the top 10% have got all
特殊权限：前 10% 的人拥有所有
the money so you just give free value to
你用这笔钱提供免费价值。
90% of people and you only create
90%的人，而你只会创造
products and services for the top 10%
面向前 10% 人群的产品和服务
that's very much a new business model at
那是一种全新的商业模式。
the moment and the 90% are driving your
此刻和90%的人正在驱动着你
content your business your product to
内容涉及您的业务和产品
the top 10% through their engagement
通过参与度，排名前 10% 的人群脱颖而出
they're sharing Etc well it's a fractal
他们分享等等，嗯，这是一个分形
it doesn't matter what you do the top 1%
无论你做什么，前1%的人都无关紧要。
will even if even if you only did
即使你只做了
something for billionaires the top 1% of
专为亿万富翁和最富有的1%人群准备的东西
billionaires have got 15% of the total
亿万富翁们拥有总额的15%。
budget and the and the bottom 90% of
预算以及底层90%的人
billionaires have actually only got 40%
亿万富翁实际上只拥有40%的财富。
of the budget if you take the Forbes
如果你参考福布斯预算的话
list it's still those numbers still
列表仍然是那些数字
apply um the key is is that you well
应用的关键在于你……
actually what you want to do is the
实际上你想做的是
opposite you don't want to get dragged
相反，你不想被拖下水。
down into the 90% because the 90% are
下降到90%，因为90%
the noisiest they're the loudest so if
最吵闹的那些人声音最大，所以如果
you ask everyone how much should I
你问每个人我应该多少钱
charge the Aver Aver answer is going to
平均答案将要
be $500 but if you ask the top 1% how
可能是 500 美元，但如果你问顶尖 1% 的人，他们会怎么说？
much should I charge the average answer
我应该向平均答案收取多少费用
is going to be $5 to
将是 5 美元
$20,000 so you have to be very very
2万美元，所以你必须非常非常
careful not to create a product that
小心谨慎，不要创造出这样的产品
gets dragged down towards the 90%
被拖到90%左右
because the 90% don't have the budget to
因为90%的人没有足够的预算来
pay the top money you're far better off
付最高的价钱，你绝对会受益匪浅。
having a way of
有办法
um a way of segmenting that top 10% so
嗯，一种将前10%人群细分的方法。
that you can actually pick up the signal
你实际上可以接收到信号。
from them and not the noise from
来自他们的，而不是噪音
everybody else are there any other
还有其他人吗？
Frameworks that you would use in that
你会用到的框架
early stage where you're trying to
早期阶段，你正试图
figure out if your idea has traction or
弄清楚你的想法是否有可行性
even from a sort of motivation
甚至出于某种动机
psychology
心理学
perspective if it's worth pursuing this
从这个角度来看，是否值得继续下去
thing for the next 10 years of your life
未来十年你生活中最重要的事
because we talk a lot about a cave
因为我们经常谈论山洞
someone's clicked on it someone there's
有人点击了它，有人在那里
demand and interest but the Journey of
需求和兴趣，但旅程
an entrepreneur is an emotional one and
企业家都是感性的人，
as you often say there's you go through
正如你常说的，你会经历很多事情。
hell in high water ups and downs as an
地狱般的高水位，起起伏伏，就像……
entrepreneur so there's an element of
所以其中蕴含着企业家的元素。
this which is like you figuring out what
这就像你弄清楚什么
you want to commit your life to well we
你想把一生奉献给我们
call this the entrepreneur Sweet Spot
称之为创业者的甜蜜点
and The Entrepreneur sweet spot is a
而《创业者》的最佳切入点是……
vend diagram and you're trying to
销售图表，而你正在尝试
balance between your passion yeah the
在你的热情之间找到平衡
problem and the value of the problem
问题及其价值
that you solve and how much people are
你解决了这个问题，以及有多少人……
willing to pay for that so passion
愿意为此付费，所以充满热情。
problem payment uh so ultimately things
付款问题，呃，所以最终事情
that we're highly passionate about
我们对此充满热情
that's great but that only ticks one box
那很好，但这只满足了一个条件。
and if you're passionate about something
如果你对某件事充满热情的话。
but you're not solving a problem for
但你并没有解决问题。
others and they're not willing to pay
其他人则不愿意支付。
you for it you're going to feel very
为此你会感到非常荣幸。
unrewarded you're feel um disconnected
没有得到回报，你会感到与外界脱节。
maybe you feel even unethical uh about
或许你甚至觉得这样做有违道德。
that uh a lot of people in corporate
很多企业人士都这样认为。
jobs they solve a problem and they get
他们通过解决问题获得工作。
paid well but they're not passionate
薪水不错，但他们缺乏热情。
about it and what they tend to do is
关于这件事以及他们通常会怎么做：
throw the baby out with the bath water
把婴儿连同洗澡水一起扔掉
and they go and pursue being a yoga
然后他们去追求成为瑜伽士
instructor from being a corporate lawyer
作为一名公司律师的讲师
and then they wonder why they got no
然后他们就纳闷为什么自己什么都没得到
money because they just kind of threw
因为他们只是随便扔了点钱。
away the thing that they're very good at
把他们非常擅长的事情抛在脑后
and the thing that they get paid for and
以及他们获得报酬的事情
just exchange it so what we have to do
直接换一下就行了，所以我们该怎么做？
is actually try and capture all three by
实际上，我试图通过以下方式捕捉这三个人：
making some com risers and the
制作一些通信立管和
compromises are I'm not going to go to
妥协方案是我不会去的。
the thing that is the extreme of passion
激情的极致。
and I'm not going to go to the thing
我不会去参加那个活动。
that the extreme of financial rewards
极端的经济回报
not going to go to the extreme of my
我不会走极端。
intellectual property and my problem
知识产权和我的问题
solving abilities I'm going to find
我将要发现的解决问题的能力
something that is in the middle that
介于两者之间的某种东西
ticks all of those boxes so I'm getting
它完全符合所有这些条件，所以我决定购买。
a good blend while understanding that
既要理解这一点，又要保持良好的融合。
I'm there's going to be a trade-off
我认为这其中肯定存在权衡取舍。
there's going to be there's got to be
肯定会有，必须有
some trade-offs yeah you can't have you
有些权衡取舍，你不能拥有你
can't have it all at the extremes you
你不可能在两个极端都拥有你想要的一切。
can have it all but not uh all at the
可以拥有一切，但不可能一次性拥有所有。
extremes you you talked about some at
你谈到了一些极端情况
the start of this conversation you
这段对话的开始是你
mentioned the word
提到了这个词
geography um as we were talking about
地理，嗯，就像我们刚才谈到的那样
the macro factors that are at play in
影响宏观经济的因素
the transitions we've seen my question
我看到的转变，我的问题
to you is does geography matter for
对你来说，地理位置重要吗？
success as an entrepreneur so those kids
成为成功的企业家，所以那些孩子
in Cape Town do they need to be thinking
在开普敦，他们需要考虑什么？
listen we need to move to one of the
听着，我们需要搬到其中一个
major cities if we're going to have
如果我们要拥有主要城市，那就需要
stand a chance in most of these new
在这些新事物中，大多数都有机会
digital um opportunities it used to
它曾经拥有的数字化机遇
matter a lot when we used to think about
当我们过去思考这个问题时，它非常重要
entrepreneurs we thought about two men
我们想到的两位企业家是……
typically in their 20s
通常在20多岁
who came from a prestigious us
他们来自一所享有盛誉的美国学校。
University they got into a garage they
他们大学时进入了一个车库
you know they Dro they dropped out of
你知道他们退出了。
Harvard they dropped out of Stamford uh
哈佛大学，他们从斯坦福大学辍学了。
and then they started something that was
然后他们开始做一些事情，那就是
VC backed that was the old model of what
风投支持的是旧模式，即……
we think of as an entrepreneur and it
我们把创业者视为……
was very much dependent upon those
很大程度上取决于那些
parameters entrepreneurships transcended
创业精神超越了各种参数
that it's transcended geography gender
它超越了地理和性别的界限。
race um and and also the size and scale
种族，还有规模和比例
of what we consider to be successful so
我们认为的成功，所以
what we're now seeing is people all over
我们现在看到的是到处都是人
the world who are able to connect with
能够与世界连接的人
markets anywhere in the world launch a
世界各地的市场推出
product that can be sold anywhere in the
可以在任何地方销售的产品
world um we're seeing people who
世界，嗯，我们看到人们
bootstrap rather than get VC Capital uh
与其寻求风险投资，不如自筹资金。
we're seeing people who um rather than
我们看到的是一些人，嗯，而不是
trying to create something Mass Market
试图创造一些面向大众市场的产品
they create something niche market
他们创造了一些小众市场的东西
rather than trying to scale to be a
而不是试图扩大规模成为一个
unicorn they actually ask the question
独角兽，他们居然问了这个问题
at what size would I be fulfilled so
达到什么尺寸我才会感到满足？
there are plenty of people who you well
有很多像你这样的人
one of the most fulfilling businesses
最有成就感的行业之一
that you'll ever have has between 6 and
你将拥有的介于 6 和 之间
12 people and does 3 or 4 million of
12个人做了300万到400万件
Revenue and if you've got that probably
收入，如果你有那份收入的话，那可能
you're going to be the most fulfilled
你将会感到最满足
person in the world it's profitable yeah
世界上对任何人来说，这都是有利可图的，是的。
well because a lot of these businesses
因为很多这样的企业
have 60% margins if they're digital
如果是数字产品，利润率可达 60%。
businesses if they're intellectual
如果企业是知识型企业，那么它们就是知识型企业。
property um you know if they're running
房产，嗯，你知道，如果他们正在运行
on the new economy assets then they'll
那么，在新经济资产方面，他们将
be wildly profitable so you might have 6
利润非常丰厚，所以你可能会有 6 个
to 12 people do 2 or three million a
12个人就能做200万到300万。
year you might make a million of clear
一年之内你可能会赚到一百万。
profit um and then you're totally
盈利，然后你就完全
building business on fund freedom and
基于资金自由构建业务
fulfillment are you the next Google
你是否具备成为下一个谷歌的潜质？
absolutely not do you have VCS breathing
绝对不是，你有VCS呼吸吗？
down your neck no um are you able to
脖子下面，嗯，你能……
pick and choose the types of people and
挑选合适的人选和
opportunities you want to work with yes
你想参与的工作机会是的
so incredibly fulfilling so that's a new
如此令人满足，这真是一个新的体验。
type of business I would call that a
我称之为“一种类型的企业”
lifestyle Boutique um there's another
生活方式精品店，嗯，还有另一家。
type of business called a performance
这种类型的业务被称为表演
business um and this is a business that
嗯，这是一项业务，这项业务是
typically has 30 people normally working
通常有30名员工在岗
with some sort of technology and they
他们运用某种技术
build a business that they build a
建立他们所建立的企业
business that can be solded for between
可以以介于
10 and 100 million and that's my that's
1000万和1亿，那就是我的……
my game I like businesses that achieve
我喜欢那些取得成功的企业。
10 to 100 million of valuation with
估值在1000万至1亿美元之间
about 30 people on a team and we can
团队大约有30人，我们可以
sell to either a public listed company a
出售给上市公司
private Equity backed company um we can
私募股权支持的公司，嗯，我们可以
exit to any of those kind of companies
退出到任何这类公司
but you know we don't have to be the
但你知道我们不必成为……
next Google and we also don't have to
接下来是谷歌，我们也不必如此。
split the exit with a VC why do you say
你为什么说要和风险投资公司平分退出份额？
that when you also just said that the
你刚才也说过，
most fun and fulfilling businesses are
最有趣、最有成就感的生意是
actually those small ones with a small
实际上，那些小的，小的
group of people in order to go to that
一群人为了去那里
next level you have to be a business
下一个阶段，你必须成为一家企业。
geek so anyone can build a to 12 person
极客们，所以任何人都可以建造一个最多可容纳 12 人的
business and at that point all you have
商业，到那时你所拥有的就只有
to geek out on is the topic of interest
让我着迷的话题是感兴趣的话题。
to the customer so if your customer
对客户而言，如果你的客户
loves yoga you're just talking about
你喜欢瑜伽，你刚才说的就是这个。
yoga all the time or if your customer
一直练瑜伽，或者如果你的客户
loves photography you're talking about
你说的就是喜欢摄影的人。
photography and you don't have to be a
摄影，你不必是……
business geek at that point when you've
当你成为商业极客的时候
got a team of about 30 to 100 uh you
团队大约有30到100人，呃，你
have to be a you have to be totally into
你必须完全投入。
the product the intellectual property of
该产品的知识产权
what you do but you also have to geek
你做的事情，你也得有点极客精神。
out on technology and you also have to
你对科技不感兴趣，而且你还得……
geek out on business so not everyone is
有些人对商业过于痴迷，所以并非每个人都如此。
built for that you have to really love
专为热爱而打造
your acronyms you need to like oh go to
你需要知道的缩写词，比如哦，去
market strategy or you know lifetime
市场策略，或者你知道的，终身
value of a client okay what's the LTV
客户价值，也就是客户终身价值（LTV）。
what's the GT you know GTM so you kind
GT是什么？你知道GTM是什么？所以你懂的。
of got to be into all of those things uh
我必须对所有这些都感兴趣。
quite naturally you naturally want to
你自然而然地想要
read business books um so you're not
读商业书籍，嗯，所以你不是
going to enjoy that if you hate business
如果你讨厌商业，那你一定会喜欢这个。
or if you hate technology because those
或者如果你讨厌科技，因为那些
businesses tend to be about um business
企业往往与商业有关。
strategy and Tech these ones are about
战略与科技，这些就是关于
intellectual property media and data got
知识产权媒体和数据
you
你
do you think you would be happier if you
你觉得如果你……你会更快乐吗？
were less ambitious um I my happiness
没那么雄心勃勃，嗯，我的幸福
levels are really high um I walk around
浓度真的很高，嗯，我四处走走
feeling like I'm super lucky to do what
感觉自己非常幸运能做这件事
I do and it's total privilege and I love
是的，这完全是我的荣幸，我非常喜欢。
living in these times I can't believe
生活在这样的时代，我简直难以置信
I'm lucky enough to be born at the
我很幸运出生在……
perfect time to see this change and and
现在是见证这一变化的绝佳时机。
to have access to all these resources
能够获取所有这些资源
and what how do you think about work
你对工作有什么看法？
life balance these days and how should
如今如何平衡生活和工作？
especially sort of young Founders when I
尤其是一些年轻的创始人，当我
say young Founders I don't mean age I
我说的是年轻的创始人，我指的不是年龄。
mean stage um should be thinking about
平均阶段嗯，应该考虑
work life balance in your view so I had
你认为工作与生活平衡很重要，所以我……
no balance for many years probably a
多年来可能一直没有余额
decade or more um all I did was uh
十多年里，我所做的只是……
essentially just get out of bed work uh
基本上就是起床工作。
everything related to work and the
所有与工作相关的事项
reason I did that is that it ticked all
我这么做的原因是它满足了所有条件。
of my human needs right I was getting
我的人性需求得到了满足，我正在获得
significance and variety um and I was um
意义和多样性，嗯，我当时是……
you know getting uh certainty and I was
你知道，获得确定性，而我当时
getting all of those things that we want
得到我们想要的一切
from life and I was feeling a sense of
来自生活，我感到一种……
growth and development and learning so
成长、发展和学习
everything plugged into those human
所有东西都连接到那些人类身上
needs and my business was giving me all
我的事业满足了我的所有需求。
of that when I had uh kids and I got
后来我有了孩子，就……
married there was this whole other side
结婚后，还有完全不同的另一面。
to me that needed to be balanced and I
对我来说，这需要保持平衡，而且
think that there's more to do with there
我觉得还有更多的事情要做。
some Seasons like that we go through
我们会经历一些这样的季节。
Sprints and I tell friends family uh Hey
Sprints 和我告诉朋友家人呃嘿
I'm going through a bit of a Sprint
我最近有点儿忙不过来。
right now we're launching something new
我们现在正在推出一些新产品。
um and then there are times where I
嗯，还有一些时候，我
switch off a lot do do you goal set at
关闭很多东西，去做你设定的目标。
all do you set goals and if you know I
你们都设定目标吗？如果你知道我
used to I used to set goals and I used
我过去常常设定目标，而且我过去常常这样做。
to love setting goals I don't anymore
我不再喜欢设定目标了。
because my key person of influence brand
因为我的关键影响人品牌
brings in opportunities that I can't
带来了我无法获得的机会
predict so this di of a CEO thing was an
所以，预测这位CEO的这种做法是……
example of that I had all these goals
例如，我当时有所有这些目标。
for 2024 and then you message me while
2024年，然后你给我发消息
I'm skiing and say would you like to
我在滑雪，然后问你想不想……
come on the show and I go of course that
来参加节目吧，我当然会去。
would be amazing so I come on the show
那太棒了，所以我来参加节目。
and then that totally transformed my
然后，那彻底改变了我
year so as you build a brand it's harder
随着品牌建设的深入，难度也会增加。
to goal set because you've got too many
设定目标，因为你有太多目标了。
things so goal setting is about direct
所以目标设定是关于直接的。
power direct influence and um having a
权力、直接影响以及拥有……
brand is about indirect power or
品牌关乎间接的力量或
indirect influence it's what you attract
间接影响，就是你吸引的东西。
so uh ultimately at the early stages
所以，嗯，最终在早期阶段
goal setting is really important because
设定目标非常重要，因为
it's how do I direct my energy once you
问题在于，一旦你……之后，我该如何分配我的精力。
get a little bit bigger you have to slow
再大一点，你就得慢下来。
down to speed up you have to create
为了加快速度，你必须创建
space to see what's happening around you
有足够的空间观察周围发生的事情
one of the biggest mistakes I've ever
我犯过的最大错误之一
made was filling my diary so full that I
做这件事让我把日记填得满满当当，以至于我
didn't see some of the biggest
没能看到一些最大的
opportunities that were going on around
当时出现的各种机会
me and I think this has cost me tens of
我觉得这让我损失了数十万美元。
millions and I really think at a certain
数百万，而且我真的认为在某种程度上
level strategically you have to slow
从战略角度来看，你必须放慢速度。
down to speed up you have to create gaps
减速需要制造间隙。
where things can hit you things can get
哪里有事会发生，哪里就可能发生
onto your radar um or else you miss all
务必关注，否则你会错过一切。
the benefits of having a great brand so
拥有一个优秀品牌的好处
I had a few questions here one of them
我这里有几个问题，其中一个
is about how
是关于如何
you measure or quantify the value of an
你衡量或量化一个的价值
opportunity looking forward when you
期待机会，当你
have very little information about the
关于这方面的信息非常少。
opportunities so so what we what we're
机会，所以我们是什么？
trying to move towards is leverage so
试图利用杠杆作用来取得进展
that we live in a world of leverage and
我们生活在一个充满杠杆的世界里，
there are types so it's important to
有很多类型，所以了解它们很重要
understand there are type two types of
了解有两种类型的
opportunities there's bell curve
机会呈钟形曲线分布
opportunities and power L opportunities
机会和权力 L 机会
so bell curve opportunities means that
所以，正态分布的机会意味着
everything fits within a bell curve and
一切都符合正态分布曲线，而且
it's very unlikely that anything will be
发生任何事情的可能性都非常小。
outside of that bell curve power LW
超出该正态分布曲线功率 LW
opportunities means that because of
机会意味着因为
Leverage the sky the limit um what we
利用天空的限制，嗯，我们
have to do is have the courage to move
你只需要有勇气行动起来。
out of bell curves and into Power laws
从钟形曲线过渡到幂律
so for example a doctor in the NHS who I
例如，一位在英国国家医疗服务体系（NHS）工作的医生，
know um recognized that all doctors earn
我知道，所有医生都认识到这一点。
roughly the same amount of money there's
金额大致相同
no outliers everyone who works in the
没有例外，所有在职人员都是如此。
NHS if you're a new doctor you earn
如果你是NHS（英国国家医疗服务体系）的新医生，你将获得
about this if you have been around for
如果你一直关注此事，应该对此有所了解。
20 years you ownn about this um and most
20年来你一直拥有这方面的知识，嗯，而且大多数
people fit within that bell curve
人们符合这个正态分布曲线。
there's no doctors who are making a
没有医生在做
million a month um type thing then
月入百万之类的，嗯……
there's the power law law this
这里涉及到幂律定律。
particular guy dropped out of being an
某个人退出了……
NHS doctor to become a YouTuber and
英国国家医疗服务体系（NHS）医生转型成为YouTube博主
recognized that there are some YouTubers
意识到有一些 YouTuber
who are actually earning a million a
实际上，有些人年收入达到了一百万美元。
month and boom there is this power law
一个月后，突然就出现了这种幂律
that goes up so what we're trying to
它会上升，所以我们正在努力
find out Ali AB
找出阿里·AB
yes of course Ali abdal so what we're
当然，阿里·阿卜杜勒，所以我们……
trying to figure out is we're trying to
我们正在努力弄清楚的是……
figure out um is this a b curve or a
弄清楚这是B曲线还是A曲线
power curve power law so being a speaker
功率曲线 功率定律 所以作为一名演讲者
on a stage absolutely a power law uh
在舞台上，绝对遵循幂律。
move being friends with a billionaire in
与亿万富翁交朋友
Italy and having access to that Capital
意大利以及获得该资本的机会
Access to how whatever networks they've
了解他们拥有的任何网络
got all of that sort of stuff if they're
如果他们有这些东西的话
the right sort of person there's
那里有合适的人选。
definitely two types of billionaires but
亿万富翁绝对分为两种类型，但是
um but uh that's probably an exponential
嗯，但是，呃，那可能是一个指数级增长
opportunity right it it puts you further
机会就在眼前，它能让你走得更远。
up the power power law um it's not a
提高功率幂律嗯，这不是一个
bell curve opportunity um however if
钟形曲线机会，嗯，然而如果
someone says you know can we meet to
有人说，你知道吗，我们可以见面吗？
talk about some incremental thing no
谈谈一些渐进式的事情吧，不。
that's that's a bell curve right that's
这就是正态分布曲线，对吧？
not going to that's not going to break
不会的，那不会打破
me out of what I'm doing so for most
让我从我正在做的事情中抽离出来，所以大多数情况下
people listening to this most people are
听这段话的人中，大多数人都是
trapped inside a bell curve you're never
被困在正态分布曲线中，你永远不会
going to get out of that bell curve
摆脱那种正态分布曲线
every opportunity fits within that bell
每一个机会都契合在那口钟的范围内。
curve you're only going to incrementally
你只会逐步地改变曲线
move to one from one side of the bell
从铃铛的一侧移动到另一侧。
curve to the other side side of the bell
弯曲到钟体的另一侧
curve and that's about it there is no
曲线，仅此而已，没有其他内容。
massive
大量的
upside if that's you what you need to be
如果你需要成为那样的人，那这就是好处。
doing is spending a little bit of time
做这件事就是花一点时间
talking to people about exponential
与人谈论指数增长
opportunities right and exponential
机会正当时且呈指数级增长
opportunities always involve leverage
机会总是与杠杆作用有关。
that's what creates the exponential
这就是指数增长的成因。
shift leverage could be Fame leverage
转变杠杆作用可能是名望杠杆作用
could be Capital leverage could be large
资本杠杆可能很高。
databases uh leverage could be huge
数据库的杠杆作用可能非常巨大。
distribution networks that already exist
现有的配电网络
leverage could be a partnership with
利用杠杆作用可能是一种合作关系
someone who's way further along than you
比你走得远得多的人
are uh leverage could be being in
杠杆作用可能在于……
business versus being in a job so all of
创业与工作的区别，以及所有这些
those things are things that move you
那些事情会让你感动。
onto the power law and there's it's
回到幂律，那就是……
almost the Skies of the limit at the
几乎是无限的天空
moment because in
此刻，因为在
2010 28% of the world had fast internet
2010年，全球28%的人口拥有高速互联网。
and in 2025 70% of the world has fast
到2025年，全球70%的人口将拥有快速……
internet so 70% of 8 billion people have
互联网让80亿人口中的70%拥有了互联网。
got fast internet so the world the
有了快速的网络，所以全世界
actual the number of people available to
实际可用的人数
talk to has gone into the billions and
谈话内容已涉及数十亿美元，
billions and billions the amount of
数十亿，数额巨大
capital is flooding into the internet um
大量资金正涌入互联网。
everything is in that space and
一切都在那个空间里，
ultimately unfortunately one of the
最终不幸的是，其中之一
things that's happening at the moment is
目前发生的事情是
that you're either in competition with
你要么与……竞争
everyone in the world or everyone in the
全世界所有人或所有人
world is a is a potential customer and
世界是一个潜在客户，
um if you feel that you're in
嗯，如果你觉得你处于……
competition with everyone in the world
与全世界所有人竞争
which a lot of people do it's terrifying
很多人都这么做，这太可怕了。
it feels horrible it's it's absolutely
感觉糟透了，真是太糟糕了。
uh scary to think that you know for a
呃，想到你知道这一点就觉得可怕。
lot of businesses and a lot of
很多企业和很多
individuals with a career it's it's like
对于那些有事业的人来说，这就像是……
wow I'm in competition with AI I'm in
哇，我居然在和人工智能竞争！
competition with an agent uh an agency
与经纪人或代理机构的竞争
in India or or a a remote worker in the
在印度，或者是一名远程工作者
Philippines who's happy for $5 an hour
菲律宾人每小时 5 美元就很开心
um I'm in competition with someone who's
嗯，我正在和某人竞争，他/她……
phenomenally well funded in La uh I'm in
在洛杉矶资金非常充足，呃，我参与其中
competition with this incredible Tech
与这项令人难以置信的技术展开竞争
Team in Silicon Valley uh YouTubers
硅谷团队，呃，YouTube 用户
YouTubers I'm competing on the
我在 YouTube 上与一些 YouTuber 竞争
opportunity I'm competing for attention
我正在努力争取关注的机会
like how am I going to survive and then
我该如何活下去？
the flip side of that is that once you
另一方面，一旦你
make this transition to this new rules
完成向这些新规则的过渡
new way of doing things then it flips
先是采用新的做事方式，然后它就翻转了。
it's like oh everyone's a potential
感觉就像每个人都有潜力一样。
customer so how do you think about
那么，客户，您是如何看待这个问题的？
defense you know you in many of your
你知道，在很多情况下，你的防御都很重要
businesses that you run you're in
你经营的企业，你身处其中
competition with lots of people where do
和很多人竞争，在哪里？
you find areas to defend against that
你需要找到防御的领域来应对这种情况。
competition the sort of proverbial blue
竞争就像一句谚语所说的蓝色
oceans so what I'm looking for when when
海洋，所以我在寻找什么？
I set up my businesses to scale is we
我建立这家公司是为了实现规模化发展，我们
asked the question how many people this
问有多少人
year could we either
一年后我们是否可以
uh take on and leave them feeling
呃，接受并让他们感觉
completely
完全地
delighted uh how many people this year
很高兴，呃，今年有多少人？
would represent a phenomenally good year
这将代表着一个极其美好的年份。
right so in one of the businesses the
对，所以在其中一家企业里
number is 600 we say Okay 600 people if
如果人数是600，我们就说好的，600人。
we have 600 people 600 clients in this
我们有600人，600个客户。
particular business for this year that's
今年的这项特殊业务是……
a really good year we're happy with that
今年真是个好年头，我们对此很满意。
year so we call that the official
所以我们称之为官方年份
capacity of the business we give it a
我们赋予企业的能力
name official capacity is 600 then we
官方容量为600人，那么我们
ask the question what percentage of our
问问我们有多少百分比
leads buy that product and and in that
潜在客户会购买该产品，并且……
business it's one in 66 so for every 66
企业倒闭的概率是六十六分之一，也就是说，每66家企业中就有一家倒闭。
leads we generate we get one client
我们产生的潜在客户最终会获得一个客户
who's who's the perfect client so it's a
谁是理想客户，所以这是一个
very particular focused business so then
非常注重特定领域的业务，所以
we know that we need to engage 49,000
我们知道我们需要吸引 49,000 人参与
people and if those 49,000 people engage
人们，以及如果这 49,000 人参与其中。
with this then we will be able to select
这样我们就可以进行选择了
the 600 clients we work with and that we
我们与600位客户合作，而且我们
will absolutely do everything we can to
我们一定会尽一切努力
leave those 600 people feeling delighted
让那600人感到高兴
that they want to recommend it and refer
他们想推荐并提及它。
it and they love it and for us just
他们很喜欢，对我们来说也一样
simply knowing those numbers that allows
仅仅知道这些数字就能做到这一点
us to say ah okay we engage 49,000
我们说啊，好的，我们参与了49,000次活动。
people we make our 600 sales it's a
我们实现了600笔销售，这是一个
super successful year we can celebrate
超级成功的一年，值得庆祝
that so by setting the rules to our game
这样，我们就可以通过设定游戏规则来做到这一点。
we're not dragged into anybody else's
我们不会被卷入任何其他人的纷争之中。
rules and that means that we're playing
规则就是游戏规则，这意味着我们要玩游戏。
uh a really defensive game we're
呃，我们打了一场非常注重防守的比赛。
defending against all the things that we
抵御我们所经历的一切
could focus on by being really specific
可以通过非常具体的方式来集中精力。
about what we want to focus on and is if
关于我们想要关注的重点以及是否
you know for those kids on the prominade
你知道，那些在海滨大道上的孩子们
in Cape Town that I keep referring back
在开普敦，我一直都在谈论它。
to if they had asked you if they said uh
如果他们问你，他们会说“呃”吗？
Daniel what industry
丹尼尔是什么行业
would you start a business in today if
如果今天发生什么，你会创业吗？
you were us and you had limited funds
你们就是我们，你们的资金有限。
well let let's do some big trends the
好，我们来看看一些大趋势。
the biggest so biggest opportunity at
最大的机遇
the moment is 50% of the economy is
目前，经济的50%是
owned by Baby Boomers people aged 61 to
由61岁至61岁的婴儿潮一代拥有
79 so that's 50% of the US economy 50%
79，占美国经济的50%。
of the Australian the New Zealand the
澳大利亚的新西兰的
Canadian the UK right so all the sort of
加拿大、英国，对，等等等等
major Western economies that had a baby
生了孩子的西方主要经济体
boom 50% of the economy is owned by
繁荣时期，50%的经济由……所有
people aged 61 to 79 um so those people
61岁到79岁的人，嗯，就是那些人
are going through a big life change
正在经历重大的人生变故
they're transforming the way they live
他们正在改变自己的生活方式
and work they want to get rid of their
他们想摆脱他们的工作
businesses they want to move into
他们想要进入的行业
advisory roles they want to travel they
他们想担任顾问角色，并希望出差。
want to have uh different relationships
想要拥有不同的关系
they want to have different priorities
他们希望拥有不同的优先事项。
um so I would definitely be thinking
嗯，所以我肯定会这么想。
about how do I work with that group of
关于我如何与那群人合作
people I'm either going to buy their
我打算买下这些人
business and take it over um which would
收购这家公司，然后接管它，嗯，这会
be an opportunity I'm going to build a
这将是我构建一个机会
business that disrupts the current way
颠覆现有模式的商业模式
that they're doing business um or I'm
他们正在做生意，嗯，或者我是。
going to sell to that market cuz they're
打算卖给那个市场，因为他们
cashed up they got loads of time loads
他们手头宽裕，时间充裕。
of money um and every business could
资金，嗯，每个企业都可以
think about how it's going to sell to a
想想它要如何才能卖出去。
baby boomer Market because that's
因为那是婴儿潮一代的市场。
50% um so a good example might be of a
50% 嗯，一个很好的例子可能是……
baby baby boomer business what's a good
婴儿潮一代的商业模式，什么才是好的？
baby boomer business everything the
婴儿潮一代的商业一切
whole econom is made up of B like if we
整个经济都是由B构成的，就像如果我们
went out on the street here yeah um the
走到街上了，嗯……
person down the road who's fixing who's
路尽头那个正在修理东西的人
doing theot on the cars is a baby Bo
在车上做theot就像个小婴儿Bo
business the guy who Services the
这位服务于商业的家伙
elevators that come up and down here
这里有上下行的电梯。
that's Baby Boom the air conditioning
那是婴儿潮时期的空调
unit business is baby boomer business um
单位业务是婴儿潮一代的业务
you know the Kier company that kind of
你知道Kier公司那种类型的
dropped everything off as a baby boomer
婴儿潮时期，我放弃了一切。
business um you know the whole damn
商业，你知道，所有的一切
shooting match is like mostly like 50
射击比赛大概有50场左右
like half the businesses and especially
像一半的企业，尤其是
by revenue and valuation it's all baby
按营收和估值来看，一切都还很年轻。
boomers or half Baby Boomers at least
婴儿潮一代，或者至少一半的婴儿潮一代
and there may be a sort of a digital
而且可能存在某种数字化
Arbitrage opportunity that there's been
存在套利机会
created with the Trans transfer of um um
用Trans转移um um创建
with the rise of digital that they might
随着数字化的兴起，他们可能会
have missed that you could seize upon it
错过了抓住这个机会的机会
massively well one of the things is that
非常好的一点是，其中一点是……
every single business in the world is
世界上每一家企业都是
going to be disrupted by AI um and
将会受到人工智能的颠覆，嗯，
you've got to be the company that um
你必须成为那样一家公司……
uses AI when they're not uh and and
当他们不……的时候，会使用人工智能。
using AI like being disrupted by AI just
使用人工智能就像被人工智能颠覆一样
means that every employee is way more
这意味着每个员工都更加……
effective because they're using AI so
之所以有效，是因为他们使用了人工智能。
one of the simple things to disrupt a
扰乱秩序的简单方法之一
business with AI is to run a training
利用人工智能开展业务是为了进行训练
workshop with all the people in the
与所有参与者一起参加研讨会
company about how they could use AI in
公司讨论他们将如何使用人工智能
their role um and you could watch some
他们的角色，嗯，你可以看看一些。
videos online and you could uh play with
在线视频，你可以玩……
chat gbt uh recently we uh introduced an
聊天 gbt 嗯，最近我们嗯，引入了一个
AI system to one of uh our businesses we
人工智能系统应用于我们的一项业务
have 250 video case studies of clients
拥有 250 个客户视频案例研究
who are happy customers and they've
他们都是满意的客户，而且他们已经
recorded a video for us and they're
他们为我们录制了一段视频，他们是
amazing video case studies but there's
精彩的视频案例研究，但也有不足之处。
too many of them there's so many video
视频太多了。
case studies so we created an AI bot
案例研究，所以我们创建了一个人工智能机器人
that reads and understands all of those
能够阅读并理解所有这些内容
video case studies and then for my sales
视频案例研究，然后用于我的销售
team when they''re talking to a customer
团队在与客户交谈时
they're just typing uh of they're typing
他们正在打字，呃，或者他们正在打字
in the type of scenario that that
在那种情况下
person's going through and the bot is
有人正在操作，而机器人是
then suggesting oh this is the video
然后暗示说，哦，这就是视频
case study this is the customer this is
案例研究 这是客户 这是
what they said same industry as you same
他们说他们和你一样，都是同一行业的。
problem same Challenge and then they
问题依旧存在，挑战也随之而来。
here's the link to the video case study
这是视频案例研究的链接
M so our sales team can be super
所以我们的销售团队可以非常出色
effective at sending you through the
能有效地引导你完成
exact video case study that's relevant
相关的具体视频案例研究
to you MH because the AI bot has read
给你 MH，因为人工智能机器人已经读过了
and understood every single one of our
并且理解了我们每一个人。
video case studies studies uh so that's
视频案例研究，嗯，就是这样。
an example you know there's been so many
举个例子，你知道，这样的例子有很多。
of these technological revolutions over
这些技术革命的
the last 50 odd years that I looked back
回顾过去五十余年
on and thought oh gosh I wish I was
继续想，哦，天哪，我真希望我是
there at the.com boom I would have
在.com网站的繁荣时期，我本可以……
become a billionaire I would have had
如果我成为亿万富翁，我本可以拥有
all you know a variety of different
你所知道的各种不同
ideas do you think AI is that now do you
你认为人工智能现在就是这样吗？
think we're living through we're early
我觉得我们正在经历的，我们还是早期阶段。
it's so early right it's it's the moment
现在还早，对吧？就是现在！
I I remember when Steve Jobs launched
我记得史蒂夫·乔布斯发布会的时候
the App Store and that was 2007 20072
App Store，那是2007年。
it was 2 years later that Instagram was
两年后，Instagram 才正式成立。
launched it was 2 years later that Uber
两年后，优步推出了
was launched and then there was a March
启动之后，就发生了三月事件。
of hundreds of different businesses and
数百家不同的企业和
now applications are you know everywhere
现在应用程序无处不在。
the the bigger example would be
更具体的例子是
electricity so it was the 1830s where we
电力普及是在19世纪30年代。
generated electricity but it wasn't
发电了，但它并没有发电。
until the 1930s that we filled our
直到 20 世纪 30 年代，我们才填满了我们的
houses full of things that ran on
房子里堆满了运行着的东西
electricity so it was a 100-year
电力，所以这是100年的
transition um now with AI where at the
现在人工智能正在发挥作用，过渡到……
early stage of generating AI but we're
虽然目前还处于人工智能开发的早期阶段，但我们正在
not yet into the stage of creating
尚未进入创建阶段
everything that runs on AI so think
所有基于人工智能运行的东西，所以想想
about uh a power station versus a
关于一个发电站与一个
toaster so the power station's been
烤面包机，所以发电站已经……
invented but there's thousands and
发明了，但还有成千上万个
thousands and thousands of toasters that
成千上万台烤面包机
can be invented toasters kettles vacuum
可以发明烤面包机、电水壶和真空吸尘器
cleaners things that run on electricity
清洁器，以及用电运行的物品
so AI like electricity but we haven't
人工智能就像电力一样，但我们还没有。
built all the businesses that are going
建立了所有正在发展的业务
to plug in and are going to be great
插上电源就能用，而且效果很棒。
opportunities and that's going to be
机会，而且这将是
over the next 10 15 years every single
在接下来的10到15年里，每一天
industry you can't name an industry
你无法说出一个行业的名称
that's not going to be impacted by this
这不会受到影响。
every industry is going to have
每个行业都会有
applications that run on AI there's
基于人工智能运行的应用程序有很多。
going to be new teams do you know what
会有新队伍，你知道吗？
happened just a couple of weeks ago uh
就发生在几周前。
Nvidia launched a supercomputer for
英伟达推出了一款超级计算机
$3,000 now this is going to be the
现在这笔钱是3000美元。
fundamental
基本的
basis for 10 people companies that do a
10人公司的基础
billion of Revenue this is going to be
这将带来数十亿美元的收入。
entrepreneurs who who like crunch some
喜欢挑战的创业者
data figure out a little application
数据弄清楚一个小应用程序
because of that kind of compute power
正是因为这种计算能力
they're going to come up with something
他们会想出办法的。
and it's going to be a billion dollar
这将是一笔十亿美元的投资。
business with 10 people working on the
一家拥有10名员工的企业
team there's going to be a little
团队里会有一些
healthc care unit that figures out how
负责研究如何运作的医疗保健部门
to Crunch data and solve a like a really
像真正的数据处理和问题解决一样处理数据并解决问题
complex health problem and they'll
复杂的健康问题，他们会
figure out how to do it that
想办法做到这一点
supercomputer for three grand supersedes
超级计算机取代了三个大型
what people used to be spending 3 to 6
人们过去常常花费 3 到 6 美元
to n Grand a month on um so previously
一个月前，我花了 n Grand 的钱。
you would have had to subscribe to that
你必须订阅那个服务。
level of compute and you would have been
计算水平，你就会……
spending you know $50,000 a year just
一年花5万美元，你知道的
for the cloud subscription to that sort
针对这类云订阅
of thing now one payment of $3,000 you
现在这件事，你一次性支付3000美元。
can be anywhere in the world crunching
可能在世界任何地方进行数据处理
any amounts of phenomenal data so just
任何数量的惊人数据，所以只是
that one thing that one Innovation is
创新的一点是
going to totally transform
将会彻底改变
Industries I would imagine that I'm
我设想的行业
going to guess
我猜
90 95% of people that are listening
90%到95%的听众
right now don't know a lot about AI they
他们现在对人工智能了解不多。
also don't really know a lot about
我对这方面也了解不多。
technology to the extent that many other
技术发展到其他许多领域都无法比拟的地步
people do the 5% do for those people who
人们为那些占人口5%的人做着同样的事情
are you know it could be the taxi driver
你知道吗，那人可能是出租车司机
it could be the the janitor it could be
可能是清洁工，也可能是……
a student in University studying
一名在大学学习的学生
philosophy or something what advice
哲学或其他什么建议
would you give them if you were the
如果你是他们，你会给他们吗？
puppet master of their life now and you
现在，你成了他们生活的幕后操纵者。
had to get them close to this
必须让他们接近这个
opportunity what are this the sort of
这是什么样的机会？
steps you take towards being able to
你为实现以下目标而采取的步骤
capitalize on something like nvidia's
利用类似英伟达的那些技术
supercomputer yes so of course it's a
超级计算机，没错，它当然是……
pyramid so the schooling system taught
金字塔，所以学校教育体系是这样教的
you that you the way to be successful
你找到了通往成功的道路
was to turn labor into skilled labor so
目的是将劳动力转化为熟练劳动力。
become skilled labor your time and your
成为熟练工人，利用你的时间和精力
skills are what's valuable and that was
技能才是最有价值的，仅此而已。
the Industrial Revolution model for
工业革命模式
everybody we all went through that
我们都经历过那段时期。
system and we said that's where the
系统，我们说那就是问题所在
journey ends in fact if you want you can
事实上，如果你愿意，旅程可以就此结束。
go to university become really skilled
上大学，成为一名真正的高技能人才
labor you can get a masters and become
你可以通过劳动获得硕士学位并成为……
really skilled labor PhD become super
真正熟练的劳动者，博士，成为超级
skilled labor and the whole goal is sell
熟练劳动力，最终目标是销售
your time for more money and then
你花费时间换取更多金钱
sitting on top of that is this new
位于其上的是这个新的
universe and the new universe is this
宇宙，而新的宇宙就是这个。
digital economy and the first step above
数字经济及以上第一步
it is called intellectual property
它被称为知识产权
intellectual property is where rather
知识产权正是如此。
than learning more stuff you reflect and
与其学习更多东西，不如反思一下。
create some stuff so you say oh over the
创作一些东西，这样你就可以说“哦，超过”
last 5 years I did something special
过去五年我做了一些特别的事。
with that client um and we got a great
与那位客户合作，我们取得了不错的成果。
result and I can explain it step by step
结果，我可以一步一步地解释。
I'm going to document that I'm going to
我将记录下我将要做的事情
turn that into a story and I'm going to
把它写成一个故事，我打算……
record a video about it and I'm going to
我会录制一段关于此事的视频。
have a little poster with a wheel that
有一张小海报，上面画着一个轮子，
explains how we did that and then I'm
解释了我们是如何做到的，然后我就……
just going to let people know about that
我只是想让大家知道这件事。
so now we're in the business of
所以现在我们从事的是……业务
intellectual property intellectual
知识产权
property is anything written anything on
财产是指任何写在纸上的东西。
video Anything Audio right so
视频、音频等等，对吧？
intellectual property couples up with
知识产权与
media so IP and media are the next level
媒体，所以IP和媒体是下一个层次
above skilled labor so the first step
高于熟练劳动力水平，因此第一步
get out of skilled labor model and get
摆脱技术工人模式并获得
into intellectual property in media and
进入媒体知识产权领域
just making that step opens you up to
仅仅迈出这一步，就为你打开了通往……的大门。
this whole other world of opportunities
这是一个充满机遇的全新世界。
uh if you you you must know the book
呃，如果你……你必须知道这本书
Seven Habits of Highly Effective People
高效能人士的七个习惯
Steven kovi he passed away 10 years
史蒂文·科维去世10年了
ago he was not some special guy he was a
以前他并不是什么特别的人，他只是一个
church leader in Utah he did some
犹他州的一位教会领袖做了一些
Consulting with small businesses and he
为小型企业提供咨询服务，他
did some Consulting with church
为教会做了一些咨询工作
but he just reflected on what he' seen
但他只是反思了他所看到的一切。
and he reflected on a few studies that
他回顾了几项研究，这些研究……
he' come across and he wrote this book
他偶然发现了这本书，并写了这本书。
Seven Habits of Highly Effective People
高效能人士的七个习惯
so he went from skilled labor Consulting
所以他从技术工人转行做了咨询顾问。
to intellectual property and media which
知识产权和媒体
was his written word plus his book
他的文字加上他的书
publishing so that's step one and mind
发布，这是第一步，记住
you he sold 20 million copies and he
他卖出了2000万张唱片，而且他
built a $400 million consulting company
创建了一家价值 4 亿美元的咨询公司
but it was based on IP not his labor so
但这是基于知识产权而非他的劳动成果，所以
that's step one sitting above that is
那是上面提到的第一步。
data and um uh intellectual property
数据和知识产权
media and data and software so once we
媒体、数据和软件，所以一旦我们
have IP and media now we want data and
我们现在有了IP和媒体，我们想要数据和
software so data is where we build a
软件，也就是数据，是我们构建软件的基础。
database we get email addresses we get
我们从数据库中获取电子邮件地址。
information about customers we know more
我们掌握的关于客户的更多信息
about markets we get people filling in
关于市场，我们会有人来填写相关信息。
forms we get people filling in
我们让人们填写的表格
scorecards we start conducting surveys
我们开始进行调查并制作评分卡
so we're capturing data that's unique to
因此，我们正在收集独有的数据
us and then software is the ability to
我们，然后软件就是能力
turn our intellectual property into an
将我们的知识产权转化为
engine that just automatically delivers
自动交付的引擎
a a result and in that software bucket
结果，并且属于那个软件桶
is the ability to create AI applications
是创建人工智能应用程序的能力
um so you're going to have to move your
嗯，所以你得搬家了。
way up that pyramid and then the final
沿着金字塔向上攀登，然后到达终点
little top of the pyramid is um the
金字塔顶端的小部分是嗯……
ability to create Financial assets
创造金融资产的能力
Financial assets is where you sell your
金融资产是指你出售你的
business for an amount of money so you
为一笔钱做生意，所以你
actually package all of that into a
实际上，将所有这些都打包成一个
business that can be sold and that
可以出售的业务，以及
business becomes a financial asset the
企业成为金融资产
shares become a financial asset and then
股票就成为了一种金融资产，然后……
you make a lot of money by selling a
你通过出售……赚了很多钱
company so you can't jump straight from
所以你不能直接从公司跳槽。
being labor or skilled labor straight up
直接从事体力劳动或技术劳动
to software and data uh and those sorts
软件和数据之类的东西
of things which is the AI Advanced AI
人工智能高级人工智能
stuff so you got to go through uh
所以你得经历这些事……
intellectual property media data
知识产权媒体数据
software and what you do with your money
软件以及你如何使用资金
so everyone has a different sort of
所以每个人都有不同的
Finance strategy or an investment
财务策略或投资
strategy what's your investment
策略是什么？你的投资是什么？
strategy uh I've said to you before that
策略嘛，我之前跟你说过。
I like I really trust the advice that
我喜欢，我真的很信任这个建议。
you can't outperform markets Market
你不可能跑赢市场。
everything's already priced into markets
一切价格都已反映在市场中。
so for me personally like I put money
所以对我个人而言，就像我投入资金一样。
into S&amp;P 500 I put you know basically
我基本上把钱投到了标普500指数上。
things that you'd call a store of wealth
你通常会称之为财富储备的东西
um I don't think that's particularly
嗯，我不认为这特别……
exciting I I'm not you know some
令人兴奋，我不是你知道的某些人
sometimes I see people talking about
有时我看到人们在谈论
like oh what should someone do if
比如，如果……该怎么办？
they're earning 50 Grand a year to
他们每年能挣5万美元。
invest honestly it's not going to do
诚实投资是行不通的。
anything like you you you just like
任何像你这样的人，你，你就像
obviously do it but I I believe it's far
当然应该这么做，但我认为这还很遥远。
better to take that money and invest it
最好把这笔钱拿去投资。
into your key relationships um I think
进入你的关键关系，嗯，我想
it's better to take that money and put
最好把那笔钱拿去存起来
it into a startup uh like actually you
把它变成一家创业公司，呃，就像实际上你
know buy yourself some time so you can
要懂得给自己争取一些时间，这样你就可以
you know move in what would move into
你知道搬进去之后会搬进去什么吗？
this new economy um the thing that
这种新经济，嗯，这件事……
excites me most is just creating really
最让我兴奋的就是创作。
valuable businesses um I have a group of
有价值的企业，嗯，我有一群
companies
公司
now um
现在嗯
and let me explain uh here here's an
让我解释一下，呃，这里有一个
idea the the economy doesn't want you to
经济形势不希望你这样做。
become Rich right doesn't want you to
致富并不希望你这样做
accumulate money right the whole economy
整个经济都在积累资金
is set up so that you can't get money um
它的设置是为了让你无法获得资金。
or you can't keep it um and what people
或者你不能保留它，嗯，还有人们
think you do to make money is that they
你认为赚钱的方法就是他们
think that you take a little piece out
想想你从中取出的一小部分
of the economy and squirrel it away and
从经济中获利并把它存起来
store it up and that's not actually how
把它储存起来，但实际上并非如此。
people become rich what they do is they
人们致富的方式是……
create something from their mind and
将他们的想象力转化为现实
they formalize it into a company and
他们将其正式化为一家公司，
then they get people to invest in that
然后他们就能吸引人们投资那个项目。
company and that creates new wealth in
公司，并创造新的财富
the economy that didn't exist never
不存在的经济体从未存在过
existed it was a figment of their
它存在过，但那是他们虚构出来的。
imagination and that new wealth we call
想象力和我们称之为“新财富”的那种新财富
that Innovation and
创新和
Entrepreneurship and what happens and
创业精神及其发展过程
I'll give you a real life example so uh
我给你举个现实生活中的例子，嗯……
bookmagic is one of my uh software
BookMagic 是我的软件之一。
startups we raised £400,000 for 10%
我们为初创公司筹集了 40 万英镑，占股 10%。
which means £ 3.6 million pound worth of
这意味着价值 360 万英镑的
value is new value that never existed
价值是以前从未存在过的新价值。
it's just added to the economy it's this
它只是对经济有所贡献而已。
new economic asset called shares in this
这种新的经济资产被称为股票。
company 10% of the shares were 400,000
公司10%的股份是40万股。
3.6 million is the other 90% that
360万是另外90%
doesn't actually exist exist it was just
实际上并不存在，它只是个传说而已。
a figment of the imagination so it's
这是想象的产物，所以……
it's called Innovation and
它被称为创新和
Entrepreneurship very slowly that
创业发展非常缓慢。
becomes more and more real and then
变得越来越真实，然后
bigger companies come in and acquire
更大的公司介入并收购
that or people acquire those shares and
或者人们收购了这些股份
then it becomes a liquidity event you
那么它就变成了流动性事件。
get capital and then you reinvest that
获得资金，然后将这些资金再投资。
Capital into creating new things in the
将资金投入到创造新事物中
economy so the way rich people become
经济，以及富人如何变得富有
rich is not by squirreling little bits
致富并非靠积攒零碎财物。
out of the existing economy it's by
从现有经济体系中脱离出来，是通过
creating something new that never
创造从未发生过的新事物
existed and slowly introducing that into
已经存在，并正在慢慢地将其引入
the economy right so it's it's building
经济形势良好，正在复苏
things that didn't H exist so when I
那些不存在的东西，所以当我
hear people trying to you know get this
听到有人试图弄到这个
tiny little bit out of the economy and
从经济中稍微脱离一点，
then they've got to pay taxes on it and
那么他们就得为此缴税。
then you know the UK government wants
那么你就知道英国政府想要什么了。
half of everything and it's it's
一半的一切，而且是它的
horrific you never like you will just be
可怕的是，你永远不会喜欢你，你只会是
on this treadmill you'll never get out
在这张跑步机上，你永远也出不来
of it but if you can create something
但如果你能创造一些东西就好了
and you can have Innovation and
你可以拥有创新，
Entrepreneurship you can build something
创业让你能够创造一些东西。
that's worth 5 million 10 million 20
那价值500万、1000万、2000万。
million from your mind from your brain
百万个来自你脑中的思想
um and then you introduce it and
嗯，然后你把它介绍出来，
formalize it and it goes into the
将其正式化，然后它就会进入……
economy and it's actually a new asset in
经济中，它实际上是一项新的资产。
the economy and what is the horror that
经济以及由此带来的恐怖究竟是什么？
we need to warn people about if they
我们需要提醒人们，如果他们
decide to do what you just said because
决定照你刚才说的做，因为
everything in life has a cost so getting
生活中的一切都有代价，所以获得
starting a$2 million company comes with
创办一家价值 200 万美元的公司需要付出怎样的努力
I meet so many Founders I had one in the
我遇到过很多创始人，其中一位就在我身边。
office yesterday um great founder from
昨天在办公室，嗯，伟大的创始人
the UK young young lady she's done
这位英国年轻女士已经完成了
exceptionally exceptionally well she
她表现得异常出色。
built a company that I think is going to
我创建了一家我认为会……的公司
make 35 million and um she's going
赚了3500万，嗯，她要走了
through a horrific
经历了一场该死的恐怖
time and came out of her brain yeah the
时间，然后从她的脑海中浮现出来，是的。
biggest horror is that we were never
最可怕的是我们从未存在过
trained for this right so all of society
接受过这方面训练，因此整个社会都应享有这项权利。
is built for the Industrial Revolution
为工业革命而建
system and it's not built for the um
系统，而且它并非为……而设计。
digital Revolution system so you know we
数字革命系统，所以你知道我们
were told don't be disruptive and yet
被告知不要扰乱秩序，然而
the disruptors are making all the money
颠覆者赚得盆满钵满。
we were told you know you can't ask
我们被告知你知道你不能问
someone uh to do your homework for you
找个人帮你做作业
yet the people who make all the money
然而，那些赚所有钱的人却是其他人。
get someone else to do all their
找别人来做他们所有的事情
homework for them uh we were told um you
他们的家庭作业，呃，我们被告知，嗯，你
know uh
知道了
you know don't be an attention seeker
你知道，别哗众取宠。
but attention Seekers make all the money
但那些博取关注的人赚得盆满钵满。
so there's all of this stuff that we
所以，有所有这些我们……
were taught about becoming standardized
他们学习了如何标准化。
component labor and that that mindset is
零部件劳动，以及这种思维方式
always fighting you when you're running
当你奔跑时，他总是与你对抗
a business because over here running a
因为我在这里经营一家企业
new business it's exciting it's
新业务令人兴奋！
exhilarating it's creative but it feels
令人兴奋，很有创意，但感觉
wrong feels like you're doing something
做错事的感觉就像你在做某件事。
like weird because you're outside of the
感觉很奇怪，因为你身处局外
system um so there's no blueprint
系统嘛，所以没有蓝图。
there's no clear blueprint that anybody
没有明确的蓝图可供任何人参考
trained you for yeah you didn't
你接受过这方面的训练，但你没有。
certainly didn't do schooling in fact
事实上，他肯定没有接受过正规教育。
schooling system taught you everything
学校教育教会了你一切
wrong it's the opposite they wanted you
错了，这跟他们想要的正好相反。
to become standardized component labor
成为标准化组件劳动力
and over here you have to be unique
在这里，你必须与众不同。
intellectual
知识分子
property you're also dealing with
你也在处理房产相关事宜
platforms that are brand new yeah and
是的，是全新的平台。
and a also just like a social
而且也像社交一样
environment that is brand new and I say
这是一个全新的环境，我说
that because obviously post pandemic the
那显然是因为疫情后
rules of work changed completely and the
工作规则彻底改变了，而且
zoom and Technology went from geography
缩放和技术从地理学转向了
to Ideal customer personas in
到理想客户画像
communities um so all of our entire
社区，嗯，所以我们所有的
economy in fact if you think about our
事实上，如果你想想我们的经济，就会发现
governments our governments are
我们的政府是
struggling because they Define
挣扎是因为他们定义
themselves by geography but the digital
他们本身按地理位置划分，但数字
world's not defined by geography so when
世界并非由地理位置定义，所以当
the government of the UK says we're
英国政府表示，我们
putting up the taxes all the
提高税收
millionaires go okay we'll
百万富翁们，好吧，我们会
leave and then they're like oh no I mean
离开之后，他们就会说，哦不，我的意思是
Norway did this as well right all these
挪威也做到了这一点，对吧？
multi-billionaires just packed up and
亿万富翁们收拾行装，离开了。
left oh we're introducing a wealth text
左边，我们正在引入财富文本
okay bye you you've commented a lot on
好的，再见，你评论了很多。
this over the last couple of months what
过去几个月里发生了什么？
is your position on this cuz there's
你对此事的立场是什么？因为……
been a lot there's lots going on
发生了很多事，有很多事情正在发生。
geopolitically the UK changed the tax
从地缘政治角度来看，英国改变了税收制度。
system us got Trump coming in and I
系统让我们看到了特朗普的到来，而我
he'll be in by the time this podcast is
他会在本期播客节目播出前到。
out probably but well my position is
可能不行，但我的立场是
that we should collect the most amount
我们应该收集最多的金额
of taxes that we can but the way to do
我们可以缴纳的税款，但方式却截然不同。
that is with low taxes not high taxes
也就是说，低税收而不是高税收。
because in a world where people can
因为在一个人们可以
freely move around you need to be an
自由行动，你需要成为一名
attractive place for people to come to
吸引人们前来的地方
um you know people say oh we you know we
嗯，你知道人们会说哦，我们，你知道我们
don't like rich people well actually
其实我不太喜欢有钱人。
rich people pay a lot of taxes 1% pay
富人缴纳大量税款，1%的人缴纳的税款也很多。
30% uh so you need if you wanted to
30% 嗯，所以如果你想要的话，你需要
double the tax base get a few more of
税基翻倍，就能多赚一些钱。
this 1% people to to come here the UK
这1%的人会来英国。
was thriving when we used to have uh a
当我们以前拥有……的时候，它发展得很好。
$10 million seis or sorry a 10 million
1000万美元，或者抱歉，1000万美元
entrepreneurs 10 million pound
企业家们投资了1000万英镑
entrepreneurs relief um you know made
企业家们松了一口气，你知道的。
the UK one of the best places to do
英国是做这件事的最佳地点之一。
business so just for people that have
所以，这只是为了那些有生意的人。
never experienced entrepreneurs relief
从未体验过创业者的解脱
can you explain exactly what that who
你能解释一下那个人到底是什么人吗？
that impacts and when yeah so
那会产生影响，而且是的，所以
essentially entrepreneurs relief
本质上是为企业家提供救济
acknowledged that entrepreneurs are
承认企业家是
taking a huge gamble in what they do
他们这样做是在冒巨大的风险。
they're pouring time effort energy and
他们投入了大量的时间、精力和心血。
resources into their business in an
将资源投入到他们的业务中
unpaid capacity and that when they
无偿劳动能力以及当他们
finally get a success if they get a
如果他们最终获得成功，那就意味着他们成功了。
success then one of the ways of of
成功之道之一
acknowledging that risk and making that
承认这种风险并做出这样的决定
a good decision is that you only pay 10%
一个明智的决定是，你只需支付10%。
tax on the first uh well it used to be
对第一笔交易的税，嗯，以前是这样的。
10 million um of exit value um and uh
1000万的退出价值，嗯，还有
now it's on the first 1 million of uh
现在它已经进入前100万了。
exit value so
退出值
essentially if you're paying roughly the
基本上，如果你支付的费用大致是
same as income tax on starting aany
与开始任何业务的所得税相同
company then for a lot of people they're
那么对很多人来说，这家公司就是
just not going to start a company right
就是不打算创办公司
they're not going to take the risk
他们不会冒这个险。
they're not going to innovate um and
他们不会进行创新。
then the investment also slows down if
如果……那么投资也会放缓。
people can earn more money by just
人们只需通过以下方式就能赚到更多钱：
sitting on their capital and sticking it
坐拥资本，坚持到底
into a property they're not going to
他们不会进入这处房产
invest in startups so you have to have
投资初创公司，所以你必须具备
if you want an economy that's based on
如果你想要一个基于……的经济体
actual Innovation and change and
真正的创新和变革
transformation and Ai and software and
转型、人工智能、软件和
data and the new economy you have to
数据和新经济你必须
incentivize investors to to to do that
激励投资者这样做
um it's also a globally competitive
嗯，它也是全球竞争的。
landscape so as soon as you've got you
风景，所以一旦你拥有了你
know Dubai saying hey we don't even do
知道迪拜会说“嘿，我们甚至都不做”
income tax right and also when you go to
所得税权利以及当你去的时候
Dubai tax feels like such a scam because
迪拜的税收感觉就像个骗局，因为
you go wait a second their police force
你去等一下，他们的警察部队
their hospitals work everything's clean
他们的医院运转良好，一切都很干净。
they've got no potholes their buildings
他们的建筑物没有坑洼。
are amazing no crime no crime uh the
太棒了，没有犯罪，没有犯罪，呃
transport's working like the whole place
交通运输和整个地方一样运转良好
is working like clockwork you go but how
它像钟表一样精准运转，你照常进行，但是如何呢？
are they doing this without collecting
他们这样做难道不是为了收集信息吗？
45% of the economy is tax in the UK
英国经济的45%用于税收。
45% of the entire economy is government
政府占整个经济的45%。
spending are people leaving the UK
支出导致人们离开英国
10,000 millionaires left last year so
去年有1万名百万富翁离开了。
when I think about all the really
当我想到所有那些真正
exceptional people that I hired over the
我雇佣的优秀人才
last 10 15 years every single one of the
过去10到15年里的每一个人
the truly exceptional ones that I go I'd
那些我去过的真正杰出的……
bet a lot on that person they all live
他们都押注在那个人身上，他们都活着
in Dubai MH they've all gone some of
在迪拜MH，他们都去过一些地方。
them have moved to America some of them
他们中的一些人已经移居美国。
are working in SF even America which is
甚至在美国旧金山工作
high tax but you start paying the
税收很高，但你开始缴纳
highest rate of tax at eight times the
最高税率为八倍
average wage here you pay the highest
这里的平均工资最高，但你需要支付最高的工资。
rate of tax at three times the average
税率是平均税率的三倍
wage yeah so they they're not letting
工资？是啊，所以他们不让。
any get ahead now the other day uh K
前几天有什么进展吗？嗯，K
stama says we want to be leaders in AI
Stama表示，我们希望成为人工智能领域的领导者。
well unfortunately we have the most
很遗憾，我们拥有最多的
expensive electricity so you can't run
电费昂贵，所以你跑不动
data centers here uh and we also have
这里有数据中心，我们还有
the highest tax rates so highly skilled
最高税率，因此高技能
highly talented people do not want to be
才华横溢的人并不想成为
here and I hate to say it everyone's
这里，虽然我不想这么说，但每个人都……
like oh you know we need to tax the rich
比如，你知道我们需要对富人征税。
sorry they can leave they they really
抱歉，他们可以离开了，他们真的
can and in this digital economy with a
在这个数字经济时代，我们可以……
personal brand with data with software
利用软件数据打造个人品牌
with media assets those assets pick up
媒体资产会吸引这些资产。
on a phone like you literally leave with
就像你真的会带着手机离开一样
your phone and you're fine I saw this
你的手机没事，我看到了。
narrative playing out over the last year
过去一年来的故事发展
and I'm a skeptic I'm also like
我是一个怀疑论者，我也喜欢
politically apolitical yeah same I'm so
政治上不关心政治？是啊，我也是。
I don't have a team I look at these
我没有团队，我看看这些
narratives playing out and I try and
故事正在上演，我试着……
figure out if it's a certain person has
弄清楚是不是某个人拥有
an agenda they're trying to push a
他们试图推行的议程
narrative because they're rich and they
因为他们富有，所以他们才会讲述这个故事
want the tax lower or if another person
想降低税负，或者如果是其他人
on the other side has an agenda because
对方另有图谋，因为
they want to tax the rich more and where
他们想对富人征收更多税，而且是在……
I ended up Landing purely based on what
我最终选择登陆完全取决于什么
I saw in my life with um rich people
我一生中见过一些有钱人。
around me and the decisions they started
我周围的人和他们开始做出的决定
to make is a lot of the most successful
制作很多最成功的东西
people that if I was kired armor I'd
如果我穿着基雷德盔甲，我会……
want to keep in this country especially
尤其想留在这个国家
the ones that don't have the mortgage
那些没有抵押贷款的人
yet and the family they are off they're
然而，他们一家人却离开了。
off they are they are going and then the
他们走了，他们要走了，然后
stats came out which I think recently
最近公布了一些统计数据，我认为是这样的。
said that about 10,000 we've had like an
他说，我们已经有大约10000个了，就像……
exodus of these people and I know I know
这些人的外流，我知道我知道
it's triggering for some people because
这会引发某些人的心理创伤，因为
they hate rich people and they
他们他妈的恨透了有钱人，而且他们
they just think that rich people should
他们只是认为富人应该
just um but if you are truly I think in
嗯，不过如果你真的……我想……
the middle you do come to understand to
你最终会理解中间部分
some degree that the backbone of our
在某种程度上，这是我们的脊梁。
economy is entrepreneurship small
经济就是小企业
businesses with AI and Technology
利用人工智能和技术的企业
becoming an even greater part of our
成为我们生活中更重要的一部分
economy there's a certain type of
经济中存在某种类型的
entrepreneur that's likely to build and
很可能建立和发展事业的企业家
succeed in AI that we really need to
我们真正需要的是在人工智能领域取得成功
keep and they we are competing
保持，我们正在竞争
geographically with San Francisco Dubai
地理位置上与旧金山和迪拜相邻
Abu Dhabi we absolutely are the other
阿布扎比，我们绝对是另一个
reason the other thing people think that
人们认为的另一件事的原因
rich people are taking money out of the
富人正在把钱从……中取出
economy and the opposite is happening
经济形势却恰恰相反，正在发生这样的变化。
they're creating wealth that pumps into
他们创造的财富会注入……
the economy and they're creating it from
他们正在创造经济，并从中汲取灵感。
figments of their imagination they're
那是他们想象出来的。
building things that didn't exist that
建造原本不存在的事物
come into the econ as New Wealth if we
如果我们进入经济体系，新财富就会成为我们的一部分。
were living now mind you that's not all
请注意，我们现在就生活在这样的环境中，但这并非全部。
millionaires some millionaires are
有些百万富翁是百万富翁。
horrible landlords who make their money
那些靠坑蒙拐骗赚钱的糟糕房东
by bullying people uh if you live in
通过欺凌他人，呃，如果你住在
certain locations the only millionaires
某些地方只有百万富翁
you've met are probably uh slum
你遇到的那些人，大概都是些贫民窟居民吧。
landlords or something like that that's
房东之类的。
not who we're talking about we're not
不是我们谈论的对象，我们不是
talking about people who are rent
谈论租房的人
Seekers or people who you know kind of
寻求者或你认识的那种人
bully people around or any of that sort
欺凌他人或任何类似行为
of stuff we're talking about wealth
我们正在谈论的是关于财富的事情。
creators uh people who are coming up
创作者，呃，那些崭露头角的人
with new intellectual property and
拥有新的知识产权
bringing it into the economy to create
将其引入经济体系以创造
jobs and wealth and Investments and they
工作、财富、投资以及它们
make the world go around one of the
让世界围绕其中一个运转
reasons we have wealth inequality is not
我们造成财富不平等的原因并非如此。
what's being talked about wealth
人们都在谈论财富
inequality is because of technology and
不平等是由于技术造成的，
Technology adoption so I want you to
技术普及，所以我希望你
imagine that we've got two people who
想象一下，我们有两个人，
are racing each other in a marathon one
他们在马拉松比赛中互相竞争
person is running and one person's on a
一个人在奔跑，另一个人在……
bicycle so they've got technology that
自行车，所以他们拥有这种技术。
they're leveraging the person on the
他们正在利用这个人。
bicycle is going to be powering ahead
自行车将继续向前疾驰
effortlessly and it's going to look like
毫不费力，而且看起来会像这样
a very unfair thing and you say well
这很不公平，你说得对。
this person works just as hard as this
这个人工作起来和这个人一样努力。
person why are they getting ahead a lot
为什么有些人总是能取得如此大的成功？
faster cuz this one on the cycle is
速度更快，因为这个在循环中。
leveraging technology and this person is
利用科技，而这个人是
not leveraging technology when we go
当我们外出时，没有充分利用技术
through these great shifts we actually
通过这些巨大的转变，我们实际上
get people who are stuck in the old
让那些困在旧世界的人
system and people who are in the new
系统和新系统中的人员
system Charles Dickens wrote about this
查尔斯·狄更斯曾写过关于这个系统的描述。
in the early Industrial Revolution there
在工业革命初期
were all of these kids that were on the
这些孩子当时都在……
street right all of a Twist and there
街道右侧全是扭曲，然后就到了。
was this huge wealth inequality as some
这种巨大的财富不平等是否如某些人所说的那样？
people were industrialists and some
这些人是实业家，还有一些
people were still in the feudal system
人们仍然处于封建制度之下。
and the agricultural age some people's
以及农业时代某些人的
income was linked to capitalism some
收入与资本主义有些联系在一起。
people's link income was linked to
人们的收入与……有关
feudalism um so in the same way that
封建主义，嗯，所以也以同样的方式
that was happening then we're going to
当时正在发生那件事，我们要去
see a very similar Dickens I mean he had
我觉得他跟狄更斯很像，我的意思是，他有
that famous book called The Tale of Two
那本著名的书叫做《双子传说》。
Cities it was the best of times it was
城市，那是最好的时代。
the worst of times was the opening line
最糟糕的时代是开篇第一句
we're going to have the same thing now
我们现在也要面临同样的问题。
it was the best of times it was the
这是最好的时代，这是
worst of times because we're going to
最糟糕的时刻，因为我们将要
have some people who are leveraging
有些人正在利用……
technology uh and they live a life of
科技，他们过着这样的生活
fun Freedom fulfillment financial
乐趣、自由、成就感和财务自由
success and with some people who are
成功，以及与一些人的合作
stuck in the Industrial Age who sit
那些停留在工业时代的人坐在
there and say I work as hard as I
在那里，我会说我工作非常努力。
possibly can and I cannot get ahead I'm
或许可以，但我无法取得进展。
falling behind year after year after
年复一年地落后
year and it's because we have two
今年，因为我们有两个
systems operating in parallel okay so
系统并行运行，好的。
the people that would counter you now at
现在会反对你的人
when you talk about you know the idea
当你谈到你知道的那个想法时
that these individuals that are leaving
这些离开的人
our wealth creators um what is the
我们的财富创造者，嗯，什么是……
Counterpoint that is that
反驳观点是：
is you know does make sense there are
你知道，这确实有道理。
some rich people I know that are
我认识的一些有钱人是
hoarding a lot of stuff I mean they are
他们囤积了很多东西，我的意思是，他们是
they're also they do create
他们也确实创造了
opportunities for the economy but they
经济机遇，但它们
are they're in a hoarding season of life
他们正处于囤积物资的时期吗？
just kind of stacking it up they're not
他们只是在堆积东西，他们不是。
really giving it to many people and
真的给了很多人
they're playing certain money games just
他们只是在玩一些金钱游戏而已。
to build wealth and not necessarily
积累财富，不一定
creating huge economic
创造巨大的经济效益
value um so what we need is nuance and
价值嘛，所以我们需要的是细微差别和
we need the Nuance to understand that
我们需要理解其中的细微差别。
there are poor people who are who are um
有些穷人……
rent Seekers who are not productive who
那些不追求利润的寻租者
are takers from the economy there are
经济中的掠夺者有很多。
rich people who are takers from the
那些从……中攫取利益的有钱人
economy and there are rich people who
经济状况良好，而且也有富人
are phenomenal wealth creators who
他们是杰出的财富创造者，
create opportunities around them there
为他们创造机会
are poor people who are phenomenally
他们是贫穷却非常出色的人
valuable to the economy so if we were to
对经济有价值，所以如果我们要
just simply uh make no distinction by
就简单地说，不做任何区分
just simply the level of wealth or
仅仅是财富水平或
income it doesn't distinguish between
收入不区分
let's say a nurse who's on 30,000 and
假设一位护士的年薪是 30,000 美元，
someone who's a drug dealer on 30,000
一个贩毒分子，身价30000美元
they're not they might be economically
他们不是，他们可能在经济上是。
the same they're not the same types of
它们虽然相同，但并非同一种类型。
people in the economy so um what we need
经济中的人们，所以，嗯，我们需要什么
to do is have some nuance and understand
要做的就是要有一些细微差别并理解
what is the behaviors that we want to
我们想要的行为是什么？
incentivize what is the behaviors that
激励哪些行为
we want to uh avoid we want to make it
我们想避免，我们想做到
hard to Simply stick all of your money
很难简单地把所有的钱都存起来。
in expensive assets and then rent them
投资昂贵资产，然后出租它们
out uh we want to tax that uh and we
呃，我们想对它征税，呃，我们
want to make it easy to invest in new
想让投资新项目变得更容易
economy we want to want to make it easy
我们希望经济能够变得容易
to bring down the prices of things we
为了降低商品价格，我们
want to make it easy to we want to make
我们想让它变得简单，我们想让它变得简单
it easy for wealthy people to invest
富人很容易投资
into startups uh we want to make it easy
进入创业领域，我们希望让它变得简单。
for people to relocate here um and uh
让人们搬迁到这里……嗯……
you know it's an attractive opportunity
你知道这是一个很有吸引力的机会。
to BU to build a business here and
来波士顿大学创业
create jobs here we've just stuck a 15%
在这里创造就业机会，我们刚刚设定了15%的利率。
tax on top of employing people so a lot
除了雇佣员工之外，还要缴纳很多税款。
of entrepreneurs have responded by
企业家们已经做出了回应
Outsourcing to remote workers um I know
外包给远程工作者，嗯，我知道。
plenty of companies that are now hiring
现在有很多公司正在招聘
people in the Philippines and South
菲律宾和南部的人们
Africa because it's 15 but straight off
非洲，因为它是15，但直接
the back all things being equal it's 15%
在其他条件相同的情况下，背面是15%。
cheaper to hire someone overseas than
雇佣海外员工比雇佣海外员工更便宜
here you know so the government is
你知道，所以政府是
making the wrong moves they're just
他们只是做出了错误的决定。
doing the wrong thing they're making it
他们做错了事，结果反而造成了现在的局面。
expensive to hire people here they're
在这里雇佣员工成本很高。
making expensive for talented people to
这使得有才华的人成本高昂
live here and be here um so the economy
住在这里，待在这里，嗯，所以经济
is going to suffer until they get their
他们会一直受苦，直到他们得到……
head around the fact that we're a
别纠结于我们是……
globally competitive economy we have to
在全球竞争激烈的经济环境中，我们必须
be globally competitive that we live in
在全球竞争中，我们生活在一个
a digital world it's just going to get
数字化世界终将到来
worse and worse is this in part because
情况越来越糟，部分原因是……
the way that the political system is set
政治体制的设定方式
up is that the prime minister or the
是首相还是
president has four years so actually
总统任期四年，所以实际上
they're quite short term because I'm
因为它们都是短期的，因为我
thinking of K D he's he's saying that he
想到K D，他说他
walked into this deficit and now he it's
他当初承担了这笔债务，现在他……
looks like he scrambling around for the
他看起来好像在四处奔波寻找……
money and the long-term play here would
金钱和长远发展前景
be we need to change the schooling
我们需要改变学校教育
system so that in 15 years time we've
建立这样的系统，以便在15年后我们能够
got a lot of AI um knowledge based in
掌握了很多基于人工智能的知识
our economy it's not that it's just that
我们的经济，不仅仅是这样。
in the Industrial Age we created
在工业时代，我们创造了
institutions that were appropriate for
适合的机构
the Industrial Age and now they've run
工业时代，现在他们已经……
to the end and now they're just outdated
一直用到最后，现在它们都过时了。
uh look at the name the UK government
呃，看看这个名字：英国政府
that means it's a geographical border
这意味着它是一条地理边界。
the London city council means it's a M25
伦敦市议会将其定义为M25高速公路。
right uh is is the geography the the
对，呃，是地理。
British you know uh the the UK economy
英国，你知道，呃，英国经济
uh so anything that is defined by
呃，所以任何由……定义的事物
geography already misses the point
地理学已经偏离了重点
straight off the bat it misses the point
一开始就没抓住重点。
and the point is that we live in a a
关键在于我们生活在一个
world where you can sell to anyone in
在这个世界里，你可以把东西卖给任何人。
the world you can uh hire anyone in the
在这个世界里，你可以雇佣任何人。
world you can pay anyone in the world uh
在世界上，你可以付钱给世界上任何人。
you can build a brand effortlessly from
你可以轻松地从以下方面打造品牌：
your phone you can live and work from
你可以用手机生活和工作
anywhere you can create companies super
任何你能创建超级公司的地方
easily like all of those things like the
很容易就喜欢上所有这些东西，比如……
fundamental technology has shifted so
基础技术已经发生了如此巨大的转变。
it's like saying oh how do we change the
这就像在问，哦，我们该如何改变……
Juke and Lord system and the surf
Juke 和 Lord 系统以及冲浪
serfdom system it's like well that was
农奴制就像……嗯，那就是……
for the agricultural age that was the
对于农业时代而言，那就是
system that evolved we're going to need
我们需要的这套不断演化的系统
a completely different system because we
一个完全不同的系统，因为我们
now have an industrialized economy so
现在拥有工业化经济，所以
unfortunately we're going into a digital
不幸的是，我们将进入数字化时代。
uh world or we're in a digital world and
呃，世界，或者说我们身处一个数字世界。
the entire government is set up for the
整个政府的设立都是为了……
industrial economy national identity was
工业经济民族认同是
a massive thing in the Industrial Age
工业时代一件大事
National currency was a was a very big
国家货币曾经是一个非常大的货币。
thing for the industrial age um do you
工业时代的东西，嗯，你呢？
think Trump's going to make good
我认为特朗普会做得很好
decisions he's certainly going to be a
他肯定会做出一些决定。
disruptor he's going to be an accelerant
他会是个颠覆者，也会是个加速器。
whatever's happening um I think he's
不管发生了什么事，嗯，我觉得他是……
going to break things that we're going
我们要打破一些东西。
to break and I think he's probably going
打破僵局，我觉得他可能要走了
to bring in some things that uh you know
引进一些东西，你知道的
emerge as as good things um I think we
出现是好事，嗯，我认为我们
were definitely going in the wrong
我们肯定走错了方向。
direction um you know we were becoming
方向，嗯，你知道，我们正在变成
you know governments of the world were
你知道世界各国政府是
becoming very authoritarian for a while
有一段时间变得非常专制
there um you know they were really
你知道，他们当时真的很……
policing uh different you know elements
警务工作涉及不同的要素
of our lives and spee and those sorts
我们的生活、言语以及诸如此类的事情
things and uh all of that's going to
事情，还有所有那些都将……
definitely swing back the other way the
肯定会朝另一个方向摇摆不定
pendulum is already swung back the other
钟摆已经摆回另一边了。
way if you saw the Mark Zuckerberg uh
如果你见过马克·扎克伯格的话……
announcement the other day are you
前几天的公告是你吗？
bullish on America oh America is
看好美国，哦，美国是
definitely the most bullish Place yeah
绝对是最看涨的地方，没错。
so so this is goes back to something I
所以，这要追溯到我之前说过的一些话。
said earlier in terms of if I'm an
前面说过，如果我是一个
entrepreneur and I want to position
企业家，我想定位
myself where the opportunity is where
我自己在哪里，机会就在哪里。
the capital is where the mentality is
首都是思想所在的地方。
yeah where is actually online so the the
是的，实际上它在哪里在线，所以
the we is digital um you know you can go
我们指的是数字化，嗯，你知道你可以去
to Silicon Valley and you'll see some of
去硅谷，你就会看到一些
the poorest people living next to some
住在某些地方附近的最贫困的人
of the richest people so it's not a
是最富有的人，所以这不是一个
geographical thing it's a mindset and
地理因素，这是一种思维方式。
the mindset is digital versus analog or
思维方式是数字化与模拟的对比，或者
digital versus GE geographical so but
数字技术与地理信息系统 (GE) 的区别，但
the biggest economy the winner take all
最大的经济体，赢家通吃
is the US right because the US is in a
美国是对的，因为美国正处于……
very unique position they're energy
他们所处的位置非常独特，他们充满活力。
independent they're food independent
它们是独立的，它们的食物是独立的。
they've got na massive natural
他们拥有大量的自然资源
geographical borders so they don't have
地理边界，所以它们没有
to police their neighbors they don't
他们不会去管束邻居。
have they have one friendly neighbor at
他们有一位友好的邻居吗？
the North called Canada and one uh
北方称之为加拿大，还有一个呃
neighbor they can work with called
他们可以与之合作的邻居，叫做
Mexico below contrast China I think they
墨西哥与中国形成鲜明对比，我认为他们
got 17 uh neighbors to manage so um the
我要管理17个邻居，所以……
US has got clear runways biggest economy
美国拥有畅通无阻的跑道，是全球最大的经济体。
in the world um most technology most
在世界上，大多数技术
universities all of that sort of
大学等等
stuff we take our time when it comes to
我们会花时间认真对待的事情
hiring at flight story because I
Flight Story 正在招聘，因为我
fundamentally believe the success of a
从根本上相信成功
business is directly linked to how good
商业与质量直接相关。
you are at hiring and better hiring
你正在招聘，并且正在招聘更好的人才。
starts with smarter insights LinkedIn
从更智能的洞察开始 LinkedIn
who's a sponsor of this podcast to some
谁是这个播客的赞助商？
of the strongest hiring data available
现有最可靠的招聘数据
to help you identify the best candidates
帮助您找到最佳候选人
for your business their platform will
他们的平台将为您的企业提供服务
even paay you with those who match what
甚至会和那些符合条件的人一起支付你报酬
you're looking for which might lie
你正在寻找的可能
outside of the job description and More
工作职责范围之外及更多
in their unique skills and interests
他们拥有独特的技能和兴趣
because these days hiring isn't just
因为如今招聘不仅仅是
about finding the most qualified person
关于寻找最合格的人
but also finding the one whose
但也要找到那个人
experience abilities and interests align
经验、能力和兴趣相符
with your company's Mission and it goes
与贵公司的使命相符，然后……
beyond candidates who are applying for
除了正在申请的候选人之外
jobs too in any given week 17 1 million
每周新增就业岗位17个，达到100万个。
members who aren't actively seeking jobs
不积极寻找工作的成员
are open to New Opportunities find your
乐于接受新机遇，找到你的
next great hire on LinkedIn and start
LinkedIn上的下一个优秀招聘对象，开始
today by posting your job for free just
今天就免费发布您的招聘信息吧！
by visiting linkedin.com
通过访问 linkedin.com
doac so is there anything else that
doac，还有其他什么吗？
would be on the list of things that if
如果……，那将列入清单。
you were a you know a 21-year-old Daniel
你当时是，你知道，一个21岁的丹尼尔
Priestley and you're in
普里斯特利，你也在其中
2025 what are the like fundamental moves
2025年有哪些类似的基本面变化
You' be making I can guess a couple of
你会做一些我猜想是几件的事情
things You' definitely be making content
你肯定会创作内容
yeah for sure you'd be climbing the
是的，你肯定会爬上去的。
podcast pyramid to build more and more
播客金字塔正在不断壮大
leverage and reputation Etc are there
杠杆作用和声誉等等都存在。
any other big big stuff so the big so
还有其他什么大事，所以大事
the key is the big opportunity is build
关键在于，最大的机遇在于建设。
a personal brand next to an elegant
优雅的个人品牌
business model that is that's everything
商业模式，这就是一切。
if you build the personal brand it
如果你打造个人品牌
doesn't have to be a massive personal
不必是件大事。
brand if you've got 5 to 50,000
如果你有 5 到 50,000 个品牌
followers within a high value Niche if
在高价值细分领域拥有众多追随者
you're seen as a key person of influence
你被视为一位关键的影响力人物。
in a high value Niche that's enough of a
在高价值的细分市场中，这就足够了。
personal brand to make seven figures uh
打造个人品牌，赚取七位数收入
if you've got an elegant business model
如果你有一个精妙的商业模式
you can sell to anyone in the world uh
你可以把产品卖给世界上任何人。
you can communicate your value to anyone
你可以向任何人展现你的价值
in the world that's some of the stuff
世界上有些东西就是这样。
with an elegant business model so
凭借优雅的商业模式
essentially those are the two pillars if
从本质上讲，这就是两大支柱。
you're not financially successful or
你经济上并不成功，或者
where you want to be at the moment you
此刻你想去的地方
want to look at building a personal
想看看如何构建个人
brand and attaching that personal brand
品牌以及与个人品牌的关联
to the right business those are the two
对合适的企业来说，这就是这两点。
steps so ultimately if you said if I was
步骤，所以最终如果你说如果我是
21 I'm trying to build my personal brand
21 我正在努力打造我的个人品牌
I'm trying to attach that brand to a per
我正试图将该品牌与一个个人联系起来。
to a great business that's the key to
打造一家伟大的企业，关键在于……
Capital it's the key to Talent it's the
资本是关键，人才是关键。
key to customers so it's that personal
对客户而言至关重要，所以这非常个性化。
brand on a scalable business you look at
品牌在可扩展业务中的作用，值得您关注
every single person who's who's
每一个人，无论他是谁
succeeding right now they're focused on
他们现在取得成功的重点是
just those two things why don't people
就这两件事，为什么人们不这么做呢？
do that when you when they hear you say
当你说的时候，就那样做。
all of that why is it that they then
这一切，为什么他们最终却……
don't do it and those people agree so
不要这样做，那些人也同意这一点。
they're sat at home now they go yeah I
他们现在坐在家里，他们会说，是的，我
get it I the foundations you laid are
我明白了，你打下的基础是
perfect make sense and they still don't
完美是合理的，但他们仍然不合理
I'll tell you why years ago I went to
我来告诉你为什么多年前我去了
Barley and I saw this massive Mountain
我和巴利看到了这座巨大的山
on the horizon and uh we decided that we
在地平线上，呃，我们决定我们
were going to book a a trip to climb it
我们打算预订一次登山之旅。
and uh it's called Mount uh Mount aong
呃，它叫安山。
so they wake us up at midnight and we
所以他们会在半夜把我们叫醒，然后我们
get in a bus and we have to go to the
坐上公交车，我们得去……
mountain at midnight and climb through
午夜时分攀登高山
the night right it was crazy and so from
那晚真是太疯狂了，所以……
1:00 in the morning all through the
凌晨1点，一直到凌晨1点
night we got this tiny little headlamp
那天晚上我们拿到了这个小小的头灯
on and we're climbing and we're
继续，我们正在攀登，我们正在
scratching and we're like going up the
抓挠，我们就像在往上爬
side of the mountain
山的一侧
and finally we get up there about 6:00
最后我们大约6点钟到达那里。
a.m. and I'm like I didn't even realize
早上，我心想我都没意识到。
why we were climbing through the night
我们为何彻夜攀爬
like it hadn't even occurred to me why
我之前竟然完全没想过为什么
would we be doing it like this and then
我们会这样做吗？
finally we get up the top and I realize
最后我们爬到了顶峰，我意识到
oh this is why we're doing it at 6: a.m.
哦，这就是我们为什么早上6点做这件事的原因。
cuz the sun comes up at 6: a.m. so we
因为太阳早上6点升起，所以我们
get to the top of the mountain and the
到达山顶，然后
sun comes up and it's like glorious the
太阳升起，景色美极了。
air is thin it's crisp it's just
空气稀薄，空气清新，就是这样。
incredible and it's cold right which is
难以置信，而且现在很冷，对吧？
rare in barley and then the sun lights
大麦很少见，然后阳光照耀着大麦。
up barley and I can see all of barley
向上望去，可以看到所有的大麦。
and all of glimmering sea and it was
还有波光粼粼的大海，那就是
just beautiful I'm standing there and
真是太美了，我站在那里，
I'm just loving it taking it in and we
我非常享受这一切，我们
put eggs in the uh hole and the volcano
把鸡蛋放进那个洞里，然后放进火山里
steam Cooks the eggs and then I look
蒸汽把鸡蛋煮熟，然后我看着
onto the Horizon and there's this thing
地平线上，有这么个东西。
called Mount ranani I say to the guide
我对向导说，这座山名叫拉纳尼山。
what's that mountain over there he goes
他走过去问：“那边那座山是什么？”
oh that's Mount ranani I go oh is that
哦，那是拉纳尼山，我去，哦，是吗？
on the island of b he goes no no that's
在B岛上，他说不不，那是
on a different Island I go oh how do you
在另一个岛上，我问，哦，你怎么……
get there you got to catch a ferry how
到那儿你得坐渡轮，怎么走？
many days does it take oh you got to go
需要好几天？哦，你得走了
for three days how long does it take to
三天需要多长时间？
climb oh it takes about this much CL is
爬升大约需要这么多 CL 是
it higher or lower or blah blah blah how
它更高还是更低，或者等等等等，怎么会这样
much is it can I book through through
我能通过什么方式预订？
you and he says Mr Daniel you need to
你和他说丹尼尔先生，你需要
appreciate the mountain you're standing
欣赏你脚下这座山峰。
on right
右侧
now puts his arm around me you need to
现在他搂着我，你需要
learn to appreciate the mountain you're
学会欣赏你所在的这座山。
already standing on so when I was
我已经站在那里了，所以当我……
standing on that mountain I could see
站在那座山上，我可以看到
everything but the mountain right I'm
除了山以外，我什么都有。
looking around the Horizon I'm seeing
环顾四周，我看到地平线上……
all this I'm seeing the mountain on the
我看到这一切，就像看到了山一样。
thing but I couldn't see the mountain
但我看不到山。
that I was already standing on because I
我当时已经站在上面了，因为我
was too close to it so the biggest thing
离得太近了，所以最大的事情
that people Miss in today's world is
当今世界人们所怀念的是
that they already standing on a mountain
他们已经站在山上了
of value they've already got so much
他们已经拥有如此多的价值了
value but they're so distracted by the
价值，但他们却被其他事情分散了注意力
mountain on the horizon they go oh
他们看着地平线上的山峰，发出“哦”的叹息。
Steven bartler he's already so much
史蒂文·巴特勒，他已经非常非常
further ahead he's creating he creates
更进一步，他正在创造他正在创造
podcast I could never do that right or
播客 我永远也做不好那个，或者
they go oh uh you know I saw this person
他们说，哦，呃，你知道，我看到这个人了
who's really good in my industry and
我所在行业里最优秀的人是谁？
they wrote a book and I could never
他们写了一本书，而我永远也无法理解。
write like that or you know you you know
那样写，或者你知道，你知道
I don't know I've got anything of value
我不知道我有没有值钱的东西。
to share some people have floated a
分享一下，有些人提出了一个
company for a billion dollars and I I'm
一家价值十亿美元的公司，而我……
only you know I've only just started
只有你知道我才刚刚开始
right what am I going to share and what
好吧，我要分享什么呢？
they miss is that every single person
他们忽略的是，每个人都是如此。
your story is relevant your background
你的故事与你的背景相关
is relevant uh the people that you know
这与你认识的人有关。
is part of the Mountain of value you
是你价值之山的一部分
know the your relatability is part of
要知道，你的亲和力是……的一部分
the Mountain of value you're losing your
您正在失去的价值山
relatability because as you go so high
因为当你达到如此高的境界时，共鸣感就会增强。
people just starting out can't even
刚入行的人甚至都做不到。
comprehend how to get there so someone
明白如何到达那里，以便某人
in the middle is going to take a place
中间部分将占据一个位置
that you previously occupied because
你之前占据的，因为
they're more relatable they're only two
他们更容易引起共鸣，因为他们只有两个人。
steps ahead not 20 steps ahead so every
不是提前20步，​​而是每一步。
single person has this mountain of value
单身人士拥有如此巨大的价值。
but the biggest thing at the moment is
但目前最重要的事情是
the distraction of all the other stuff
其他种种事情分散了我的注意力。
and you're so close to your own mountain
你离自己的山如此之近
of value you can't see it so the first
你看不见它的价值，所以第一个
thing I love to do is just put my arm
我最喜欢做的事就是把我的胳膊伸过去。
around people and say please learn to
在人群中说“请学习”
appreciate the mountain you're already
欣赏你眼前的这座山峰
standing
常设
on it's so true and um yeah so I was
确实如此，嗯，是的，所以我当时
just talking to someone before you came
在你来之前和人聊了一会儿
in about my my girlfriend she's a breath
说到我的女朋友，她简直像个呼吸一样。
work practitioner her St she's got her
工作实践者她的圣她有她的
own Studio B breathwork do.com if anyone
拥有 Studio B 呼吸练习 do.com 的人
wants to go to her Retreats and she um
她想去参加她的静修活动，她嗯……
hashtag ad I guess um and she we're
#广告 我想嗯，她和我们是
spending a lot of time talking about
花很多时间谈论
making Instagram videos again and in
再次制作 Instagram 视频
fact I think a year two years passes and
事实上，我认为一年两年就过去了。
she's talking about it and she's going
她正在谈论这件事，而且她要去
to buy she buys a camera and buys
她买了一台相机，然后又买了一台其他东西。
another camera and buys another camera
又买了一台相机。
Etc as we all do and um I realized that
等等，就像我们所有人一样，嗯，我意识到……
eventually the reason why she wasn't
最终，她没能成功的原因揭晓了。
starting is she was
开头是她
so I think a little bit too focused on
所以我觉得有点太专注于……
how it might perform that first video
它会如何表现第一段视频
she dropped that she never dropped the
她放弃了，她从未放弃过
video and I was reading um reading a
视频，我当时正在看书，嗯，正在看书。
book over the Christmas break I think it
我觉得可以在圣诞假期期间读这本书。
was the courage to be disliked and it
是被人讨厌的勇气，以及
talks about the possibility Gap
谈到差距的可能性
something like the possibility Gap where
类似可能性差距之类的东西
it's the Gap when you say you announce
当你宣布的时候，那就是盖普。
your
你的
intention and before you do it and you
意图，在你做这件事之前，你
can live in this Gap because there's
能够生活在这个缺口中，是因为有
been no evidence to prove you can't yet
目前还没有证据证明你不能这样做。
there's been no evidence to prove that
目前还没有证据证明这一点。
you're actually not good at violin or
你其实并不擅长拉小提琴
you're not good at dejing so you can
你不擅长德劲，所以你可以
live in this gap for a long time it's
长时间生活在这种差距中是……
like the world of the realm of
就像那个领域的世界一样
possibility you've announced it people
有可能你已经向人们宣布过了
are now giving you credit for it and
现在他们把功劳归于你了。
there's been no evidence to prove you
没有任何证据证明你
can't do it and one of the things
我做不到，而且其中一件事
actually got her posting over Christmas
实际上，她在圣诞节期间发帖了。
was when I I said to her instead of like
当时我对她说，而不是像
trying to make good videos let's make
努力制作优质视频，让我们开始吧！
the objective get to video
目标是获得视频
1,000 she's she's posted every day since
1000 她每天都发帖，从
she's posted 30 OD videos on her
她在她的网站上发布了30个吸毒过量视频。
Instagram since then changed the goal
此后，Instagram改变了目标。
the minute she the goal became let's get
她立刻就把目标定为“让我们开始吧”。
to video 1,000 she was Off to the Races
视频播放量达到1000次，她开始参加比赛了。
the other thing that happens is in an
另一件事发生在……
exponential World in an exponential
指数级世界中的指数级增长
curve every double eclipses everything
曲线每双重蚀都掩盖一切
that came before it and when you go
那件事发生在它之前，当你走的时候
through a doubling speed you're doubling
通过倍速，你正在翻倍
and doubling and doubling each double is
而每翻倍再翻倍，就是
worth everything before so imagine this
一切都值得，所以想象一下。
we put one grain of rice on a chessboard
我们在棋盘上放了一粒米。
then two then four then eight eight is
然后是二，然后是四，然后是八，八是
bigger than seven that came before then
比之前的七个都要大
16 which is bigger than 15 that came
16 比 15 大，
before that right and it goes like this
在那之前，事情是这样的。
so every double eclipses everything that
所以，每一个双重奏都会掩盖一切。
came before so in an exponential world
在指数级增长的世界中，它出现得更早。
just those first thousand videos is it
就只有前一千个视频吗？
it you might only get you know 10,000
你可能只能得到10000
followers right it might be small but
粉丝数量可能不多，但
then you get a breakthrough and then in
然后你取得了突破，然后在
that breakthrough you get more than
那次突破你得到的远不止这些
10,000 followers from that breakthrough
那次突破带来了1万名粉丝
but it was all of that that led to that
但正是这一切最终导致了那件事。
it's exactly what happened to me almost
这几乎就是我遇到的情况。
to the number and to me the really
对这个数字来说，对我来说，真的
important part there for me as well is
对我来说，其中重要的部分也是
just to to go for 10 years at anything
仅仅为了在任何领域坚持十年。
you are going to need to really love the
你需要真心热爱……
thing and so as much as we talk
这玩意儿真他妈糟糕，所以我们聊得越多，就越觉得它荒谬。
about strategies and tactics and weight
关于战略、战术和权重
L and all these things the overarching
L 和所有这些统摄一切的事物
thing of how do we get to consistency so
想想我们如何才能保持一致性。
we can start to compound is a
我们可以开始复合了
consequence of love and passion and and
爱情和激情的后果
repetition this is what we're talking
重复，这就是我们正在讨论的内容。
about repetition how many times has a
关于重复，重复了多少次？
Dell song Set Fire to the Rain how many
戴尔的歌曲《Set Fire to the Rain》有多少首
times Ed Sheeran done Castle on the hill
艾德·希兰演唱《山丘上的城堡》的次数
uh how many times have Metallica done
呃，Metallica 做过多少次了
Master of Puppets so like all of the
《傀儡大师》就像所有……
greatest that you um that you admire
最让你钦佩的是你
they all do repetition and it's perfect
他们都在重复练习，这很完美。
reps they do it over and over and over
他们一遍又一遍地重复这个动作。
again no one's talking about this some
还是没人谈论这件事。
of the biggest most successful
最大最成功的
businesses WD40 WD40 was the 40th
企业 WD40 WD40 是第 40 个
attempt to create a spray that would um
尝试制作一种喷雾剂，该喷雾剂会……
do that thing that WD40 does and then
用WD40的那种方法，然后
for the last 50 years they've just been
过去50年来，他们一直都是
selling WD it's their one product and
销售WD是他们唯一的产品。
they just sell it in a small can or a
他们就用小罐子或小瓶子装着卖。
big can um Tobasco Source it's 150y old
大罐装的塔巴斯科辣椒酱，它已经有150年的历史了。
business and they just sell Tobasco but
他们做生意，只卖塔巴斯科辣椒酱，但是
every house in the world has Tabasco
全世界每家每户都有塔巴斯科辣椒酱。
Source Fender Stratocaster guitars they
来源：Fender Stratocaster 吉他
figured it out in 1950s and they have
他们在20世纪50年代就弄明白了，而且他们……
made that same guitar ever since Porsche
自从保时捷以来，我就一直在做同样的吉他。
9911 they've barely changed it but
9911 他们几乎没怎么改，但是
Porsche 911 is the most successful
保时捷911是最成功的车型。
sports car because they just get good at
跑车，因为它们性能优异
doing Porsche 911s um you know I love
做保时捷911，你知道我喜欢
Swiss Army knives Rolex Watchers they
瑞士军刀和劳力士手表
are all businesses where they figure out
这些都是他们会想办法解决的企业
what to to do and then they just fall in
不知道该怎么办，然后他们就倒下了
love with the repetitions they just do
喜欢他们所做的重复。
it and do it and do it and do it and
去做，去做，去做，再去做。
you've done 400 episodes of the show I
你已经制作了400集节目了。
think um you know and the first 100 is
想想，你知道，前100名是
that true uh 421 421 so you've done 421
确实，呃，421 421，所以你已经完成了421
episodes of the show I would almost uh
我几乎会……的几集
guess that the last 21 probably eclipse
我猜最后21次日食可能会发生。
the first 100 um to say the least to say
至少可以说，前100微米。
the least Right In fact when I was on
最不正确的是，事实上，当我在
the show uh last time you just crossed 5
上次你刚过完5岁生日，节目就结束了。
million subscribers I think you're
百万订阅者，我想你是
coming up on 10 million yeah we did um
快到1000万了，是的，我们做到了。
500,000 in December so this is called
12月份达到50万，所以这被称为
doubling speed yeah manal you doubling
速度翻倍，是的，马纳尔，你翻倍了
and doubling and doubling what will blow
并且不断加倍，最终会爆炸
your mind is that you'll go from 10
你的想法是你会从10开始
million to 20 million in the year ahead
未来一年将从数百万增至2000万。
um so it feels because that's
嗯，感觉是因为那是
exponential growth what what if you
指数增长，如果你……会怎样？
continue to do the Reps you will cross
继续做你将要完成的重复次数
10 million and in the same speed that
1000万，而且速度与此相同
you went from 5 to 10 you'll go from 10
你从5升到了10，你将从10升到
to 20 uh you'll have 20 million
到20，呃，你将拥有2000万
subscribers to the channel uh if if you
频道订阅者，呃，如果你
know if you continue to do the rep so
知道你是否继续重复这个动作
when we crank the handle we go through
当我们转动把手时，我们会经过
doubling speeds and you want to figure
速度翻倍，你想弄清楚
out what is the activity that leads to
找出导致以下情况的活动
exponential growth and just do it do it
指数增长，然后去做！
again and fall in love with doing it
再次这样做，并爱上它。
it's really that simple in many well if
很多情况下，事情其实就这么简单。
you're playing the right game it is I
你玩的游戏没错。
analyzed your episodes by the way of
通过以下方式分析了您的剧集：
your last 117 episodes what percentage
最近117集占比多少？
what
什么
offers I'm going to say it's a high
我觉得这很划算。
percentage it's very high 78% okay 91
百分比非常高，78%，好的，91
out of 117 are authors they've all
117 位作者中，他们都……
written books uh what's interesting is
写书……嗯，有趣的是……
the ones who haven't written books are
那些没有写过书的人是
typically like Superstars and like mega
通常喜欢超级巨星和巨型巨星
mega stars in some other thing but
巨星们在其他领域也扮演过类似的角色，但是
almost all of your guests have written
几乎所有宾客都写了
at least one book but 78% of your guests
至少有一本书，但78%的客人
have written a book writing a book is a
写了一本书，写书是一件很有意义的事情。
good idea it is a good idea and it's a
好主意，这确实是个好主意，而且……
good idea for the unobvious reasons that
这是一个好主意，原因不言而喻：
most people don't think it's not
大多数人并不这么认为。
necessarily to sell books cuz you know
不一定是为了卖书，因为你知道
I've got a book that's sold pretty well
我有一本书卖得相当不错。
but I I don't think it's going to I
但我认为不会。
don't necessarily think it's made much
不一定认为它制作精良。
money no it's it's relationships on
金钱？不，是人际关系。
steroids it is the ability to have a
类固醇是一种能够……的能力
relation it's a parasocial relationship
它是一种准社会关系
it's the ability to have a relationship
这是建立关系的能力。
with an anonymous person on the other
另一边是匿名人士
side of the planet where they clock up 7
地球的这一侧，他们在那里记录了7次。
hours with you in your literally what
和你在一起的几个小时，你到底在做什么？
was once inside your head word for word
曾经一字不差地出现在你的脑海里
is now inside their head word for word
现在这些话一字不差地印在了他们的脑子里。
so you actually connect at a very deep
所以你们实际上建立了非常深层次的联系。
level with people at scale so authors
与大众保持平等，以便作者
becoming an author one thing that I
成为一名作家，其中一件事就是……
recommend to all the listeners is have a
建议所有听众都拥有一个
goal to become an author even if you
即使你的目标是成为一名作家，你
haven't done anything yet you well you
你还没做任何事呢，你……
can document your journey you can
你可以记录你的旅程
discover that you are standing on a
发现自己正站在一个
mountain of value a lot of people think
很多人认为它价值连城。
they're not they've not done anything um
他们没有，他们什么都没做。
I have had uh I've had people who' have
我遇到过……我遇到过一些人……
written really successful businesses
写出真正成功的企业
About the Passion that they have and the
关于他们所拥有的热情以及
vision that they have uh sorry really
他们所拥有的愿景，呃，抱歉，真的
successful books about the passion and
关于激情和成功的书籍
vision that they have I have people who
他们所拥有的愿景，我有一些人
like I've got someone who was very
就像我认识的那个人非常
successful at selling as a small
成功地以小规模销售的方式出售
business selling a corporate contract
企业出售公司合同
and they wrote a book about how small
他们还写了一本书，讲述了小
businesses can sell to corporates and
企业可以向公司销售产品，
that was based on maybe eight to 10
那大概是基于八到十个人的数据。
major contracts that they had won but
他们赢得的一些重大合同，但
then they documented the process and now
然后他们记录了这个过程，现在
they have a whole business teaching
他们拥有一整套教学业务
small businesses to sell to corporates
小型企业向大公司销售
so like if you've done one little thing
所以，如果你做了一件小事
that could actually be a massive
那实际上可能是一个巨大的
business bigger than one of our guys
这家公司比我们任何一个员工都大。
Howard Tinker he ran a successful
霍华德·廷克经营着一家成功的公司
restaurant and he had had a successful
他开了一家餐厅，生意很成功。
process for building his restaurant
他餐厅的建造过程
regulars and people who you know locals
常客和你认识的当地人
who come back and back and he actually
那些来来往往的人，他实际上
wrote a book uh it's an Australian term
写了一本书……呃，这是个澳大利亚俚语。
but he says more bums on seats in
但他表示，更多的人会坐在座位上。
America it would have to be more butts
美国的话，恐怕得有更多的屁股才行。
on seats but he wrote the book called
座位上，但他写了一本书，名为
more bums on seats gave it out to a
更多人坐在座位上，这让……
thousand restaurants and said here's how
上千家餐厅，并说方法如下
I built my restaurant and then ended up
我建好了餐厅，然后就……
building a massive coaching and
建立庞大的教练团队和
Consulting business teaching restaurants
咨询业务教学餐厅
how to do their sales and marketing um
他们的销售和市场营销是如何进行的？
so he had one little
所以他有一个小……
restaurant uh and then he turned it into
餐厅，然后他把它变成了
a a big thing um Gabriella who I
一件大事，嗯，加布里埃拉，我
mentioned before she helped some couples
之前提到过，她帮助过一些夫妇。
get pregnant through her fertility
通过她的生育能力怀孕
interventions and then she wrote a book
干预之后，她写了一本书。
called fertility breakthrough and now
被称为生育突破，现在
she gives away 4,000 copies a year and
她每年赠送4000册，
her business is massive on that point of
她在这一点上的生意规模非常庞大。
sales are there any Frameworks for sales
销售方面是否有任何销售框架
that you advise or give to entrepreneurs
你给创业者的建议或帮助
when they're trying to because on stage
当他们试图在舞台上这样做时
a lot of people ask me this they say
很多人都问过我这个问题，他们说
things like this I'm trying to sell to a
像这样的东西，我正试图卖给……
customer or I'm trying to sell to the
顾客，或者我正在尝试向……销售
CEO of this company some idea that I
这家公司的首席执行官有一些想法，我认为
have to change the company or I'm trying
我必须换公司，或者我正在尝试
to sell downwards as a leader yeah is
作为领导者向下抛售是的。
there a framework for selling well you
销售是有框架的。
want to productize your sales and what
想将销售产品化以及什么
you want to do is productize the demo
你想做的就是将演示产品化
and the customer needs analysis and give
以及客户需求分析和提供
it a name so that it feels like a
给它取个名字，让它感觉像个
product and it doesn't feel like a sale
产品，但感觉不像是在打折。
it feels like a product so that you feel
感觉像个产品，让你感觉
that you're getting something of value
你会得到一些有价值的东西。
by seeing the demo and doing the
通过观看演示并进行操作
customer needs analysis that's one of
客户需求分析是其中之一
the first things so break that down for
首先，让我们把这些分解开来。
me so when you say the word demo so the
所以当你提到“演示”这个词的时候，我……
demo is explaining the value of what you
演示是为了解释你所拥有的价值
do so you want to craft a demo uh
这样做是为了制作一个演示……
crafting a demo is like uh you want to
制作演示就像……你想……
be able to do the features advantages
能够做到这些功能优势
benefits the research that backs it up
支持这项研究的成果是有益的。
uh you want to be able to show some data
呃，你想展示一些数据
you want to have an emotional story that
你想讲述一个感人的故事，
tells people how this product works and
告诉人们这款产品是如何工作的
how it changed someone's life or how it
它如何改变了某人的生活，或者它如何
delivered a valuable outcome so all of
取得了有价值的成果，因此所有人都……
that's in the demo and the demo shows
演示中已经包含了这一点，演示也展示了这一点。
how your product is the path of least
你的产品是如何成为最不具竞争力的途径的
resistance between the current reality
当前现实与阻力
the desired reality and the obstacles uh
理想的现实和遇到的障碍
that a ideal customer has so you take an
理想客户所具备的条件，所以你要采取
ideal customer this is where they are
理想客户就在这里
this is where they want to be this is
这就是他们想来的地方，这就是
what's stopping them look at our path of
是什么阻止了他们？看看我们走过的路。
least resistance that we've created but
这是我们所能创造的阻力最小的局面，但
it's not for everybody you have to do a
这并不适合所有人，你必须去做。
customer needs analysis so a survey or
客户需求分析，例如调查或
an assessment and then that tells you
评估之后，它会告诉你答案。
whether you need this product or not so
无论你是否需要这款产品
you want to producti that you want to
你想生产你想要的东西
give it a name and you want to give it a
给它起个名字，你想给它一个
like a landing page and people can sign
就像一个登录页面，人们可以在上面注册。
up to it um so they can experience the
取决于此，这样他们就能体验到……
presentation and and do the customer
向客户进行演示和沟通
needs analysis I've got a picture here
需求分析 我这里有一张图片
called uh the messy middle yeah the
叫做混乱的中间地带，是的。
Google Google report I've actually never
谷歌报告说我实际上从未
seen this before this image yeah um can
之前看过这张图，嗯，可以
you explain to me I'll put it on the
你给我解释一下，我就把它放上去。
screen and Link it below for anyone that
截图并把链接放在下面，方便任何人查看。
wants to look at it I highly recommend
想看看的话，我强烈推荐
you do what this image is yeah so we
你做的就是这张图片所表达的意思，是的，所以我们
used to think of marketing as marketing
过去人们认为营销就是营销
funnels and marketing funnels
销售漏斗和营销漏斗
essentially we would push people through
基本上我们会推动人们通过
a marketing process from awareness to uh
从认知到营销的整个过程
consideration through to trust and
通过考虑建立信任和
commitment and purchase so it was this
承诺和购买就是这样。
marketing funnel and we're just kind of
营销漏斗，我们现在就有点像……
funneling them through
将它们引导通过
um and that's how we you know almost all
嗯，这就是我们几乎了解所有事情的方式。
marketers draw funnels yeah um and then
营销人员会绘制销售漏斗图，嗯，然后
Google did some research to see is this
谷歌做了一些调查，看看是否如此。
actually true is this still how people
这真的是事实吗？人们现在还是这样吗？
buy and they found it's actually not how
买回来之后，他们发现实际情况并非如此。
people buy at all anymore um so um top
现在人们都不买了，嗯，所以，嗯，顶部
of funnel middle of funnel and bottom of
漏斗的中部和底部
funnel has been replaced by a trigger a
漏斗已被触发器取代
totally random journey through a
一段完全随机的旅程
playground uh where we explore and
游乐场，呃，我们可以在那里探索和
evaluate randomly and then a trigger for
随机评估，然后触发
signaling intent and then
发出意图信号，然后
uh purchase over here so what this might
呃，在这里购买，所以这可能
look like is I might see an influencer
看起来我可能会见到一位网红
uh talking about her you know handbag
呃，说到她的手提包，你知道的。
and I go oh I'm interested in that brand
然后我就想，哦，我对那个品牌很感兴趣。
I'll give them a follow yeah and then I
我会关注他们，然后我
ignore them um and then I discover that
别理他们，嗯，然后我发现……
they've actually put some videos on
他们实际上已经上传了一些视频。
YouTube and I start watching a video on
我在YouTube上开始看视频。
YouTube but then I go and do something
YouTube，但之后我又去做别的事了。
else and then I see a review website and
否则，然后我看到一个点评网站……
um I go on the review website then I
嗯，我先去评论网站看看，然后……
find out that that brand has actually
发现该品牌实际上
created a waiting list for a new product
为新产品创建了等候名单
so I actually say oh I might drive drive
所以我其实会说，哦，我可能会开车。
the waiting list now I'm like ending up
现在候补名单上我感觉快要结束了
down here and then um I get on the
下来之后，嗯，我就上去
waiting list they tell me that uh
他们告诉我，等候名单上……
they're only releasing 500 of that
他们只发行了500个。
product would I like one yes I would so
我想要这个产品吗？是的，我想要。
then I uh basically go and purchase so
然后我就去买了。
it's no longer a funnel experience
这不再是一种漏斗式的体验
because customers have figured out that
因为顾客已经意识到这一点
they can disappear within 3 seconds if
如果
they want to right they can just jump
他们想做对，他们可以直接跳下去。
your fence and and the funnel feels
你的栅栏和漏斗感觉
dehumanizing for most people so they
对大多数人来说，这是非人道的，所以他们
don't like to be funneled they like to
他们不喜欢被引导，他们喜欢
go on an adventure so rather than
去冒险，而不是
thinking about our marketing as a funnel
将我们的营销视为一个漏斗
we want to think about it as an
我们想把它看作是一个
adventure or a playground so we're going
去冒险或者去游乐场，所以我们要去
to create things that people can
创造人们可以……的东西
interact with and play with um so they
与它们互动和玩耍，所以它们
could watch a uh watch a video they
他们可以看一段视频
could listen to a podcast they could
他们可以听播客
take an online assessment uh they could
参加在线评估，他们可以
um complete a customer needs analysis
完成客户需求分析
they could watch a demo they could uh
他们可以观看演示，他们可以……
get free access to a trial in a portal
通过门户网站免费试用
um they could join a community they
嗯，他们可以加入一个社区。
could join a discussion group right so
现在可以加入讨论组了
these are all things that people can
这些都是人们可以做的事情。
engage with or play with and we want it
参与其中或与之玩耍，我们想要它
to avoid feeling like a funnel we want
为了避免感觉自己像个漏斗，我们想要
to feel like it's um lots of value lots
感觉它很有价值。
of great experiences and then at the
美好的经历，然后是
certain time there are moments to act if
有时，会有行动的契机。
you want to buy something if you're in a
如果你想买东西，如果你身处……
if you're the right person at the right
如果你是合适的人选，那么你就是在合适的时间。
time this is the moment to act so it's a
现在正是行动的时刻，所以这是一个
bit of a different way of thinking about
换个角度思考这个问题
marketing but it acknowledges the fact
营销，但它也承认这一点
that we're living in a very different
我们生活在一个截然不同的世界
world where you know funnels worked when
在那个世界里，你知道销售漏斗在何时发挥作用。
people were afraid of not seeing you
人们害怕见不到你
ever again or that they're afraid they
再也不会，或者他们害怕他们
would miss out but no one's afraid of
会错过机会，但没人害怕。
that
那
anymore the people that came to you
再也没有人来找你了
following your our last conversation and
继我们上次谈话之后
that me sent you messages and DMS what
我给你发了什么消息和私信？
is the most frequently occurring
是最常见的
question that they asked
他们提出的问题
you how do I start when I don't have a
我该如何开始，当我没有任何……
brand um like a lot of people say I've
就像很多人说的那样，我……
got a big idea or I want to launch but I
我有个好点子，或者想启动项目，但是
don't have a brand yet I I'm I'm
我还没有品牌。
invisible um you know I feel invisible
隐形的，你知道吗，我觉得自己隐形了
and that makes me feel stuck uh and
这让我感觉很无助。
essentially
本质上
they know what they're excited about
他们知道自己兴奋的是什么
they know what they're passionate about
他们知道自己热爱什么。
um I've got a big I've got a big new
嗯，我有一个很大的……我有一个很大的新……
product idea I've got a way of expanding
我的产品创意有扩展的方法
into a new territory but I don't have
进入一个全新的领域，但我没有
the brand and is that where your 5ps
品牌，以及你的5P在哪里？
come in for becoming a key person of
成为关键人物
influence so the yeah so the 5ps is uh
影响，所以，是的，所以5P是……
we have to learn to pitch right the
我们必须学会如何正确地投球
entrepreneur journey is a journey of a
创业之旅是一段……的旅程
thousand pitchers uh one way or another
一千个投手，嗯，不管怎样
you're either going to pitch an average
你要么会投出平均水平的球。
pitch and end up with nothing or you
推销失败，最终一无所获，或者你
pitch a phenomenal pitch and end up with
提出了一个精彩绝伦的方案，最终……
a 10 to100 million business um if you're
一家年营业额在1000万到1亿美元之间的企业，嗯，如果你是
Elon Musk you'll end up pitching your
埃隆·马斯克，你最终会推销你的
way to Mars right but journey is the
通往火星的道路是正确的，但旅程本身就是……
entrepreneur journey is all about
创业之旅的全部意义就在于此
pitching so we've got to have a a great
投球方面，我们必须要有出色的表现。
way of pitching the business so people
向人们推销业务的方式
are excited in person or digitally could
无论是亲身参与还是线上参与，都可能感到兴奋。
be video right I've seen Mark zukerberg
视频没错，我见过马克·扎克伯格
do hundreds of pictures uh over the last
过去一段时间拍了数百张照片
20 years for Facebook and new features
Facebook 成立 20 周年及其新功能
um uh Steve Jobs used to do it on stage
嗯，史蒂夫·乔布斯过去常常在舞台上这样做。
um but then the video went out so you
嗯，但是后来视频就发出去了，所以你
can do it to video you can do it to
你可以把它拍成视频，你可以把它拍成视频。
camera you can do it on a podcast you
你可以在播客节目中用摄像头做到这一点。
can Do It um uh live you can do it Ono
可以做到，嗯，现场你可以做到，小野
one you can do it to groups but you have
你可以对群体这样做，但是你有
to learn how to be able to pitch an idea
学习如何推销自己的想法
get people excited about something
让人们对某事感到兴奋
through your words entrepreneurs and
通过你的话语，企业家们和
Founders they are the spokesperson for
创始人是他们的发言人
their business they have to be able to
他们的业务他们必须能够
be good at pitching the second thing is
第二件事是擅长投球。
publishing content publishing videos
发布内容、发布视频
publishing podcasts publishing a book
发布播客 出版书籍
publishing on LinkedIn right so it's
在LinkedIn上发布，对吧？
essentially taking the elements of a
本质上是取以下要素
pitch but putting into different formats
提案，但要以不同的形式呈现
7114 stuff mhm the third element is the
7114 东西 嗯，第三个要素是
product ization the product ecosystem
产品化 产品生态系统
too many people sell time and skills
太多人兜售时间和技能
they have to sell intellectual property
他们必须出售知识产权
media data software or producti services
媒体数据软件或产品服务
or they have to have a scalable product
或者他们必须拥有可扩展的产品。
something that doesn't require their
不需要他们的东西
time and effort in order to sell it
花费时间和精力去卖掉它
again and again um because your time and
一遍又一遍，嗯，因为你的时间和
effort as a Founder has to be on the
作为创始人，必须付出努力。
demand side not the supply side so we
是需求方而非供给方，所以我们
got to producti uh raising profile uh is
进入生产阶段，呃，提高知名度，呃，是
the next one so having your social media
接下来，你需要拥有你的社交媒体账号。
platforms doing some Live Events um
一些平台正在进行直播活动
winning some awards
获得一些奖项
uh getting on traditional Media or third
呃，上传统媒体还是第三条？
party platforms all of that is your
政党纲领，这一切都是你的。
profile and then the next one once
个人资料，然后下一个。
you've done all of that is doing your
你已经完成了所有这些，这就是你的
first joint ventures and Partnerships so
首先是合资企业和合作伙伴关系
big business happens when you can find
大生意发生在你能找到……的时候。
the right Partners uh so you might need
合适的合作伙伴，所以你可能需要
a Capital Partner for investment or you
投资的资本合作伙伴，或者您
might need a distribution partner for
可能需要分销合作伙伴
sales you might need a um a a a product
销售人员可能需要一个产品
partner someone who actually Partners to
与真正愿意合作的人结伴
in incorporate something that they do
融入他们所做的事情
into your product so packaging up
将产品包装起来
through
通过
Partnerships um so I always Focus people
合作关系，嗯，所以我总是把重点放在人身上。
on pitching publishing product profile
关于推介出版产品简介
Partnerships that's the role of the
伙伴关系，这就是它的作用
founder we call that the key person of
创始人，我们称之为关键人物
influence role um personal brand feels
影响角色，嗯，个人品牌感觉
like this weird thing or it feels like
就像这种奇怪的事情，或者感觉像是
branding or it feels like this kind of
品牌塑造，或者感觉像是这种
like um oh I've got to you know get up
嗯，哦，我得起来了
every day and photograph my breakfast
每天都拍我的早餐照片
and you know all that sort of stuff but
你知道所有这些事情，但是
actually if we just focus on Pitch
实际上，如果我们只关注音调的话。
published product profile partnership
发布产品简介合作关系
most people who are sensible people with
大多数明智的人
successful businesses they say oh that
他们说，成功的企业，哦，那
makes sense I like all of those things
有道理，我喜欢所有这些东西。
yeah personal branding has got a bit of
是的，个人品牌塑造确实有点……
a wrap isn't it bit of a um a bit of a
包装纸，不是吗？有点……嗯……有点……
stigma the goal is not to be an
消除污名，目标不是成为一个
influencer to be a key person of
有影响力的人将成为关键人物
influence and there's a difference and I
影响，而且两者之间存在差异，我
think um there's different types of
想想看，嗯，有不同类型的
personal branding and the best most
个人品牌塑造和最佳方案
effective type of personal branding that
有效的个人品牌塑造方式
I've seen is what I call idea promotion
我所看到的，就是我所谓的理念推广。
where you're promoting your ideas to the
你在那里向……推广你的想法
world um maybe in a particular nure
世界嗯，也许在某个特定的nure
industry but it's all about here are my
行业，但这一切都与我的有关。
ideas and you can do that as well
想法，你也可以这样做。
obviously through books and through
显然是通过书籍和通过
podcast appearances and stuff but there
参加播客节目之类的，但是……
are other types of promotions so some
还有其他类型的促销活动，所以有些
people do
人们确实
deficiency promotion here are all the
这里提到的不足之处都是……
ways that I'm flawed and they build a
我身上存在的缺陷，以及他们构建的
brand around that well the the one
围绕着那个品牌，嗯，就是那个。
people most object to is self-promotion
人们最反感的是自我推销
self-promotion which is here's how great
自我推销，这就是它的妙处所在。
I am look at me this is my lifestyle
看看我，这就是我的生活方式
this is my car this is my abs yeah um
这是我的车，这是我的腹肌，嗯。
here's my dinner here's my girlfriend my
这是我的晚餐，这是我的女朋友，我的
boyfriend right so all of that sort of
男朋友对，所以诸如此类的事情
stuff is self-promotion that's
这都是自我推销。
narcissistic and that's that's
自恋，就是这样。
associated more with an influencer a key
与有影响力的人联系更紧密
person of influence is operating within
有影响力的人正在运作
a high value Niche and they're idea
一个高价值的细分市场，他们的想法
promoting they're saying here's the big
他们宣传时说，这就是大事。
insights that you need here's the data
你需要的信息就在这里，数据如下
that you should pay attention to here's
你应该注意以下几点：
the problem as I see it and here's some
在我看来，问题在于以下几点：
nuances around the problem here's the
这里的问题还有一些细微差别：
solution or outcome that's achievable
可实现的解决方案或结果
and here's how you get to that outcome
以下是如何达到该结果的方法
so they're they're basically it's part
所以它们基本上是其中的一部分
thought leader but also part
思想领袖，但也是其中一员
entrepreneur um you don't need a huge
创业者，嗯，你不需要一大笔钱。
following for this influencers
关注这位网红
notoriously can't sell stuff they many
众所周知，他们很多东西都卖不出去。
influencers have a million followers and
网红拥有百万粉丝，
it turns out they can't sell hoodies uh
结果发现他们不能卖连帽衫。
you know very very difficult to get
你知道，这非常非常难得。
anything sold people look at them as as
人们看待任何出售的物品都像看待……
entertainers but they don't really look
他们是艺人，但他们看起来并不像。
at them as thought leaders or you know
把他们看作思想领袖，或者你知道
someone who's directing serious spend a
有人在指导一项严肃的支出
key person of influence might have 5,000
关键人物可能拥有5000
or 10,000 followers but when they say
或者1万粉丝，但当他们说
this is the thing to buy everyone buys
这是人人都想买的东西。
it um you know so that's what we're
嗯，你知道，这就是我们……
we're going for that and can anyone do
我们打算这么做，有人能做到吗？
that anyone can start I mean I've I've
任何人都可以开始，我的意思是，我已经……我已经
been working on this for 15 years with 5
已经为此努力了15年，有5
and a half thousand companies we've got
我们有五百五千家公司
single moms with children who have
单身母亲带着孩子
special needs who have gone from
有特殊需要的人
struggling to multi-million businesses
苦苦挣扎的数百万美元企业
we've got um people who had been stuck
我们有一些人一直被困住了
at five people for 10 years and then
五个人，持续十年，然后
they go to 50 people um you know we've
他们去了50个人，嗯，你知道，我们有
got people in 50 different industries
接触过 50 个不同行业的人
from Real Estate to Dentistry to
从房地产到牙科
medicine to IT services so like the
从医疗到IT服务，就像……
world the world is open at the moment
世界目前是开放的
every single industry has a thousand
每个行业都有成千上万个这样的公司。
different micro niches every Micro Niche
每个微利基市场都不同
needs a key person of influence or two
需要一到两位关键人物。
every Micron Niche can have a book um
每个美光小众领域都可以有一本书。
when we were stuck in
当我们被困在
geography there was no point to doing
地理课毫无意义。
all of this cuz you only had a 5 mile
这一切都是因为你只有5英里的路程
radius or 10 m radius anyway but now we
半径，或者说半径10米，反正现在我们
can reach 1.5 billion English speakers
可覆盖15亿英语使用者
online we can reach 70% of the world on
通过网络，我们可以覆盖全球70%的人口。
fast internet your tiny little Micro
高速互联网，你的小小Micro
Niche could be extremely valuable to 35
利基市场对35岁的人来说可能极其有价值
people on the planet who each happily
地球上每个人都很快乐
pay 100,000 a year you know so we live
你知道，每年交10万，我们才能生活。
in this world where the microniches are
在这个微生态位的世界里
incredibly valuable every industry has a
每个行业都拥有极其宝贵的资源。
thousand micronas every Micron needs an
每千个微米，每个微米都需要一个
a key person of influence or two um
一两个关键人物
there's absolutely no reason why and
完全没有任何理由这样做。
this is where the econom is headed so
这就是经济的发展方向。
there's no reason why a lot of people
没有理由解释为什么很多人
can't do this can everyone do it I don't
我做不到，大家都能做到吗？我做不到。
know if everyone can do it but a lot of
我知道并非每个人都能做到，但很多人
people can definitely do it so what do
人们当然可以做到，那该怎么办？
you think is maybe the subject or
你认为这可能是主题或
question that I haven't asked at this
我还没问过这个问题
point in the conversation that people
对话中人们的观点
will be sad at home thinking there's one
独自在家会感到难过。
last thing that I think we should talk
最后，我想我们应该谈谈这件事。
about if someone's feeling frustrated
关于某人是否感到沮丧
stuck or overwhelmed there's the one
陷入困境或不知所措，那就是那一个
thing that knocks out everything else
能把其他一切都消灭掉的东西
for cutting through problems or cutting
用于解决问题或切割
through things that get in the way and
克服阻碍和
that is this idea called uh environment
这就是所谓的环境概念。
dictates performance environment
决定性能环境
dictates performance what that basically
决定性能的，基本上就是这样
means is that we behave according to the
这意味着我们的行为符合……
environments that we show up in so if
我们所处的环境，所以如果
you are in an environment where nobody's
你身处一个没有人的环境中
doing this stuff it's going to feel
做这些事会感觉很……
impossible if you're in an environment
如果你身处某种环境，这是不可能的。
where everybody's doing this stuff it's
大家都在做这些事的地方就是
going to feel
感觉
effortless if you're an environment
如果你身处一个环境，那就毫不费力了。
where everyone talks about money is evil
人人都谈论金钱是邪恶的
you're never going to make any money if
如果你这样做，你永远也赚不到钱。
you're in an environment where everyone
你身处一个每个人都身处其中的环境中。
sees money is just a tool right you're
你明白金钱只是一种工具，对吧？
going to make a ton of money many years
未来很多年都会赚很多钱
ago when I was in my early
很久以前，当我还是个年轻人的时候
20s uh someone suggested that I go to
20多岁的时候，有人建议我去……
dancing classes and I thought this is
舞蹈课，我当时想这
ridiculous why like I can't dance and
太荒谬了，我又不会跳舞。
I'll never be able to dance and dancing
我永远也无法跳舞和跳舞
is weird I went to a dance class and in
很奇怪，我去上了舞蹈课，然后……
that environment it was normal to learn
在那种环境下学习是很正常的
dancing and within three lessons I was
跳舞，上了三节课后我就
dancing really well I enjoyed it I did
跳得真好，我很喜欢。
three years of dance classes I got
我上了三年的舞蹈课
really good at it and it was one of my
我真的非常擅长这个，而且这是我的其中一项技能。
favorite places to show up but nothing
最喜欢去的地方，但什么也没有
would have happened unless I made the
除非我采取行动，否则事情就不会发生。
commitment to get into a different
致力于进入一个不同的领域
environment so the final thing to talk
环境，所以最后要谈的就是这个。
about is that if any of this feels
重点是，如果这一切让你感觉……
really hard or really like difficult for
真的很难或者真的很难
me I feel effortless because I'm
我感觉毫不费力，因为我
surrounded by people who live this way
身边都是这样生活的人
every single one of my friends is
我的每个朋友都是
scaling a business and a personal brand
拓展业务和个人品牌
um but if you're not in that environment
嗯，但如果你不在那种环境下的话。
it's going to feel really weird and
感觉会非常奇怪，
foreign so the easiest thing people
外国人，所以最简单的事情是人们
could try just simply try the idea of
可以尝试一下这个想法
changing environments immediately by
立即改变环境
doing a few following things if you feel
如果你觉得……可以做以下几件事。
stuck find the highest place that you
被困住了，找到最高的地方。
can get to GE like physically the
可以像在实体中一样到达通用电气
highest go to the top floor restaurant
最高处去顶楼餐厅
in your town go to a um a place that is
在你所在的城镇，去一个……地方
like an office that has a foyer that
就像一个带有门厅的办公室
overlooks the whole city um do whatever
俯瞰整个城市，嗯，随便做什么
you can to go high up and then see how
你可以爬到高处，然后看看情况如何
the problem feels when you're actually
当你真正……的时候，就会感受到这个问题。
high up looking out to the Horizon just
从高处眺望地平线
that change of environment will give you
环境的变化会给你带来什么
new ideas um go and talk to someone who
新想法，嗯，去找个什么人聊聊？
you haven't talked to in a while who's 2
你很久没跟2岁的人说话了
three four steps ahead of you but meet
比你领先三四步，但会遇到
them in an opulent hotel right anyone
他们住在一家豪华酒店里，对吧？
can go sit in a hotel foyer of a fstar
可以去一家五星级酒店的大堂坐坐。
hotel go and meet for coffee in a
去酒店，约在咖啡馆见面。
five-star hotel fo you with someone
五星级酒店，供您和某人入住。
who's three or four steps ahead of you
谁比你领先三四步？
suddenly you're going to feel very very
突然间你会感觉非常非常
different enroll yourself onto a course
报名参加不同的课程
where everyone's learning the same thing
每个人都在学习同样的东西
that you're learning and that
你正在学习，而且
environment means that it's normal like
环境意味着它是正常的，就像
let's say you're afraid of public
假设你害怕公开场合
speaking enroll yourself in a public
参加公共演讲活动
speaking course everyone's going through
每个人都要上的口语课
the process of public speaking suddenly
公开演讲的过程突然
it feels like pretty normal enroll into
感觉就像很正常地报名一样
an entrepreneur accelerator Everyone's
创业加速器 人人皆可
an entrepreneur in there suddenly it
突然，那里出现了一位企业家
feels very normal to be scaling a
感觉扩展规模非常正常
business so environment dictates
商业环境决定了
performance is the big thing that
表现才是最重要的。
changes everything pay attention to
一切都会改变，请注意
environment what I'd love people to do
环境，我希望人们做什么
that are listening now um on YouTube or
现在正在 YouTube 上收听的听众
wherever you might be listening I think
无论你在哪里收听，我认为
YouTube is probably the best place to do
YouTube 可能是最好的平台
it is if you are one of those people
如果你是那种人，那就对了。
that feels a little bit lost and you are
感觉有点迷茫，而你
I don't know you are working in a
我不知道你是否在一家公司工作。
restaurant at the moment and you're
你现在在餐厅，
working evenings and you heard Daniel
丹尼尔晚上也在工作，你听到了他的消息。
talk about Ai and all of these things
谈谈人工智能以及所有这些事情
and you just feel like it might be a bit
你感觉这可能有点……
far away or you don't have the people
要么太远，要么人手不够。
around you that can um potentially help
你周围可能有人会提供帮助
you with that let's start a little bit
既然如此，那我们就先从这开始吧。
of a community in the comment section so
评论区里有很多社区成员，所以
I think it would be really really cool
我觉得那会非常非常酷
if people detailed their situation
如果人们详细描述了自己的情况
talked about where they want to get and
他们谈到了他们想去哪里，以及
if you just throw that out there in the
如果你把那句话直接说出来的话
comment section who you are where you
评论区 你是谁 你在哪里
are obviously keep your private details
显然，我们会保护您的隐私信息。
to yourself but um as Anonymous as
对自己来说，嗯，匿名来说
you're comfortable being or not being
你觉得做或不做某事都自在
throw the seed out there and you it will
把种子撒出去，它就会
start conversation with somebody else I
我开始和别人聊天
see it all the time in the comment
在评论里经常看到这种情况。
section people start chatting they start
部分人群开始聊天，他们开始
getting motivated and jump on a zoom
鼓起勇气，加入Zoom会议
call with that person yeah right or a a
跟那个人打电话，对吧，或者一个
Microsoft uh meeting right or Google
微软呃会议对吧，或者谷歌
meeting right see if you can just
见面的时候看看能不能就这么办
randomly meet up with someone who's
随机遇到一个……
aligned on values because they watch the
因为他们关注价值观，所以价值观一致。
same video yeah right anyone who's going
同样的视频，是啊，谁要去？
to comment this is watched all the way
评论区全程都在关注此事
to the end yeah exactly right so have a
到最后，没错，就是这样。
little video call with them like jump on
和他们进行简短的视频通话，比如跳上去
a zoom call and just say hey let's
开个Zoom会议，然后说“嘿，我们开始吧”。
discuss the episode what are you up to
讨论一下这集节目，你最近在忙些什么？
what are you doing what are you taking
你在做什么？你在服用什么药物？
away from that that's a that's a change
远离那种状态，那是一种改变。
of environment you're you're putting
你正在营造的环境
yourself around a new person and just so
在陌生人面前展现真实的自己，就是这样
you know who these people are that also
你知道这些人是谁。
got to the end of this and that are
已经到了这个和那个的结尾
doing this if you could all start it
如果你们都能开始就这么做吧
with a waving Emoji then at least you
如果配上挥手表情符号，那至少你
know that you're people that got to the
要知道，你们是那些到达……的人
end and saw this part and um if you
最后看到了这一部分，嗯，如果你
could be friendly to those people and
可能会对那些人友好，
maybe um reach out to them talk to them
或许可以联系他们，跟他们聊聊。
and safely right do your own process of
安全地按照你自己的流程进行操作
verification to figure make sure that
验证以确保数据准确
they're not uh crypto scammer or
他们不是加密货币骗子，也不是
something safely maybe connect with them
或许可以安全地与他们联系。
on LinkedIn verify who they are and then
在领英上核实他们的身份，然后
form that relationship because there are
建立这种关系是因为存在
people in this audience that I know are
我认识的在场观众中有
searching for like-minded individuals
寻找志同道合的人
and as you say by the very nature that
正如你所说，就其本质而言……
they got to the end of a three-hour
他们完成了三个小时的训练。
conversation they are like-minded in
他们在谈话中志同道合
some way super aligned you might
某种程度上，你可能非常契合。
discover you've got more in common with
发现你和……有更多共同点
someone on the other side of the planet
地球另一端的某个人
than someone who's just down the road
比住在附近的人要好得多
this year 55% of businesses globally are
今年全球有55%的企业
utilizing AI in some form it's become so
利用人工智能的某种形式，它已经变得如此
integrated across every point of my
融入我的每一点
businesses that it's hard to remember a
很难记住的企业
time when my team and I weren't using it
我和我的团队没有使用它的那段时间
Adobe Express who sponsored this podcast
赞助本播客的 Adob​​e Express
is a prime example of a tool our team
是我们团队工具的一个典型例子
uses day in and day out its generate
它日复一日地产生
image tool only needs a few words
图片工具只需要几个字
describing what you want and using AI it
描述你的需求并使用人工智能
returns many images for you to choose
返回许多图片供您选择
from if you're watching see how quick
如果你正在观看，就会发现它有多快
and easy it is and you can try it
这很简单，你可以试试。
yourself for free the customizable
免费定制你自己
templates mean you or anyone in your
模板指的是你或你的任何人
team can create something that stands
团队可以创造出经得起考验的东西。
out without starting entirely from
无需完全从头开始
scratch or being a design expert it's
无论是从零开始，还是成为设计专家，都是如此。
the type of technology that
这种技术类型
differentiates Adobe Express from being
Adobe Express 与以下情况有所区别：
just another design tool and makes it
这只是另一个设计工具而已，而且它
the quick and easy easy create anything
快速简便地创建任何东西
app search Adobe Express or download it
在应用搜索 Adob​​e Express 或下载它
for free in the app store right
就在应用商店里免费下载
now in terms of energy there are so many
现在就能源而言，有太多了。
reasons why I'm a big matcha fan if you
如果你知道我为什么如此热爱抹茶，以下是我的理由。
don't already know by now and so much so
到现在还不知道，而且知道得如此之多
that I actually invested in the UK's
事实上，我投资了英国的
leading matcha company called perfect
一家名为 Perfect 的领先抹茶公司
Ted and one of my favorite perfect head
泰德和我最喜欢的完美头像之一
products is these delicious matcha
这些产品是美味的抹茶
pouches that come in every flavor from
各种口味的袋装食品
salted caramel to Peach flavor to mint
咸焦糖味、桃子味、薄荷味
flavor to Berry flavor one of my
浆果口味是我的其中之一
favorites is this vanilla flavor which
我最喜欢的是香草口味。
I'm going to make in just two seconds
我只需两秒钟就能做到。
you just take this mixer here get a
你只要拿着这个搅拌机……
little bit of the powder pop it on top
撒上一点点粉末。
of the shaker like that put the lid
像这样把摇酒器盖子盖上。
on shake shake
摇晃
shake delicious if you haven't tried
如果你还没试过，这款奶昔味道很棒。
this yet you can find perfect Ted at
尽管如此，你仍然可以在Ted找到完美的
Tesco and Holland Barrett stores or
Tesco 和 Holland Barrett 商店或
online where you can get 40% off with my
在线使用我的账号可以享受40%的折扣。
code diary 40 head to perfect ted.com
代码日记 40 前往 perfect ted.com
and put in code diary 40 to try this
并在代码日志 40 中输入以尝试此操作
delicious multiflor match now highly
美味的多花搭配现在非常
recommend and if you do it please tag me
推荐一下，如果你做了请标记我
send me a message
给我发条消息
online we have a closing tradition on
在线上，我们有一个结束的传统……
this podcast where the last guest leaves
在这个播客节目中，最后一位嘉宾离开了。
a question for the next without knowing
一个留给下一个人的问题，却不知其所以然。
who they're leaving it for where do you
他们要把它留给谁？你呢？
draw the line between health or
在健康与健康之间划清界限
anything optimization and pleasure I
任何优化和乐趣
think optimization can lead to pleasure
认为优化可以带来愉悦
um one of the things that happened to me
嗯，发生在我身上的一件事
uh personally is Christmas Eve uh just a
呃，就我个人而言，平安夜呃，只是一个
few week weeks ago I got a phone call
几周前我接到一个电话
from a GP who I'd never spoken to before
来自一位我之前从未交谈过的家庭医生
in my life who had looked at my health
在我生命中，谁曾关注过我的健康？
results from my blood test and said um
我的验血结果出来了，然后他说……
Daniel I need to call you before
丹尼尔，我需要在……之前给你打个电话。
something bad happens and I went what
发生了不好的事，然后我就想：什么？
are you talking about he said well your
你在说他说的那个吗？嗯，你的
pancreas has an enzyme that's associated
胰腺有一种与之相关的酶。
with bad things has anyone commented
对于不好的事情，有人发表过评论吗？
that you're turning yellow I went no uh
你脸色发黄了，我回答说不，呃。
he said uh have you um lost
他说，呃，你迷路了吗？
Consciousness or been dizzy no have you
你是否意识清醒或感到头晕？没有。
uh you know have you had to like all
呃，你知道，你是不是不得不像所有那样？
over if you had to have a sleep all
如果你必须睡一觉的话，那就结束了。
afternoon something like this I'm like
下午类似这样的事情，我就像
no none of that he said okay you're
他说，不，没有那些。好吧，你是。
you're really close to having a health
你离健康真的非常接近了。
problem the reason I'm calling you
这就是我打电话给你的原因。
Christmas Eve is because Christmas Day
平安夜是因为圣诞节
if you drink alcohol if you eat too much
如果你喝酒，或者吃得太多
food you could end up in an ambulance
吃这种食物可能会导致你最终住进救护车。
with these levels that you're in I'm
以你目前的水平，我是
like this is so weird I've never known
这太奇怪了，我以前从来没遇到过。
this I just had a blood test to sort of
我刚刚做了个血液检查，大概是为了……
see my markers and I got this
看看我的标记，我得到了这个
result and for about a week I didn't
结果，大约一周后我都没能得到结果。
know whether I had some serious disease
想知道我是否患有某种严重的疾病
I didn't know any of this I went and got
我之前对这些一无所知，我是自己去拿的。
a CT scan suddenly find out that uh my
CT扫描突然发现，呃，我的
doctor said pristine I have a pristine
医生说我皮肤完美无瑕。
pancreas in gallbladder and and liver
胰腺、胆囊和肝脏
and I had these elevated levels um but
我的这些指标都偏高，嗯，但是
it was associated with some other things
它与其他一些事物有关。
it was associated with some changes to
它与一些变化有关
diet sleep exercise all of this but it
饮食、睡眠、运动等等，但是……
was like a a reprieve it was like a stay
就像一次喘息的机会，就像一段停留。
of execution it was it was a wonderful
执行得非常精彩
experience to go oh wow okay it's not
体验之后会觉得“哦，哇，好吧”，这不是真的。
serious it's reversible that data has
严重的是，数据是可逆的。
changed my life just that week it was
那一周彻底改变了我的生活。
the greatest gift I could have got for
我能收到的最好的礼物
Christmas because for a week I felt like
圣诞节，因为我感觉自己整整一周都像
what it must feel like to lose your
失去你的感觉一定很不好
health and to be told that your health
健康，以及被告知你的健康
is in serious decline I had the I had
情况严重恶化，我曾经有过
the real experience of what it would
真实的体验会是什么样的
feel like to to receive bad information
感觉像是在接收错误信息
but then at the end of the week and I
但到了周末，我
got the CT scan I had the real
我做了CT扫描，我做了真正的
experience of like uh you know the Ghost
就像你知道的，鬼魂的经历
of Christmas right I it's okay Dan you
圣诞节对吧？没关系，丹，你
it's not too late so suddenly I'm
现在还不算太晚，所以我突然……
optimizing I've got my whooop band and
优化一下，我已经有了我的 Whooop 手环，
and I'm I'm getting a lot of pleasure
我从中获得了许多乐趣
like having the data is great data is a
拥有数据固然很好，数据本身也是一种优势。
great thing there's nothing that frees
幸好没有什么能解放它。
you more than having visibility of the
你比拥有更高的可见性更重要
data what was that Epiphany that you got
数据是什么？你得到的顿悟是什么？
in that week like what is the for us
那一周对我们来说意味着什么？
that you know for people that don't want
你知道，对于那些不想……的人来说
to have to go through that to realize
必须经历这一切才能意识到
what you realized in that week it's an
你在那一周意识到的是……
age-old epiphany but a healthy man has
古老的顿悟，但一个健康的男人却有
many goals a sick man has only
病人有很多目标
one right so when you think you've got
没错，所以当你认为你已经……
your health you've got all of the
你的健康，你拥有一切
possibilities ahead of you when you
当你……时，你将面临各种可能性。
think you've lost your health you're
你觉得自己失去了健康吗？
only focused on getting that back again
只专注于重新夺回它。
um and You Don't Know What You've Got
嗯，还有《你不知道你拥有什么》
Till It's Gone you don't like you don't
直到它消失，你不喜欢你不喜欢
know what until you hit that crisis
直到遭遇危机，你才会明白。
point you just take it all for granted
你只是把这一切都视为理所当然。
um it was just one of those magical
嗯，那只是那种神奇的经历之一。
moments of going oh my goodness I have
有时会想，哦，我的天哪，我……
this incredible body that's functioning
这具运转良好的身体真是不可思议
like I need to take care of this this is
就像我需要处理这件事一样。
my vehicle um so it was you know the
我的车，嗯，你知道的。
Epiphany was just I'm so focused on
顿悟就是我如此专注于
business and life and opportunities and
商业、生活、机遇和
all this external stuff but actually
所有这些外部因素，但实际上
there's great joy and great pleasure in
其中蕴含着巨大的喜悦和极大的快乐。
taking care of yourself I think that's
我觉得照顾好自己才是最重要的。
so wonderful to hear and so refreshing
听到这个消息真是太好了，令人耳目一新。
um because it's the often the missing
嗯，因为通常是缺失的部分。
piece in the big picture of like success
在类似成功的大局中扮演重要角色
and optimization is this um I I had it
优化就是这个，嗯，我之前也遇到过。
for many years this we take for granted
多年来，我们一直对此习以为常。
that all that we strive for and all that
我们所追求的一切以及所有的一切
we've accomplished and all that we love
我们已经取得的成就以及我们所热爱的一切
and know is sitting on this tectonic
并且知道它正坐落在这个构造板块之上
plate that we don't even know is there
我们甚至不知道它的存在。
until it shakes until it shakes it's
直到它摇晃，直到它摇晃……
like I was in over in Cape Town there's
就像我当时在开普敦那样……
an earthquake this um this year while I
今年发生了地震，当时我正在……
was there and I'm sat at my house and
我当时在那里，现在我坐在家里。
then suddenly at 2: a.m. in the morning
然后突然在凌晨2点
like underneath me starts shaking yeah
感觉脚下开始摇晃，是的
and I I oh my God I didn't realize I
我，我的天哪，我竟然没意识到
thought the house was the base actually
我当时以为那房子就是基地。
the base is the tectonic plate and in
底部是构造板块，并且在
our lives that's our health as
我们的生活，就是我们的健康。
entrepreneurs we disregard it so
企业家们对此置之不理
flippantly in the pursuit of some kind
轻率地追求某种
of Accolade until it shakes and then
赞誉直到它摇晃，然后
that becomes the only important thing
那成了唯一重要的事情。
Daniel thank you so much it's an honor
丹尼尔，非常感谢你，这真是我的荣幸。
and pleas keep doing what you're doing
请继续做你正在做的事情。
it's amazing thank
太棒了，谢谢
you do you know that 80% of New Year's
你知道吗，80%的新年
resolutions fail by February it's
到二月份，所有决议都失败了。
because we focus too much on the end
因为我们太关注结局了。
goal and we forget the small daily
我们追求目标，却忘记了日常琐事。
actions that actually move us forward
真正推动我们前进的行动
those actions that are easy to do are
那些容易做到的行动是
also easy not to do in life it's easy to
生活中也很容易不这样做，很容易……
save a dollar so it's also easy not to
省下一美元，所以也很容易不……
making one small Improvement each day
每天做出一个小小的改进
one tiny step in the right direction has
朝着正确方向迈出的一小步已经
a big difference over time and that is
随着时间的推移，情况会发生很大的变化，那就是
the 1% mindset which is why we created
这就是我们创立的初衷——秉持1%的心态
the 1% diary a 90day journal designed to
《1%日记》是一本为期90天的日记本，旨在……
help you stay consistent and focus on
帮助你保持一致性并专注于
the small wins and make real progress
取得小胜利，并取得真正的进步
over time it also gives you access to
随着时间的推移，它还能让你获得以下权限：
the 1% Comm Community a space where you
1% 社区，一个让你感到自在的空间
can stay accountable motivated inspired
能够保持责任感和动力，并充满灵感
along with many others on the same
以及其他许多人
Journey we launched the 1% diary in
Journey 我们推出了 1% 日记
November and it sold out so now we're
11月份就售罄了，所以现在我们是
doing a second drop join the wait list
进行第二次发售，请加入候补名单
at theed diary.com and you'll be the
在 theed diary.com 上，你将成为
first to know as soon as it's back in
第一时间获知它恢复供应的消息
stock I'll put the link below
股票链接我放在下面。
[Music]
[音乐]
oh
哦